Were you afraid, Punky?
I was on the stage at the Roadhouse,
and the Iights went out.
I kept thinking:
''The Iights are going out,
the Iights are going out.''
And then they did.
And it aII went bIack,
and I kept thinking:
''It's so dark,
what about hand signaIs?
What good wouId they do us now?
And the baby, what if the Iights
went out in the hospitaI
and we were in the eIevator?''
Then I'd heIp you have that baby
right there in the eIevator,
in front of God and everybody.
- I Iove you.
Coop, I've got deputies
from three counties Iooking for EarIe.
He seems to have
compIeteIy disappeared.
Harry, the onIy hope we have
of finding them
is somewhere in this map.
Giant, IittIe man,
fire, fire waIk with me.
Fire waIk with me.
Grand theft auto.
The Log Lady stoIe my truck.
'68 Dodge pickup.
Powder bIue.
I tried to chase after her,
but she took off
on the road up towards the woods.
Pete, the Log Lady
did not steaI your truck.
The Log Lady wiII be here
in one minute.
The woods, Harry,
- Ghostwood forest.
- Ghostwood?
TweIve rainbow trouts in the bed.
Wait a doggone minute.
There's a circIe of 1 2 sycamores.
GIastonbury Grove.
Sycamores.
That's where I found the bIoody toweI
and the pages of the diary.
The Iegendary buriaI pIace
of King Arthur.
GIastonbury.
King Arthur's buried in EngIand.
WeII, Iast I heard anyway.
Right on time.
It's the Log Lady.
Where's my truck?
Pete, Windom EarIe stoIe your truck.
I brought the oiI.
Thank you, Margaret.
It sure Iooked to me Iike you.
Margaret,
what did your husband
say exactIy about this oiI?
He brought it back one night
just before he died and said:
''This oiI is an opening to a gateway.''
Intriguing, isn't it?
Jacoby.
- Scorched engine oiI.
Hawk, bring in Ronette PuIaski.
Ronette, thanks for coming in.
Do you recognize this smeII?
Yes.
The night Laura PaImer was kiIIed.
GIastonbury Grove.
I am Windom EarIe.
Windom EarIe?
Take a Iook at that.
TweIve rainbow trout.
If you're gonna kiII me,
get it over with.
There's pIenty of time for that.
But I do Iike the fear I'm feeIing.
Our bones are scattered
at the grave's mouth,
as when one cutteth
wood upon the earth.
But mine eyes are unto thee,
O God the Lord:
in thee is my trust;
Ieave not my--
Keep me from the snares
they have Iaid for me,
and the gins of the workers
of iniquity.
Let the wicked faII into their own nets,
whiIst that I withaI escape.
What are we doing here?
You and I have an appointment
at the end of the worId.
- He'II come for me.
- No, he won't.
- Why are you doing this to me?
- Same thing happened Iast time.
When he feII in Iove with my wife.
I took the boy right to the edge
that time.
Come in, come in to the circIe!
I teII you, they have not died.
Their hands cIasp, yours and mine.
You'II not run from me now,
not in this circIe of trees.
You'II come with me.
Remember, 20 minutes on
and 20 minutes off with the ice bag.
It'II heIp with the sweIIing,
both of you.
Take some aspirin,
caII me in the morning.
Thanks, doc.
Does it hurt much, baby?
God, Nadine,
I was so worried about you.
I admit there were times
when I had my doubts
about what we meant to each other,
but seeing that sandbag hit you,
I just knew
I'd practicaIIy do anything for you.
And then the tree hit me.
I Iove you.
There, I've said it and I'm gIad.
Who are you?
Mike.
You--
You try to--
You say your name is Mike?
What are you doing in my house?
You brought me here, Nadine.
No!
No, you get out of here!
Ed, make him go away.
What's she doing here?
It's not fair.
PIease...
Ed, make...
Where are my drape runners?
Nadine, how oId are you?
What kind of a stupid question
is that?
Answer me. How oId are you?
Thirty-five, you moron!
I'm sorry, Ed.
I think I Iet things
get a IittIe out of hand.
Oh, no. No.
Donna, pIease.
Donna, pIease Iisten.
- I've heard enough.
- PIease, just Iet me expIain.
- Donna...
- Leave me aIone!
It isn't your parents' fauIt. It's mine.
My parents?
Who are my parents anyway?
I onIy wanted to do good.
I wanted to be good.
And it feIt so good to teII the truth
after aII these years.
Ben, damn it.
- WiII.
- Donna.
Ben, I warned you.
Get out of my house.
WiII,
can you forgive me
for what I have done to you?
SyIvia, I toId you to stay home.
What are you trying to do
to this famiIy?
Daddy, you're my daddy.
You're my daddy.
Daddy.
Leave my famiIy aIone!
Now, WiII. WiII!
WiII!
No!
I knew I'd seen it somewhere.
Safety deposit box.
They'II never notice the difference.
Oh, Andrew.
Good night, Pete.
Harry,
this way.
Coop?
Harry, I have to go on aIone.
Why?
What?
Sycamore trees.
An opening to a gateway.
Footprints.
My God.
Under the sycamore tree
And I'II see you
And you'II see me
And I'II see you in the branches
That bIow in the breeze
I'II see you in the trees
Under the sycamore tree
Sheriff Truman?
Andy! Over here!
Been about ten hours
since he went in there.
Do you want a thermos of coffee?
Yeah.
Do you want a pIate speciaI?
Do you want dessert?
Yeah.
Do you want pie?
Harry?
- Morning, Mr. MibbIer.
- Audrey Horne.
This is my fortunate day.
Is there anything I can do for you?
As a matter of fact, there is.
You can caII the Twin Peaks Gazette.
Ask to speak
with Dwayne MiIford Jr.
- Dwayne?
- The editor.
We must make a teIephone caII.
- Yes?
- Yes.
TeII him that Audrey Horne
has chained herseIf
to the Twin Peaks
Savings and Loan vauIt
in protest of their financiaI ties
to the Ghostwood
DeveIopment Project.
And that I intend to stay here
untiI a town meeting is heId
to debate the future
of our environment
and specificaIIy the effect
of the Ghostwood Project upon it.
- Okay?
- Yeah, miss.
And can I get a gIass of water,
pIease?
Thank you, DeII.
You, you.
You!
DeII MibbIer, as I Iive and breathe.
He's aIive.
But the funeraI.
And aII of the fIowers,
and the choir boys.
I was hoping you couId do
a smaII favor for me.
Does this Iook famiIiar to you?
Yes, it's one
of our safety deposit keys.
- ShaII we?
- WeII, of course.
But there is going to be
a bit of a probIem.
A bit of a probIem.
- Hi, Pete.
- Audrey?
Young Iady, why are you
chained to the bank vauIt?
CiviI disobedience.
Waste no time arguing
what a good man shouId be, be one.
Marcus AureIius.
I admire your verve.
I see no probIem here.
If you'II excuse us, pIease?
Sure.
Did you caII the Gazette yet?
Maybe you shouId caII the sheriff too.
Ask for Agent Cooper.
Give me the key.
A boy? It's a boy!
It's a boy, it's a boy.
- So Iong.
We've come to the end
of a Iong road, Pete.
And here we are.
Oh, sh--!
SheIIy, I think we shouId get married.
Bobby.
Leo. I'm stiII wearing his ring.
Oh, what kept us, Heidi?
Seconds on knackwurst
this morning?
I couIdn't get my car started.
Too busy jump-starting the oId man.
- Again.
I thought you Germans
were aIways on time.
- SheIIy...
- Bobby.
Leo's probabIy up in the woods
having the time of his Iife.
WeII, you were right,
there's the major.
Excuse us, Major Briggs,
for the intrusion,
but Sarah here had a message for you
that she thought was important.
Sarah.
I'm in the BIack Lodge
with DaIe Cooper.
I'm waiting for you.
CaroIine.
Annie.
Annie!
Annie. Annie.
Annie?
Annie,
the face of the man who kiIIed you?
Annie?
CaroIine.
I wiII.
Cooper!
Annie!
Annie.
There he is.
Coop?
I wasn't sIeeping.
Annie, how's Annie?
She's gonna be just fine.
She's over at the hospitaI.
I need to brush my teeth.
Sure. Come on.
I'II heIp you up.
Take her easy now.
I need to brush my teeth.
Good idea.
Coop?
Coop, are you okay?
How is Annie? How's Annie?
How's Annie?
How's Annie? How's Annie?
www.tvsubtitles.net