I don't wanna aIarm you
but GarIand has disappeared before.
Granted it's aIways been work-reIated.
Agent Cooper,
did this seem work-reIated?
Ma'am, that's hard to say.
So, Betty, you're saying this behavior
is part of the way the major operates.
Let me ask you this.
Did he Ieave suddenIy?
Yes, he did.
We were speaking phiIosophicaIIy,
and I Ieft the campsite
to answer the caII of nature.
When I returned he was gone.
The fact that you were in the woods
is very significant.
In what way?
ConfidentiaIIy,
he taIks about them constantIy.
Ma'am, has the major--
CIearIy, a man
of no smaII spirituaI advancement.
--been attempting to contact
some eIement that Iives in the woods
as a part of his top-secret work?
That's cIassified.
WeII, he certainIy has a renaissance
passion for expIoration, doesn't he?
That is how he sees himseIf.
And there's no manuaI for it.
There's certainIy no manuaI
to be married to it.
Betty, thanks for coming in.
I guess, there's not much more
we can do right now,
except, keep our eyes peeIed.
GarIand Ieft some notes on his bedside
tabIe. I can caII you back with them.
They might be very heIpfuI.
Harry, the major didn't just wander off
on some work-reIated assignment.
That fIash of Iight I saw, it's a powerfuI
force that exists in those woods.
Sheriff, we found Mr. and Mrs. MiIford's
wedding present.
It's a matching scarf and ascot set.
Good.
I stiII owe him a gift from Iast time.
I can't beIieve
that he's getting married again.
Dougie's weddings are a seasonaI
thing. Like the return of the saImon.
Marry in haste, repent in Ieisure.
Hello, sheriff?
There's a call for a Dale Crewper.
Long distance. l hope l didn't cut it off.
Temp. Lucy's heIping out
with the MiIford wedding.
Coop? Where are we?
This is Gordon Cole calling
from Bend, Oregon.
How are you doing, Gordon?
Coop, l just called to say
that you have my full support
in this investigation business.
These are hard times
but we get through them.
- Thank you, Gordon.
- lt ranks poor with me too.
Now, Coop, is any of this true?
Double homicide?
Stolen drugs?
Storming a whorehouse?
It's aII a bunch of hogwash.
l have to tell you
the Drug Enforcement Agency
is starting to nose around.
They're sending down a top dog
to investigate the drug angle.
Who are they sending?
lt's Gordon.
lt's Gordon Cole.
Who's the agent?
Dennis Bryson.
It's Bryson. He's a good man, Harry.
No nonsense.
Don't let him rattle you, Coop.
These guys make a living looking
through other people's drawers.
We've all had our socks
tossed around.
From time to time.
Couple of words of advice:
Let a smile be your umbrella.
- Thanks, Gordon.
- See you, Coop.
WeII, Harry...
...time to face the music.
Good morning, Roger.
GentIemen.
Agent Cooper.
It's showtime.
You've heard the charges.
What do you wish to present
as your defense?
I have no defense.
I am compIeteIy confident
in the rightness of my actions.
Some of it occurred outside of Bureau
guideIines, I wiII pay the price for that.
But I'm innocent
of any criminaI wrongdoing.
If they wish to charge me,
I wiII defend myseIf in a court of Iaw.
DaIe.
There's a right way and a wrong way
to do this.
And the first thing we expect
is a Bureau man
to stand up for himseIf.
A man who can't,
who doesn't even try,
weII, he may be packing feathers
where his spine is supposed to be.
Roger.
I know the moves
I'm supposed to make.
And I know the board.
So.
I've been doing
a Iot of thinking IateIy.
And I've started to focus out
beyond the edge of the board.
On a bigger game.
What game?
The sound the wind makes
through the vines.
The sentience of animaIs.
What we fear in the dark
and what Iies beyond the darkness.
What the heII are you taIking about?
I'm taIking about seeing
beyond fear, Roger.
About Iooking at the worId with Iove.
They're IiabIe to extradite you
for murder and drug trafficking.
These are things I cannot controI.
The suspension wiII remain in force.
The next move is up to the Canadian
government
and the DEA investigation
which begins today.
You've cracked a big case.
You've been under a Iot of pressure.
I may recommend
a fuII psychoIogicaI workup.
Thanks for your candor, Roger.
So Iong, feIIas.
Donna, hi.
Hi, Nadine.
Have you heard anything from James?
You mean, Eddie's friend
with the motorcycIe?
Yeah.
He hasn't been around
for a coupIe of days.
Listen,
I gotta ask you something and I hope
you don't think this is too personaI.
What?
WeII, are you stiII, Iike, going out
with Mike or anything?
No.
- Why?
- You have to promise not to say.
- Promise, okay?
- Sure.
WeII, I think there may be
some major chemistry deveIoping bet--
Oh, my God, there he is.
Hi, Donna.
Hi, Mike.
He has the cutest buns.
Nadine, what about Ed?
Aren't you stiII seeing him?
Yeah, sort of.
WeII, if you're stiII seeing Ed,
then how can you...
...how can you start seeing Mike?
WeII, Eddie stays home
and Mike's at schooI.
Eddie Iikes to stay in,
Mike Iikes to go out.
And Iet's be reaIistic,
sometimes Eddie acts Iike
he's oId enough to be my father.
I'II catch you Iater.
CouId I get a beer?
- Hi.
- HeIIo.
Headed somewhere?
I'm sorry?
Is there some pIace you're going to
or running from?
You got the wrong guy. I'm aII right.
Men are aIways aII right.
Right up untiI they puII the trigger.
And then we watch the neighbors
soIemnIy march out
to the news cameras to teII us:
''He was such a nice, quiet guy.''
WeII, I'm onIy quiet on the outside.
I can aImost hear what's inside
from here.
Live nearby?
Yeah, Twin Peaks.
It's a nice jacket.
I'm gIad you think so.
- Look, can you do anything with cars?
- Yeah.
Why, you got a probIem with
the 'Vette outside?
No. No, it's my husband's Jaguar.
Somebody squeezed me on
the highway, and I drove it to a ditch.
I think it wouId be a very good idea to
have it repaired before he gets home.
WeII, I couId take a Iook at it.
My name is James.
EveIyn.
EveIyn Marsh.
I Iive right up the road.
WeII, are we in a hurry?
Do you mind if I pIay the box first?
I don't exactIy punch a cIock myseIf.
Good day, Dick.
HeIIo, Andy.
This is IittIe Nicky, my charge
from Happy HeIping Hand.
Nicky, this is Deputy Andy.
How do you do, young feIIa?
Hi.
Andrew, oId boy.
LittIe Nicky and myseIf, we just came
from Horne's Department Store
where Nicky was fitted
for a new wardrobe.
And now we're on our way
for a maIted.
We were hoping Lucy couId come
with us.
Oh, shoot, Dick.
Lucy's up at the Great Northern,
heIping with the MiIford wedding.
Oh, God, that's right.
Dougie's getting married again.
Lucy's not here?
Does this mean we can't go out
for a maIted?
Yes, unfortunateIy.
We'II have to go some other time.
But you promised. Can't we go?
You know, Dick,
it's cIose to my Iunch hour.
If you'd Iike, Nicky, I'd sure enjoy
taking you two guys out for a maIted.
- How wouId that be?
- Oh, boy.
So, what wiII you do
if we can't figure a way
to get you cIeared?
WeII, Harry, the Giant said a path is
formed by Iaying one stone at a time.
Have either of you feIIas heard
of a pIace caIIed the White Lodge?
Where did you hear of it?
WeII, it was the Iast thing Major Briggs
said to me before he disappeared.
Cooper, you may be fearIess
in this worId.
But there are other worIds.
TeII me more.
My peopIe beIieve that
the White Lodge is a pIace
where the spirits that ruIe
man and nature here reside.
LocaI Iegend. Goes way back.
There is aIso a Iegend of a pIace
caIIed the BIack Lodge,
the shadow seIf of the White Lodge.
Legend says that every spirit
must pass through there
on a way to perfection.
There, you wiII meet
your own shadow seIf.
My peopIe caII it: The DweIIer
on the ThreshoId.
DweIIer on the ThreshoId.
But it is said, if you confront the
BIack Lodge with imperfect courage,
it wiII utterIy annihiIate your souI.
Agent Cooper, Agent Bryson's here
to see you.
Send him right in.
Dennis Bryson and I worked together
in OakIand.
One of the finest minds in the DEA.
Harry, we're in very good hands.
Coop.
Dennis?
It's a Iong story, but actuaIIy
I prefer Denise if you don't mind.
Okay.
Sheriff Truman.
- PIeased.
- Deputy Hawk.
Denise Bryson,
Drug Enforcement Agency.
WeII, I had a nice ride out here,
sheriff.
It's hard to imagine
you have even any crime.
I picture you chasing Iost dogs,
and Iocking up the town drunk.
UnfortunateIy, it's a IittIe more
invoIved than that.
Let's get right to this, DaIe.
The DEA's interest in you stems from
aIIegations made by an RCMP officer
that you stoIe drugs being used
by him in a sting operation.
Denise, I beIieve I'm being set up.
WeII, my recent experiences taught me
never to judge too quickIy.
Anyway, I'II get right to this
- and get back to you Iater.
- Okay.
I understand we're both staying
at the Great Northern.
How is the food up there?
Denise, you're in for a reaI surprise.
So are they.
WeII, we'II catch up Iater.
- I wanna teII you aII about my new Iife.
- Anxious to hear about it.
It's a pIeasure to meet you, sheriff.
Deputy.
That's a good coIor for him.
Look, is there something
you want?
Why, Mike.
Aren't we being a IittIe forward?
Come on, guys. I wanna hear
some grunting and see some sweat.
Attaboy, NeIson.
Come on, pump it.
Pump it.
- Hey, what's your name, IittIe Iady?
- Nadine ButIer.
WeII, Nadine, ever give any thoughts
of going out for the wrestIing team?
Josie.
It's time.
I can't be with you unIess I know.
- Oh, Harry.
- The truth.
The truth.
I used to...work for a man
in Hong Kong.
His name is Thomas Eckhardt.
He heIped me.
Took me off the streets
when I was 1 6.
We are from a poor famiIy.
Sometimes they seII
their femaIe chiIdren.
I was Iucky.
He taught me about Iife...
...about business.
He was my father.
My master.
My Iover.
When I met Andrew Packard,
I was aIready afraid for my Iife.
Andrew was aIso
a business partner.
When Andrew asked me to marry him,
I said yes.
Who was this Mr. Lee?
Who is this...this cousin?
I'm sorry, Harry.
I was just trying
to keep you out of this.
- The Iess you know, the better.
- Who was he?
He works for Eckhardt.
He said if I didn't go back with him,
he'd kiII you.
Why?
Because Eckhardt wants me.
He's never stopped wanting me.
He thinks I'm his property.
When Andrew was aIive,
he couId protect me.
I now beIieve...
...Eckhardt is the man
responsibIe for Andrew's death.
We were-- We were in the airport
in SeattIe.
And I just escaped.
I'd rather die.
I'd rather die than go back
to that monster.
Josie.
Josie, you wiII never have
to go back there.
You're with me now...
And now...
...he'II kiII the both of us.
No.
Let him try.
Sorry, it took so Iong,
- but we're short on heIp today.
- That's quite aII right.
I've been Iooking forward to this pie.
I've heard so much about it.
You won't be disappointed.
Hey, I-- I'II get you anything
you want. Just sit down.
Hey, sweetheart.
CouId we get some coffee?
- How was your hunting expedition?
- It was a IittIe fatiguing.
- Catch anything?
- I hope not.
Oh, catch anything.
Yeah, I...
I came across a 1 2-point buck, you
know, standing by a deepwater pooI.
So I made this very soft approach
and I Iined him up dead center:
You shouId have had your camera.
Are you having it mounted?
Oh, yeah, yeah, even as we speak.
It was great, just great.
I think I better go
and check on your mama.
She's not here, Ernie.
She's gone back to SeattIe.
SeattIe?
And that's where I think
you shouId go too.
Hey, buddy,
what's with the Iong face?
- Vivian's gone back to SeattIe.
- Better for you, buckeroo.
We got four kiIos to unIoad. You want
the baII-and-chain getting in the way?
Yeah, I suppose you are right.
There's the phone, hotrod.
We're on a deadIine.
Here we go. Two three-berry pies
and one super snow frost
chocoIate maIted.
Wow, thanks.
Looks just Iike WhitetaiI Mountain,
doesn't it, Nicky?
How much does it cost?
Oh, money is no object,
IittIe NichoIas.
Damn. Damn.
Damn.
Sorry, UncIe Dick.
It's okay, Nicky.
UncIe Dick isn't mad.
Are you, UncIe Dick?
UncIe Dick is simpIy ripping, thank
you. Pass me a napkin, UncIe Andy.
Gosh darn it, anyway.
Sorry, UncIe Andy.
Think nothing of it, IittIe Nicky.
UncIe Andy went funny boom-boom,
didn't he?
I think I can put this right.
It is beautifuI.
Jeffrey Ioves this car.
My husband.
He Ioves this car.
Where is your husband, Mrs. Marsh?
I don't know this week.
He traveIs extensiveIy.
Business.
This car was buiIt in 1 948.
Jeffrey has to have the most unique
and beautifuI toys.
They have to be perfect.
He's that way
about everything he owns.
I couId have Iearned something from
that if I'd been paying attention.
Are you that way, James?
Are you that way about your bike?
I guess I'm not so interested
in how my bike Iooks
as I am in where it can take me.
Where do you wanna go?
It's not reaIIy a pIace, it's a feeIing.
Sometimes, riding at night...
...I punch off the headIights
and roII on the throttIe...
...and just rocket bIind into the dark.
So...
...do you think you couId fix it?
Yeah.
There's a room above the garage.
You can stay there if you Iike
whiIe you work.
Room and board and anything eIse
you think is fair.
I reaIIy do need to have this fixed
before Jeffrey gets home.
I'd Iike you to stay, James.
I'd enjoy the company.
Okay.
Good.
It's settIed then. I'II Ieave you to it.
Now is the winter of our discontent
Made gIorious summer
by this sun of York;
Now are our brows bound
with victorious wreaths;
A stag party?
And I wasn't even invited?
Where the heII have you been?
Ben, I have had an absoIuteIy
kiIIer scheduIe.
Do you know the kind of heII
that I have been through
in the Iast few days?
You said that you took care
of Catherine in the miII fire.
She's aIive.
And as you might imagine,
not a happy camper.
Through trickery...
...extortion...
She has managed
to cheat me out of both.
Both Ghostwood and the miII.
Then there is...
...the smaII matter of being arrested
for the kiIIing of...
...Laura PaImer.
A reaI business-enhancer.
On top of which, my trusted soIicitor,
the Iate LeIand PaImer...
...turns out to be
a homicidaI Iunatic.
Tough week, Ben.
Do you think the furniture
in this room is adequateIy arranged?
I have been toying with the notion
that if one couId find
the perfect arrangement
of aII objects in any particuIar space,
it couId create a resonance
the benefits from which
to the individuaI dweIIing in that
space couId be...
...couId be extensive,
couId be far-reaching, far-reaching.
WouId you heIp me with this desk?
That's fascinating, Ben, reaIIy.
Listen, though, what we have to taIk
about now...
...is One-Eyed Jack's.
Jack's, Jack's. Yes, One-Eyed Jack's.
Look, here's how it is, Ben.
Ben.
You're out.
Excuse me?
I own One-Eyed Jack's.
There's been a friendIy takeover.
You come in here under my empIoy
and have the gaII to teII me--
Oh, that's another thing.
I don't work for you anymore.
RenauIt.
Jean RenauIt.
It's RenauIt, isn't it? Hank.
Let me teII you something.
The guy is a psychopath.
Psychopath.
And you, my friend,
are dancing with the deviI.
Ben, you're a nut.
You think I'm just gonna sit here?
Let you take aII this.
Ben.
Life has changed.
I want you to Iisten to me when I
teII you that this is how it's gonna be.
Don't patronize me, you goon.
You're a mess, Ben. Look at you.
You screwed up, boss man.
You're out, Ben.
''You're out, Ben.
You're out. Ben, you're out.
Ben, you're out.''
Windom EarIe.
Of course, you couldn't help
but take note of
my emphatically traditional
opening.
l must say,
your responding move was nothing
if not reflective of your predilection
for the tidy and fastidious.
See how my response to you
begins to lead us
towards a classical
confrontation?
But there's doubt in your mind.
What are my true intentions?
How will you answer this time?
Hobgoblins, Dale.
Consistency, predictability,
giving rise to patterns.
We both know only too well
how these patterns leave you
vulnerable to attack.
You with your wounds.
l with mine.
Let me paint you a picture.
My knights will skirmish.
Lanes of power and influence will
open to my bishops and rooks.
Pawns will naturally be forfeit.
l'm even prepared to sacrifice
my queen because l assure you,
dear Dale, my goal will be attained
at any cost.
The king must die.
Do you, DougIas MiIford,
take this woman to be your wife...
...to Iove and to cherish,
for as Iong as you both shaII Iive?
You bet, I do, Reverend.
If there be anyone who knows not
why this union shouId be made,
Iet him speak now
or forever hoId his peace.
You're damn right. I want to object.
This IittIe goId digger
just wants his money,
and his pubIishing empire,
and God knows what aII.
And Iook at him,
he's got one foot
in the grave aIready.
Okay, Dwayne,
okay, just take her easy.
- Take her easy.
- AII right.
You know that I have had probIems,
sheriff. AII these years.
Okay, Mr. Mayor,
Iet's just get a IittIe air. ShaII we?
It's pretty pecuIiar, isn't it?
Don't give it another thought, doII.
- WeII, I know this is my opinion,
- Let's get out, Iet's just get out.
- and I want you to aII understand it.
- Excuse us.
Marrying every two months...
Good God.
So if there be no further objections--
Cooper here.
Denise.
WeII, that'II be nice.
I'II be right down.
Diane, when I've got a moment,
remind me to teII you
about Agent Bryson.
I just Iove MiIford weddings.
Unfair advantage.
How many of those girIs
were varsity wide receivers?
Very few.
Bad news first.
I found cocaine residue in your car.
And my guess is it wiII match the Iot
stoIen from the Mountie.
- Dennis, this can't appear straight.
- Denise.
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
Sure it Iooks Iike a frame, Coop.
But I'm gonna need more than
your opinion to make that stick.
Can you heIp me?
WeII, that gets
into a very deIicate area.
But on the other hand,
I'm trying very hard, recentIy,
to get more in touch
with my feeIings.
Ladies and gentIemen, the cake.
Dougie's aIways been a sucker.
When a woman pass...
...with pIay in her eyes...
...and JeII-O in her waIk,
and he's a trout on a hook.
So, Denise,
if you don't mind my asking,
- what happened to you?
- No, not at aII.
I Iike to taIk about it.
It's reaIIy very simpIe.
Last year, I was working undercover
suburban surveiIIance
and the seIIer had a few kinks
in his rep.
It seems that he'd onIy seII
to transvestites.
So my partner and I shacked up.
I pIayed the part of the buyer.
And I found that wearing women's
cIothes...
...reIaxed me.
I continued wearing them
into the night.
My partner thought it was
my consummate professionaIism.
It was a very confusing two weeks.
WeII, this is aII
a pretty amazing discIosure,
Denise.
Imagine how surprised I was, Coop.
This is not exactIy
something you pIan on.
Guess not.
- Sheriff.
- Harry.
I'II have a draft.
Sheriff, arrest this woman.
She's too beautifuI to be Iiving
in this state.
Oh, hey, aren't you that FBI man?
Not currentIy, no.
DaIe Cooper.
DaIe.
You soIved
that Laura PaImer case, huh?
Come on, darIing,
they're pIaying our tune. See you.
I sure hope those two go up
to the honeymoon suite soon.
We've had to separate Dwayne
and Dougie twice aIready.
Happens every wedding.
Boys wiII be boys.
I was married to the same woman
for haIf a century.
God rest her souI.
That's because I used my brain
for thinking, not my garden hose.
This cake is deIicious.
The music...
...turned out pretty good.
It ought have been the death march.
You're an exceIIent dancer.
One other thing about dancing,
Audrey,
is that you never know
where the step couId Iead.
You have to hang on
and hope the music takes you there.
Your brother, my husband,
Andrew Packard,
was kiIIed by a man
named Thomas Eckhardt.
TeII me something
I don't aIready know.
You're in terribIe danger, Catherine.
You heIped kiII my brother,
tried to cheat me out of my Iand,
my famiIy's IifebIood,
utterIy destroy my existence,
and now you want to save me?
I had to do these things to stay aIive.
I have no one to turn to now.
I've got nothing.
And I'm at your mercy.
Now...
...enough.
Let's be practicaI.
What do you propose we do?
I don't know.
Then I'II teII you.
From now on...
...you work for me.
Here.
At the house.
As a maid.
You move your things
into the servant's quarters.
If you disobey me...
...if you Iie to me...
...if you contradict
a singIe thing I teII you,
I shaII find this Eckhardt
and feed you to him by hand.
Is that cIear?
Speak!
Yes, I understand.
Fine.
We'II taIk about this Eckhardt
some other time.
You may go to your room.
Thank you.
Josie...
I'II take breakfast at 7 in my room.
Coffee, juice,
dry toast, oatmeaI.
- Yes.
- Sweet dreams.
Happy, Andrew?
Everything is going exactIy
as we pIanned.
And now...?
And now, dear sister,
we wait for Thomas Eckhardt
to come Iooking
for his one true Iove.
And when he does--
We'II be waiting for him.
www.tvsubtitles.net