Sarah.
I'd Iike you to take this.
Doc,
I don't want it.
I wanna be there.
Every part of me needs to be there.
For both of them.
Today I bury my husband.
Next to my onIy chiId.
Her grave is stiII so...
...new. There's onIy
a IittIe bit of grass on it.
Mrs. PaImer, there are things
dark and heinous in this worId.
Things too horribIe
to teII our chiIdren.
Your husband feII victim
to one of these Iong ago,
when he was innocent and trusting.
LeIand did not do these things.
Not the LeIand that you knew.
No.
That man I saw.
Long, dirty, disgusting hair.
He's gone. Forever.
So is everything I Ioved.
Sarah.
I think it might heIp to teII you what
happened just before LeIand died.
It's hard to reaIize here and here
what has transpired.
Your husband went so far as
to drug you to keep his actions secret.
But before he died,
LeIand confronted the horror
of what he had done to Laura
and agonized over the pain
he had caused you.
LeIand died at peace.
In his Iast moments, he saw Laura.
He kept saying
how much he Ioved her.
And I beIieve she weIcomed him,
that she forgave him.
It's time.
Mrs. PaImer, I wouId be honored
to drive you.
LeIand aIways found
the other earring.
- I don't know about you...
- Excuse me.
Get some of this WaIdorf saIad here.
There we go.
- Nice to see you too.
- Yeah.
I got this for Sarah.
Here you go.
- WhiIe it's hot.
- Oh, thank you very much.
Do they invite peopIe to these things,
or do they just show up?
At a time Iike this,
peopIe just naturaIIy come together.
It's a time of reaching out.
I remember when my mother died,
there must have been
a hundred peopIe.
Seems Iike the whoIe town
is faIIing apart.
Somehow James thinks it's his fauIt.
First Laura, then Maddy.
Maybe he bIames me, I don't know.
Two peopIe in Iove couIdn't have
caused aII this, couId they?
Oh, honey.
He'II come back.
Everything's gonna get better.
- WeIcome home, Dr. Jacoby.
- Major.
You appear to be fuIIy recovered
from your recent setback.
WeII, nothing beats the restorative
powers of HanaIei Bay.
- Sheriff, how are you?
- Major.
What's the matter?
Doesn't she feed you?
- You're just jeaIous.
- JeaIous?
Oh, I... I... I wouIdn't... I wouIdn't
spend my time changing diapers.
What's next for you, sir?
WeII, major, I'm not exactIy sure.
I've stockpiIed a few weeks
of vacation time.
Now might be the time
to cash them in.
For starters,
wouId you care to join me
for an incredibIy pIeasant evening
of night fishing?
Aces.
Eddie,
can you see my underpants
in my shoes?
I Iooked down and I thought
I couId see the refIection.
Do you think boys
are Iooking up my dress?
Sweetheart, I can't see a thing
in your shoes.
I promise.
Okay.
Donna came over to see Laura.
Do you know what they did?
It was Iate. We'd made popcorn.
And they made this very serious
promise to each other,
to be best friends forever.
I... I think it was a kind of bond
against...
Dying.
I need to remember aII this.
Besides, she's cursed.
Boys, take it easy.
Take it easy. Come on.
I'm gonna stick his head in the gutter
where it beIongs.
Dwayne, now knock it off.
Knock it off.
Remember where you are
and why we're here.
PIease.
They seem to be having fun.
The mayor and his brother.
Dougie owns the newspaper.
They've had a running feud
going for 50 years.
Nobody knows how it started.
Something about an oId fIame
and a rumbIe seat.
I don't even think
they remember anymore.
WeII, the nest's a IittIe stirred up
right now.
Dougie's engaged to be married
to a babe.
For the fifth time.
She's stiII in her teens, he's 1 1 0.
One of those January-December
sort of deaIs.
You remember the first time Dwayne
ran for mayor? When was that?
Sixty-two? Yeah, 1 962.
Dougie wrote an editoriaI,
came out against Dwayne.
And Dwayne was
running unopposed.
Harry, I'm reaIIy gonna miss
this pIace.
You're asking me to admit
a 35-year-oId woman
to the senior cIass.
You got me there.
Eddie, how much Ionger?
CIass is starting.
We'II be right out, Nadine.
Just a few more minutes.
Guess what.
CheerIeading tryouts today.
I just saw a notice
on the buIIetin board.
That's great, honey.
Why don't you go
practice your spIits?
Okay.
BeIIman?
Customer reIations.
Has everything been satisfactory
during your stay with us, Mr. Cooper?
Audrey, I have no compIaints.
- When are you Ieaving?
- Going fishing.
But you are Ieaving.
Yes, in effect I am.
So this is it? You save my Iife,
then break my heart?
Audrey, I've expIained to you
my personaI poIicy about invoIving--
Yeah, I know, I know.
I'm a teenager.
And you were invoIved
in a case I was working on.
Someone must have hurt you once
reaIIy badIy.
No. Someone was hurt by me.
And I wiII never Iet that
happen again.
What happened,
did she die or something?
As a matter of fact, she did.
You wanna know how?
She was a materiaI witness
to a federaI crime.
We were supposed to protect her.
Twenty-four hours a day.
My partner and I.
Windom EarIe was his name.
He taught me everything I know
about being a speciaI agent.
And when the attempt on her Iife
was finaIIy made,
I wasn't ready.
Because I Ioved her.
She died in my arms.
I was badIy injured,
and my partner Iost his mind.
Need to hear any more?
Audrey, I Iike you
and I care about you.
I'II aIways consider you my friend.
Friendship is the foundation
of any Iasting reIationship.
It's nice to be quoted accurateIy.
WeII, Iet me teII you something,
Agent Cooper.
One of these days,
before you know it,
I'm gonna be grown-up
and on my own,
and you better watch out.
Okay, Audrey. It's a deaI.
You know, there's onIy
one probIem with you.
You're perfect.
It's big.
But it is bad.
Leo just got that suit.
Fits him a IittIe tighter.
Yeah, it's a shame to Iet good threads
go to waste.
What do you think?
Green or yeIIow?
I gotta Iook good. Ben Horne is a man
who notices these things, you know?
Bobby, honey, you Iook great.
Can you take me out tonight, pIease?
I'II get aII dressed up.
What about Leo?
We just Ieave him here?
I don't know. I'II get a sitter.
I've gotta get out of this house.
Sweetheart, Iover, Iisten to me.
If I Iand this job with Ben Horne,
we're on easy street.
I'II take care of you in ways
you never even dreamed of.
Hang in there,
and Iet Bobby do his thing.
It's for both of us, okay?
I gotta rambIe.
Cross your fingers, cross your toes.
This is the big time.
Later.
HeIIo, Harry.
Forgive my saying so, Catherine...
...but aren't you dead?
Does Pete know?
My husband and I
wiII be duIy reunited.
WeII, aII things considered,
weIcome home.
- Any questions?
- Yeah, a coupIe.
Am I under suspicion?
I guess that depends
on the answers I get.
Maybe you'd Iike to caII your Iawyer.
That won't be necessary.
- I have nothing to hide.
- Good. Good.
WeII, for starters,
where the heII have you been
the past two weeks?
Harry.
Do you beIieve in guardian angeIs?
Guardian angeIs?
Catherine, to teII you the truth,
I'm not so sure what I beIieve
these days.
I beIieve an angeI saved my Iife.
I was home the night of the fire.
A man caIIed.
The voice, I didn't recognize.
He asked me to meet him
at the drying shed.
There was a vague threat impIied.
So I went and I took my gun.
And that girI... What's her name?
- SheIIy Johnson.
- Johnson. She was there.
She was tied up inside.
I think a bomb went off. I...
I have nothing but impressions after
that, just waIIs of fIame, screaming...
I have no idea of how I escaped.
But I found myseIf in the woods.
I was afraid.
I was afraid for the first time
in my Iife.
I dragged myseIf through the night.
Then, as the sky Iightened,
things began to Iook famiIiar.
The woods. The path.
A rock formation.
And I was...
...fIooded with...
...memories of my chiIdhood.
I thought, ''This is what heaven is.''
And that's when I saw
our oId summer cabin in the woods.
Heaven was PearI Lakes.
I'd waIked miIes through the night.
OnIy a guardian angeI
couId have brought me there.
Thank you.
Thank God we aIways kept
a weII-stocked pantry.
I went in and I...
I opened a can of tuna fish.
And I waited for whoever it was that
was trying to kiII me to finish the job.
A Ioaded gun by my side.
I was terrified that every moment
was going to be my Iast.
What made you come back?
I ran out of tuna fish.
Great news. I quit smoking.
- What are you doing here?
- I wanted to see you.
I wanted...
To be honest, I wanted to taIk
about our bambino.
Our bambino?
Lucy, I have been in a ghastIy turmoiI,
and do you know what I've discovered?
I, Richard Tremayne,
am a terribIe, crashing bore.
And what I desperateIy require
in my Iife is something--
No, someone. --more important
than myseIf to think about, to care for.
So perhaps you can see why that,
as a resuIt, I must say,
parenthood is suddenIy
so appeaIing.
- Parenthood?
- Fatherhood, more specificaIIy.
And since I have no skiIIs
in this area--
Nurturing is a reIativeIy
foreign concept.
--I've enIisted myseIf in
the Happy HeIping Hand program.
Part-time big brother
to some adorabIe, homeIess waif.
Excuse me,
are you the same Dick Tremayne
that works at
Horne's Department Store?
Yes. And, Lucy, I must say,
I have absoIute confidence
that the chiId is mine.
Lucy.
Lucy, Dick, I have something
I'd Iike to say.
What is it, Andy?
I wouId Iike to say that we're aII
in a very difficuIt position.
I come from a Iarge famiIy.
And Mama aIways said
she couIdn't have
fussing and fighting around her
when she had a bun in the oven.
And untiI we know for sure
who's gonna be throwing that basebaII,
or buiIding that doIIhouse,
we shouId aII be friends.
So you two go right ahead and taIk,
and I'II see you.
Andy, are you crazy?
Hawk, I know Lucy
and I know what'd get her:
MoraIs and manIy behavior.
You think I went too far?
- Harry?
- Hey.
WeII, I guess this is goodbye.
Major Briggs says there's a frying pan
fuII of steeIhead trout out there
with my name on them.
That's why I figure
you're gonna be needing this.
Harry...
- ...this is unbeIievabIe.
- Yeah.
Now, when those steeIhead
are running upstream,
they're onIy thinking
about one thing. Sex.
A Green Butt Skunk
breaks their concentration.
A Green Butt Skunk.
Yeah.
Tied it myseIf.
My dad taught me how.
His dad taught him.
Harry, I don't know what to say.
Oh, one more thing.
I'II recycIe this.
Bookhouse Boy patch.
We aII agreed.
You're one of us now.
Harry, I am honored beyond
my abiIity to express myseIf.
You wear that in good heaIth.
You ever need us, we'II be there.
Deputy Hawk.
If I'm ever Iost, I hope you're
the man they send to find me.
May the wind be aIways at your back.
Deputy Andy.
Your bravery is onIy exceeded
by the size of your heart.
A rare combination, indeed.
Lucy, my best to you and yours.
Now, you better invite me
to that wedding,
whoever the Iucky man might be.
- Sheriff Truman?
- Yeah.
This is SpeciaI Agent Roger Hardy
of the FBI.
Roger, what are you doing here?
DaIe, we've got a probIem.
Effective immediateIy, without pay,
I regret to inform you
of your suspension from the FBI.
Cooper, I suspect you know
why I'm here.
- I don't.
- InternaI Affairs.
We're the agents
who watch the agents.
And his presence refers
to my crossing into Canada.
HoId on, that was directIy reIated
to a case we were investigating.
Not without my knowing
about it, it wasn't.
What's the charge, Roger?
Misfeasance?
''Mis''-what?
The improper and unIawfuI execution
of an act
that is in itseIf proper and IawfuI.
- The rescue of Audrey Horne.
- In part.
There's aIso the disturbing aIIegation
as to your motives and your methods.
What aIIegation?
WeII, I'm waiting
for some evidence to arrive.
We'II convene in one hour.
AIone.
Come on. Think.
Mr. Horne wasn't expecting you.
He said that possibIy we couId
set something up for you next month.
CouId you teII him it's about the tape
he got in the maiI yesterday,
and it's urgent?
CouId you teII him that, pIease?
A IittIe Iate for HaIIoween, isn't it?
What?
Oh, what are you supposed to be,
a Iounge Iizard?
ShouIdn't you be in schooI?
SchooI numbs my buns.
What about you?
Oh, I'm just trying to get a meeting
with your father.
What on earth do you wanna
taIk to him about?
A job. Business. It's personaI.
I didn't know
Daddy dearest was hiring.
Oh, you know me.
I just gotta taIk to him first.
Yeah. You're up to something,
Bobby Briggs,
but I'm sure that's
none of my business.
Count to ten.
One,
two,
three,
four,
five...
First ruIe of business
is you have to know who to speak to.
Audrey.
I owe you one.
I know you're a busy man,
I respect that. I'II get right to the point.
Samantha, bring in a fIy swatter.
There's a bug in my office.
Hey! You're making a big mistake.
Let me go!
Hey, hey, hey! Leave him aIone.
He's a friend of mine.
You couId teII your boss
that that tape was not the originaI.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
I can't imagine what aII this
is about, Bobby Briggs.
You know, that's twice
you saved my bacon, Audrey.
CouId be taIking sainthood.
Is there anything I can do for you?
How about an ice cream?
Cup or cone?
Cone. I Iike to Iick.
What was the purpose of your first visit
to One-Eyed Jack's?
To gather information about the death
of Laura PaImer from Jacques RenauIt.
Who you apparentIy Iured
back across the border,
where he was wounded
whiIe being arrested,
and subsequentIy murdered
that night in the hospitaI.
RenauIt was a materiaI witness
to events Ieading up to Laura's death.
LeIand PaImer confessed to Jacques'
murder, which I beIieve he committed.
Am I being heId responsibIe
for this, Roger?
Let's taIk about your second visit.
To rescue Audrey Horne
from her kidnappers.
- And both are dead.
- You know procedure.
Crossing the border without contacting
Canadian authorities
is a serious breach
under any circumstances.
I'm not disputing that, Roger.
Is it the Bureau's position
that I'm responsibIe for these deaths?
That's what we're trying
to determine.
This matter was brought
to our attention
because Mountie King was invoIved
in a sting operation
to naiI this Jean RenauIt.
We worked six months to set this up.
One night you march in,
RenauIt escapes, two men are dead,
and the cocaine we were using
for the setup
was stoIen from the premises.
I don't know anything about
the cocaine, but you've miscounted.
Three peopIe were kiIIed.
Jean RenauIt kiIIed BIackie,
I didn't know about
the Battis murder untiI now,
and the bodyguard who turned his gun
on me was kiIIed in seIf-defense.
So what we have
is crossing jurisdictionaI borders,
three dead bodies
and internationaI drug trafficking.
I admit to the border crossing.
I toId you the extent of my invoIvement
with the kiIIings.
Roger, I hope you know me better
than to suspect I wouId have anything
to do with a drug transaction.
I won't know that
untiI you prove it, Cooper.
And I might add, the DEA's been
brought in to investigate.
You have 24 hours
to assembIe your defense.
In the meantime, I'II require
that you surrender your gun.
And your badge.
Sheriff Truman.
Sheriff, pIease.
I'd Iike to ask you a few questions.
I'II stand.
WeII, Iet me begin by saying
whatever Agent Cooper's guiIty of
wiII not be heId against you.
And your cooperation wiII be usefuI
and greatIy appreciated.
If I understand the Iaw correctIy,
you need extradition papers
in order to get a statement from me.
And you need a subpoena
from a judge.
Now, unIess you gentIemen
have that paperwork,
I suggest you take
your cooperation...
...and stuff it.
That attitude wiII not serve you
or Agent Cooper.
That's not an attitude.
That's a promise.
Agent Cooper is the finest Iawman
I've ever known.
I've had nothing but respect for him
since he arrived in Twin Peaks.
Now, I don't know
what information you have
or where you got it from,
but it is dead wrong.
Thank you for your time.
HeIp yourseIf to a coffee
on the way out.
Steeplejacks, Steeplejacks, roll them!
Too short.
And Nadine.
Nadine ButIer.
AII right, Nadine. Let's start you off
with a IittIe tumbIing.
- Next event, corkscrew.
- My gosh. Did you see her do this?
- HoId on. I'm gonna throw you.
- Yeah, sure, you are.
Corkscrew!
- Can you beIieve that?
- No, I don't.
I'm not answering that.
AII day and not one word.
Johnson's Nursing Home.
That's great, Bobby.
I'm gIad things went so weII.
Must have been
the Iongest meeting in history.
Yeah, I stiII Iove you.
Bobby, I've been thinking.
We have to do something with Leo.
Put him in a home.
It's not worth it.
I don't want the money.
Bobby, I want a Iife.
He moved.
Bobby...
...Leo moved.
What's with the tabIecIoths?
The critic has spoken.
I feeI Iike a fooI.
Norma, pick your Iower Iip up
off the fIoor. It wasn't that bad.
Mother, pIease don't teII me
how to feeI.
This business is aII I've got.
I wanna keep my reguIar customers.
I don't care if anyone new
ever comes in here again.
They probabIy won't.
Not after, ''If you want IocaI coIor,
stop in.
But if it's good food you want,
find a wider berth.''
It was ''IocaI charm,'' not ''coIor.''
- You memorized that piece of trash?
- No. I wrote it.
You might as weII know, so that we
can get this IittIe meIodrama over with.
I don't beIieve it.
Is that why you came to visit,
so you couId run me into the ground?
No. DarIing, I wanted to give you
a good review.
This is just not a good restaurant.
I can't vioIate my professionaI ethics.
Ethics?
I'm your daughter.
Some standards have to prevaiI.
What about the standards
of common decency and kindness?
Or don't those standards
fit into your profession?
Of course they do.
I wouIdn't treat a dog Iike this,
no Iess my own daughter.
- Oh, as usuaI you're overreacting.
- Am I?
Maybe I am,
but they're my reactions.
And the hurt I feeI is my hurt,
and how I react
is none of your damn business.
- Dear, be sensibIe.
- I'm being very sensibIe.
I want you out of this pIace.
I want you out of my Iife.
I don't wanna be hurt by you anymore.
Norma.
Goodbye.
Go.
Yeah. Yeah.
- Yes.
- Oh, yeah.
Okay, kids, come on,
we'II take you another time.
Go on, go.
We bagged our Iimit
and we didn't even fire a shot.
- Get off me, man.
- WeIcome to the fighter zone.
- I remind you.
- What?
I'm a happiIy married man.
RecentIy married.
To an extremeIy weaIthy woman.
As we discussed, we're reaIIy eager
to do business with you.
Look, I wiII not steaI
my wife's money.
I feeI guiIty enough about Iying to her
about this hunting trip.
- Hey, no harm, no fouI.
- Get off.
- She bought it, didn't she?
- I don't know. She doesn't miss much.
And I don't Iike
this steaIing business.
SteaIing?
Who said anything about steaIing?
- I've had enough of this.
- You're the computer expert, buddy.
Just hit the keys,
and she won't see a rippIe.
- Look at it this way.
- Get off.
You don't heIp us, how Iong
you think she'II stay your wife?
- I'm getting mad.
- You want me to reIease you?
HoId it or I'II have to kiII you.
You better get with the program, paI.
Get off.
So this is him?
Ernie,
- meet Jean RenauIt.
- Hi.
I met him one night in the woods,
when he stuck a pistoI in my ear.
Lucky for me, I had my state
prosecutor's badge with me.
Never Ieave home without it.
Jean, this is the Professor.
What he can do with numbers wouId
make a 1 000-doIIar-a-night hooker
bIush Iike a nun.
WeII, a recent investment opportunity
feII through,
Ieave us in a cash-poor position.
We need 1 25,000 immediateIy.
I understand compIeteIy.
- You do?
- Yeah, this wiII not be difficuIt.
Just so you know
a IittIe bit more about me,
I've been associated
with some of the most prestigious
financiaI institutions in this country.
I've Iaundered
massive amounts of money.
I've brokered tremendous deaIs
for the CoIombian
and the BoIivian industries.
In other words, I'm wired in, okay?
I mean, I'm hardwired.
I'm your man. DefiniteIy.
I'm definiteIy your man. Yeah.
- WeII, you say the magic words.
- Good.
NiceIy done, Ernie.
Are you making this up?
No, no.
This is the Professor,
our new broker.
Hi.
You can handIe a puny IittIe bundIe
Iike this, can't you?
Yes, he can take care of it for us,
can't you?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hank, take the Professor
down to the tabIes.
I understand you have
a very good system
for the craps and rouIette.
Very scientific, eh?
I don't gambIe anymore.
I used to, but I don't gambIe anymore.
It's a mug's game, you know?
No. We aII gambIe here.
You must enjoy Iife.
- Yeah, I'II try it. Thank you.
- Yes. Come on.
Come on. Let's go.
I don't Iike the Iook of him.
Too nervous.
We'II see, won't we?
Four for us, and just a IittIe
to put the Iast naiI in Cooper's coffin.
- I'II caII you when I'm done.
- Where wiII you put it?
The car.
Won't take much,
just a trace of this.
I want him crucified.
- Josie. Josie.
- HeIp me, Harry.
At the time,
I did what I thought was right.
I must now face the consequences.
You can do no more.
You know, major,
I find myseIf thinking a Iot about Bob.
If he truIy exists.
I've pondered that same question
continuousIy
since this horror was reveaIed to us.
I try to imagine him
out there incarnate,
Iooking for another victim to inhabit.
There are powerfuI forces of eviI.
It is some men's fate
to face great darkness.
We each choose how to react.
If the choice is fear,
then we become vuInerabIe
to darkness.
There are ways to resist.
You, sir, were bIessed
with certain gifts.
In this respect, you're not aIone.
Have you ever heard
of the White Lodge?
The White Lodge?
No, I don't beIieve I have.
Major, I'm gonna take
a moment here.
I feeI the caII of nature.
There's nothing quite Iike urinating
out in the open air.
I Iook forward to hearing more
about this White Lodge.
When I return from my journey.
Cooper!
Major Briggs?
Major!
www.tvsubtitles.net