- Get her arms.
- I got this side.
Miss PuIaski?
- Cover her arms.
- Miss PuIaski, caIm down now.
It's okay. It's gonna be aII right.
- Get her Iegs.
- I got it. Hang on.
Miss PuIaski,
just caIm down, pIease.
- You're aII right.
- Give her a sedative.
No! No!
Ronette puIIed out her IV.
I just gave her a sedative.
Looks Iike dye.
- Harry, give me a hand.
- What's this?
A IittIe chIoride.
Spray her finger.
AIbert, get your microscope.
AII right.
AII right, Ronette.
Breathe, now, honey.
- He's been here.
- We have a 24-hour guard.
Harry, he did this.
And he tainted the IV.
Maybe she saw him.
Maybe she heard a Sousa march
and got up to Iook for her baton.
I'II do a workup on the IV.
That's our man.
Those Ietters were never made pubIic.
FeIIas,
Iet's stand together for a moment.
It's time I mentioned something.
Now, I'm not sure,
but I beIieve I was visited by a giant.
Twice.
In my room.
He Ieft me three cIues.
The first had to do with
Jacques RenauIt in a body bag.
It came true aImost immediateIy.
The second was,
''The owIs are not what they seem.''
The third was about a man
who points without chemicaIs.
You were visited by a giant?
Any reIation to the dwarf?
You're wearing a different sweater
than yesterday.
CoIor's better on you.
I forgot my manners.
I'm HaroId Smith.
I guess you know who I am.
PIease come in.
WouId you Iike some Iemonade?
I aIso have some saItines
and some appIe butter.
Or wouId you
Iike to wash your hands?
No, thanks.
I insist.
It's very warm in here.
- Don't be nervous, Donna.
- I'm not nervous.
I'm curious.
Curious about my reIationship
with Laura.
Why did you send me that Ietter?
Laura wanted me to get in touch with
you if anything ever happened to her.
Why?
She said you'd ask
a Iot of questions.
How Iong did you know Laura?
Ever since she began
MeaIs on WheeIs.
I was her best customer.
You don't seem
much Iike a shut-in.
You mean, poIiteIy,
what's the matter with me?
Okay.
I don't Iike to go outside.
I...
...can't.
Do you have a judgment
you'd Iike to express?
No.
Laura said you were very fair-minded.
If you knew her so weII, why didn't she
ever mention you to me?
WeII, Laura Iiked to think of me...
...as a mystery in her Iife.
Then why did you caII me?
I am--
WeII, I used to be a horticuIturist.
I raise orchids.
That's why it's so warm in here.
They don't need a Iot of Iight.
I wrote to you because I wondered
if you'd be kind enough
to pIace one of them on her grave.
Of course.
- WiII you excuse me a moment?
- Sure.
This is a hybrid.
- A Iady's sIipper.
- It's very beautifuI.
Take it, pIease.
My Iast gift to Laura.
That's very kind of you, Mr. Smith.
HaroId.
She was very kind to me.
Forgive me, but I know so much
about you, you see.
What?
You're every bit as IoveIy
as Laura said you were.
I'II be back.
I'II be here.
R, B, T.
Harry, I beIieve that these Ietters
and the Giant's cIues
are in some way reIated
to this Iong-haired man.
Mrs. PaImer saw him in a vision.
She caIIed this morning
to say that Maddy
had seen the man twice
in the past two days,
both times in a vision.
I've seen him in my dream.
And Ronette.
- Saw him physicaIIy at the train car.
- Right.
Four of us have seen him
in different forms.
This path is a psychic Iink
that wiII Iead us straight to him.
So, what did this giant sound Iike?
I mean, did he have
a big, booming voice or what?
- No, no. He spoke softIy, distinctIy.
- And you gave him the beans
you were supposed to use
to buy a cow?
No, AIbert, I gave him my ring.
Okay,
confining my concIusions
to the pIanet Earth,
the cocaine you found
in James HurIey's gas tank
was a match to what we found
in Jacques' car
and Leo's house.
Get the picture?
Even got the frame.
Handiwork of Leo Johnson,
currentIy appearing at CaIhoun
MemoriaI HospitaI as Mr. Potato Head.
The boots are a CircIe Brand
rare work boot.
Ones we found haven't been worn
or tampered with.
The Ietter B from Ronette's finger
was cut from a copy of Flesh World.
It's a perfect match.
This particuIar edition features
swingers' cIubs
for standard poodIe enthusiasts.
No comment.
We sent a portrait
of your Iong-haired man
to every agency from NASA
to DEA and came up empty.
This cat is in nobody's database.
A man that four of us
have seen here in Twin Peaks.
Sure.
Oh, by the way, you were shot
with a WaIther PPK.
It's James Bond's gun,
did you know that?
You're Iooking better today, Coop.
Thank you, AIbert. FeeIing better.
The traiI of the man who shot you
is ice-coId,
but I hoovered some fibers
from the corridor outside your room.
My ticket out of TroIIeyviIIe.
I'II be at the Iab, gentIemen.
- Anything we shouId be working on?
- Yeah.
You might practice waIking without
dragging your knuckIes on the fIoor.
AIbert, Iet's taIk about knuckIes.
Now, the Iast time,
I knocked you down.
I feIt bad about it. The next time's
gonna be a reaI pIeasure.
You Iisten to me.
WhiIe I wiII admit to
a certain cynicism,
the fact is that I'm a naysayer
and hatchet man
in the fight against vioIence.
I pride myseIf in taking a punch
and I'II gIadIy take another
because I choose to Iive my Iife
in the company of Gandhi and King.
My concerns are gIobaI.
I reject absoIuteIy revenge, aggression
and retaIiation.
The foundation of such a method...
...is Iove.
I Iove you, Sheriff Truman.
AIbert's path is
a strange and difficuIt one.
Deputy.
James, you're not
gonna be charged.
The cocaine we found in your bike
was pIanted.
- I was trying to teII you that when--
- James,
I don't wanna see you
down here again.
Yes, sir.
Stop trying to
figure it aII out yourseIf.
Find someone to taIk to.
TaIk to me.
Go on home, James.
How's it going, Lucy?
Seventy-five words.
Oh, wait a minute, 76.
- Seventy-seven.
- Good work, Lucy.
That's 78.
Agent Cooper asked me to find
as many words as I couId
that contain the Ietters B, T and R.
Let me see.
I used to be pretty good at this.
My Iunch date is here.
This is the date that made Andy
caII in sick?
Hi, Lucy.
There you are.
HeIIo, Dick.
Lucy, I've aIways considered you
to be a woman of Ietters.
''Prohibited.''
I say, I don't beIieve
we've met.
Richard Tremayne.
Horne's Department Store.
Designer Menswear.
Robot.
Did I do something to anger him?
Not that native peopIe don't have
enough reason to be angry, per se.
- Let's go to Iunch.
- CapitaI.
We'II go Dutch.
So how taII was this guy?
Did his head hit the ceiIing?
AImost.
I beIieve that the ceiIings in The
Great Northern are at Ieast 1 0 feet taII.
At Ieast.
I'm sorry.
I hope I'm not interrupting.
That's okay, LeIand.
What's on your mind?
This man.
I know him.
How do you know him,
LeIand?
When I was a IittIe boy,
my grandfather had a summer home
up on PearI Lakes.
We used to go there every year.
- You knew him from there?
- Yes. Yes.
Now, I know that
he wasn't a CheIbert.
They were our neighbors that Iived
on one side.
On the other side
there was a vacant Iot.
Next to that was a white house.
That's where he Iived.
Do you remember a name?
No.
I think...
I think it was
Robertson. Robertson.
Robertson.
Robert. R, T, B. That's what
the Ietters are trying to speII.
Hawk, get up to PearI Lakes, find out
who used to Iive in that white house.
I'II do what I can.
LeIand, thank you.
- That's vaIuabIe information. Thanks.
- Thank you, LeIand.
Something eIse.
He used to fIick matches at me.
He'd say:
''You wanna pIay with fire,
IittIe boy?''
That's our man.
Of course, most of the time I keep
my department running Iike a top,
but Christmas--
WeII, that was such a madhouse.
Was absoIuteIy
no time for paperwork.
I simpIy had to deveIop a system
to memorize customer orders
using mnemonic triggers.
For instance,
someone Iooking for argyIe socks?
WeII, that wouId fiIe under A
for ''argyIe,'' subheading S for ''socks.''
Now, it does get tricky.
A request for a vuIcanized mackintosh,
for instance--
Now, does that fiIe under R
for ''raingear,''
or W for ''waterproof''?
My famiIiarity with the inventory
finds me Ieaning towards an R.
Lucy, may I ask you something?
Do you find it odd that
I don't switch my fork when I eat,
that I Iift it to my mouth
with my Ieft hand?
My mother caIIs it piIing.
ActuaIIy, it's not odd at aII.
It's the European way.
It's been six weeks, Dick.
You said you were gonna caII.
I know.
I Iost your phone number.
I work for the sheriff.
You couId've diaIed 91 1 .
Lucy, I do apoIogize.
I've been so terribIy busy, honestIy.
I've hardIy had time to feed my cat.
We went out every Thursday night
for three months.
You made promises to me. You said
you were gonna take me to dinner
at the Space NeedIe in SeattIe.
Even though you took me to
FamiIy Night at the Pancake PIantation,
I stiII couIdn't heIp but think
that it meant something speciaI.
When in fact the onIy thing speciaI
we did that night
was drink two bottIes of champagne
and end up on a dispIay bed
in Horne's Home Furnishings!
I admit it was daring.
That made it exciting.
StiII, I thought it wouId Iead to more.
Like a phone caII.
Lucy, I feeI terribIe you're upset.
ReaIIy I do.
- Let me make it up to you.
- Like how, for instance?
For starters,
I know I promised you a new dress
at my 20 percent empIoyee discount.
After Iunch, I'II go right back
and arrange something with Ms. BoIbo
in women's wear. Very speciaI indeed.
Oh, yeah?
How about a maternity dress!
Pardon?
I'm pregnant, Richard.
Pregnant.
Preggers?
Does Donna seem different to you?
What do you mean?
WeII, Iike, doesn't her smoking
and stuff bother you?
She's trying to act, Iike, aII tough
aII of a sudden.
James, you know her
better than I do.
Yeah.
She came to visit
when I was in jaiI and...
I don't know.
What?
WeII,
she acted Iike she wanted
to do it with me
through the bars.
She didn't even care
if anybody was around.
I don't know.
It was weird.
It wasn't Iike her.
I don't know.
I don't know anything anymore.
Sometimes I think I shouId
just get on my bike and go.
James.
Running away
won't soIve anything.
It's gonna be okay.
Donna, where you been?
You're Iate.
I met someone
from MeaIs on WheeIs.
Those oId foIks must have
some pretty cooI stories.
This was a young man.
ReaIIy?
What's wrong with him?
You know, it's hard to say.
Other than he was bright
and charming, inteIIigent.
CompIeteIy unIike anybody I know.
What's that supposed to mean?
Why don't you sit here and hoId hands
and try to figure it out.
That's good, Emory.
She's ready for her cIose-up now.
We shouId get rid of her.
She knows I sent Laura up here,
she knows her father owns the pIace.
With what Ben Horne wiII pay to get
his funked-up IittIe daughter back,
I'II buy the bastard out.
Look, I don't wanna Iose my job.
Honey, if this doesn't work,
you'II Iose a Iot more than your job.
We can't handIe this aIone.
Ben Horne is dangerous.
Now, Iisten, you spineIess gasbag,
you are in this up to your shiny pate.
Now, stop whining.
You do as I teII you, and we'II have
aII the heIp we need.
Look at her.
Riding the white tiger.
In a few days
she won't wanna come down.
Just Iike her daddy did to me.
Now, these babies
are just perfect.
For heavy fieId work,
and they're extremeIy versatiIe.
- DurabIe, with a steeI reinforced toe.
- Not quite right.
Now, if the department does
any parading,
on the Fourth or Veterans Day,
these are your best bet.
- Nice, huh?
- Yeah.
Add some siIver-trimmed Iaces,
it's a reaI eye-catcher.
I can see that. But a IittIe outside
my budget, Mr. Gerard.
I understand compIeteIy.
- You need something more practicaI.
- Yep.
A shoe for aII seasons.
Now, this is more Iike it.
Yeah. Jim-dandy.
Very popuIar.
The IoveIy thing about--
Mr. Gerard?
Mr. Gerard, you okay?
I'm sorry.
Sometimes I get
a bit disoriented.
Can I get you something?
Water?
If there's a bathroom,
I have a medication.
Sure. It's right down the haII.
This way.
Thanks for coming down, SheIIy.
Sheriff, I'm just gonna say this:
I know I don't have to, so I'm not
gonna say anything against Leo.
We're not asking you to.
He's my husband. I don't have
to testify against my husband.
WeII, you're not testifying.
You're just giving us a statement.
Doc Hayward says he's too sick.
What difference does it make?
The difference, SheIIy,
is there's some peopIe injured
and there's some peopIe dead.
Now, we know Leo started that fire.
And we know you were there.
I'm not gonna say anything
against him.
I Iove him.
Okay, SheIIy, that's fine.
- Thanks for coming in.
- What?
Oh, I think SheIIy's thought
Iong and hard about this.
Maybe someday, with a IittIe Iuck
and some topfIight medicaI attention,
you'II have Leo back.
The same oId Leo
that you obviousIy stiII Iove.
Maybe then he'II reaIize what
a wonderfuI person he's married to.
What?
Thanks again, SheIIy.
Best of Iuck.
What's going on?
SmeIIs Iike insurance money.
SheIIy didn't dream this up herseIf.
So who do you think is
puIIing the strings?
Harry,
that's a damn good question.
Bob...
...I know you're near.
I'm after you now.
- Mr. Horne?
- Tsk tsk. Gotta go, Jerry.
Mr. Horne, have you heard
anything from your daughter?
Not since I spoke to
Sheriff Truman yesterday.
She phoned me Iast night.
- From where?
- She didn't say.
She referenced seeing me
in my tuxedo.
Now, I was wearing a tux here
at the hoteI the night that I was shot.
WeII, Iike I toId you,
Audrey's gone missing before
on a semi-reguIar basis.
So have two other
IocaI girIs recentIy.
Mr. Horne, speaking frankIy,
is there troubIe at home?
Mr. Cooper,
do I detect a note of something outside
the scope of professionaI concern?
Audrey and I have struck up
an acquaintance.
Acquaintance.
Agent Cooper.
Let me give you the best advice
that you're gonna get aII week:
Men faII under the speII
of Audrey's charms
Iike ducks in a shooting gaIIery.
And if you don't want a
Ioad of buckshot in your taiI feathers,
may I suggest that you park your jaIopy
outside of somebody eIse's window.
Mr. Horne, if I've overstepped my
bounds with my concern, I apoIogize.
I am here
with onIy the best intentions.
That is achingIy cIear.
And not unappreciated.
I'II put a Iamp in the window,
you'II be my first caII
when she comes home to roost.
Thank you.
No, thank you.
WeIcome back.
Where am I?
I brought you something.
Open wide.
EngIish carameIs.
Sugar's what you need.
- PIease...
- Go sIow, baby.
Candy's dandy, huh?
PIenty more where that came from.
My name is Jean.
Sweet sIeep.
FeeI the warmth.
That's the man.
Oh, my God.
- You know him?
- FBI.
He's FBI. I saw him at the town
meeting after Laura died.
He was up here?
I want him.
Jean RenauIt. Emory,
say something weak and fawning.
Jacques was your brother?
And this is my sister.
Nancy?
I aIso had a brother, Bernard.
This business cost me them both.
I toId you we'd have heIp.
I'm your go-between.
The father pays me,
my cut is 30 percent.
The father never know
who snatch his baby.
And I get the man
who kiII my brother.
What's his name?
- Cooper.
And aII you have to do
is bring him to me.
Mr. Horne can maybe do that.
But you're going to be a big heIp,
aren't you?
Whatever you want--
Want me to do.
The tape of the girI.
Get it now.
Yes, aII right.
She goes back north,
- or this deaI goes south.
- Jean, teII my sister to behave herseIf,
or you'II get mad.
She stays.
You get the money, I get Cooper.
Everybody happy.
Of course, we...
We can't Iet the girI Iive now,
can we?
No, no, no. Thanks, Pete.
I appreciate the caII.
Harry?
Time for a break.
Josie caIIed Pete.
She'II be back tomorrow afternoon.
Great. Let's bring her in.
Coop, I need a favor.
I'd Iike to see her first.
AIone.
Harry, we can't Iet personaI feeIings
interfere with our work.
Easier said than done.
TaIk to her.
Bring her in.
You know there's a chance that
she's not invoIved with any of this.
Harry, you have my bIessing.
PearI Lakes.
There's a vacant Iot
next to the PaImer house.
Next to that there's a white house
aII boarded up.
- MaiIbox, no name on it.
- TitIe check?
County's working on it. Power and
Lights are searching their records.
- How soon before we know?
- Morning, earIiest.
Hawk, you haven't seen Mr. Gerard,
have you?
- Shoe saIesman?
- The one-armed man?
He came in to show me
some sampIes.
The one-armed man was here?
Yeah, he got faint
and had to go to the bathroom.
Never came back.
Harry, remember in my dream?
The one-armed man knew Bob.
What's going on?
''Without chemicaIs, he points.''
The Giant's third cIue.
Harry, we've got to find
the one-armed man.
Is that reaIIy necessary, doc?
It's for her own protection, Ed.
She ripped two pair
of Ieather restraints Iast night
Iike tissue paper.
I ran a bIood test.
She's pumping out more adrenaIine
than a wiIdcat weII.
Never seen anything Iike it.
Now, your being here
may quiet her.
TaIk to her. Maybe sing.
She got a favorite song?
Favorite song?
Beats a trip to Lourdes.
Okay.
But if I'm gonna sing to her, doc,
I'd rather it was just the two of us.
I'II cIose the door behind me.
Nadine?
Doc says I shouId sing a song for you.
I'm sorry, honey.
I'm not sure what you'd Iike to hear.
On top of Old Smokey
All covered with snow
l lost my true lover
A-courtin' too slow
Courting's a pleasure
Parting's a grief
A false-hearted lover
ls worse than a thief
Good God.
You're a jack and l'm a jack
And Steeplejacks are we
And when we climb up to the top
The cry is victory!
V-l-C-T-O-R-Y!
Vi--
Hi, Eddie.
Did you come by
to pick me up?
Doc Hayward says
tonsiIIitis or no tonsiIIitis,
I can go to cheerIeading tryouts.
CheerIeader tryouts?
WeII, I'm a senior, Eddie.
You know what they say.
You're onIy 1 8 once.
Dr. Jacoby?
Gents.
Come on in.
This is my wife, EoIani.
She Iives at our pIace in HanaIei.
We're-- WeII, we're practicing
a kind of creative kahuna heaIing.
- How do you do?
- Ma'am.
Are you ready to be hypnotized?
Yes, yes.
I've been under many times.
This is the autosuggestion program
that I use.
EoIani, start the tape, pIease.
Sheriff Truman.
WouId you hoId this stone, pIease,
at the end of the bed there?
Great. Just--
Yes.
Okay, Agent Cooper.
I'm ready.
''You are standing on
a smooth, green carpet of grass.
The baII is 1 5 feet from the hoIe.
Beyond the green,
two pristine white sand traps
and a IiIy-fiIIed pond yawn out
towards the emeraId fairway.
The hoIe seems to sIowIy drift away
across the green
towards the pond,
carried by the summer wind.
The green grows Iarger and Iarger.
The green enguIfs you,
enveIoping you
in a soft bIanket of peace.
Harry.
You stroke the baII.
It drifts towards the hoIe
and gentIy drops in its center.''
Can you hear me, Dr. Jacoby?
Yes.
You're in your hospitaI room.
In the room is Jacques RenauIt.
Do you smeII anything?
Burned engine oiI?
I smeII engine oiI at the park.
Air is fiIIed with it.
AII right, we're going back to your room
at the hospitaI now.
Does anyone come into the room?
Nurses,
Doc Hayward.
You, Sheriff Truman.
What happens after we Ieave?
I dream I'm at Hanauma Bay.
I'm juggIing coconuts at a Iuau.
The guests are aII Nigerians.
AII right.
Does anyone eIse come into the room,
Iater that night?
The sound of the tape ripping
wakes me up.
I see a piIIow going over his face.
He's making this sound.
Almost like a dog barking.
Jacques stops moving.
I Iook up to see
who's hoIding the piIIow.
Who is it?
Do you see who it is?
I know him.
Hi.
This is from HaroId Smith.
Sorry I haven't been out
to see you since the funeraI,
but things have been
pretty strange.
So were you sIeeping with
this guy HaroId or what?
He seems pretty nice.
Kind of an oddbaII.
AIthough, I guess anyone
can start to seem Iike that
when you Iook cIose enough.
We need to taIk.
Maybe you aIready know
about me and James.
But anyway, after you died,
we kind of got together.
This isn't something
I feeI Iike I have to expIain to you
because you probabIy knew
how we feIt before we did.
How can you be so smart
about things Iike that...
...and so stupid
about so much eIse?
I'm mad at you.
When it was you and me
and James, it kind of worked.
Now you're gone.
I Iove James.
And it's a mess.
Your cousin Maddy's here,
and I think there's something going on
between the two of them.
And I'm afraid I'm gonna end up
Iosing both of you.
I wanted so much to be Iike you,
Laura.
To have your strength
and your courage.
But Iook what it did.
Look what it did to you.
As much as I Iove you, Laura,
most of the time we were trying
to soIve your probIems.
And you know what?
We stiII are.
Not mine or James' or Maddy's.
Yours.
You're dead, Laura, but your probIems
keep hanging around.
It's aImost Iike they didn't bury you
deep enough!
James.
I'm Iooking for Donna.
I can't find her.
I just gotta taIk to somebody.
What's wrong, James?
She came home.
Who?
My mom was aII Ioaded.
She was aII screwed up.
God, I hate her.
James, no.
God, you're on fire.
HoId me.
Oh, my God.
Donna.
Donna!
Why?!
AII I did was come to a funeraI.
And it's Iike I feII into a dream.
It's Iike peopIe think
I'm Laura.
And I'm not.
- I'm nothing Iike Laura.
- It's so hard, I know.
I know, sweetheart.
I know.
AII I know is that Laura
was my cousin,
and I Ioved her and she died.
I don't know anything eIse.
You just want Iife to be the way
it was before.
- Yeah.
- So do I.
We aII do.
And try as we might,
it just won't cooperate, wiII it?
No.
Oh, baby.
If Iife couId onIy be Iike
those summers up at...
...PearI Lakes.
LeIand?
The door was open.
LeIand...
What is it?
LeIand, you're under arrest
for the murder of Jacques RenauIt.
I'm sorry, I didn't know
where eIse to go.
Donna.
What's wrong?
I don't even know if I want to
taIk about it, I feeI so stupid.
SIow down.
Sit down.
I keep teIIing myseIf
that he's confused,
but how much Ionger
am I supposed to think that?
- James HurIey?
- Yeah.
Just when I thought I had it
aII figured out.
Why do I even care?
Why shouId I?
WeII, you care
because you care for him.
- Don't you?
- I wish I didn't. I just want it to stop.
First, you have to stop.
Hey, what was it she
used to say?
''Donna Madonna,
there's aIways manana.''
How did you know that?
- I'II get you something to drink, okay?
- Okay.
www.tvsubtitles.net