- Hey, Donna.
- Hi.
- James, come on in.
We just came
to say goodbye to Maddy.
Oh, I'm sorry, you just missed her.
In fact, I dropped her off
at the bus station not 20 minutes ago.
- She's gone?
- Yes.
She thought that you were coming
over Iast night.
Did she say anything?
WeII, I wouId have to say that
she was a IittIe bit disappointed.
LeIand?
LeIand, honey?
Excuse me.
You know, if you'd Iike,
you couId write her.
I'm sure she'd be gIad
to hear from you.
Yeah. Look, I'm sorry
we bothered you.
Hey, no bother, no bother.
- Say hi to your foIks for me, Donna.
- Okay.
- Goodbye, Mr. PaImer.
Bye, James.
- Take it easy now.
- AII right.
- LeIand?
- Yes, dear.
Remember to sign us up for
the GIenn MiIIer Night at the cIub.
Don't worry, dear, I won't forget.
- Bye, hon.
- Bye, LeIand.
It smeIIs Iike a toiIet in here.
There's nothing...
Jerry, what the heII
took you so Iong?
Gee, dateIines, time zones,
I don't even know where I am.
God, you Iook terribIe.
- Jerry.
- Ben.
WeII, Ben,
since your reguIar mouthpiece
has been charged
with murder himseIf,
I'm gonna be handIing your case
personaIIy. So Iet's get started.
Did you kiII her?
- Jerry, for God's sakes.
- Sorry, you're right.
The Iast thing a good defense attorney
needs to know is the truth.
Jerry, can you get me out of here?
WeII, they can onIy hoId you
for 24 hours without charging you.
Or is it 48?
Oh, Jerry, Jerry,
I am in troubIe here.
Under controI, big brother.
Okay, so where are we saying
you were on the night Laura died?
- I was with Catherine.
- That's not a good choice.
It happens to be the truth.
Oh, dear.
Is there any sign of her?
Bone-- Bone fragments or teeth?
Charred corroborating note
regarding your whereabouts?
I'm so depressed.
Bunk beds.
Do you remember
our first room, Ben?
Me on the top bunk
and you on the bottom bunk.
And Louise Dombrowski dancing
on the hook rug with a fIashIight.
Lord, what's become of us?
You know, the first time I went in,
they thought it was my bIadder,
so they checked it again.
It was an infection.
I hadn't even been near a rusty naiI.
I mean, you remember that time
my toe turned purpIe, right?
So instead, I took a bath in baking
soda and then my toe came around,
but I got the worst cramps
Iike I swaIIowed
a kinked hose or something.
Have you seen Andy?
Oh, you must be that native person
I've heard so much about, EagIe Eye?
Hawk. Sister?
Oh, yeah, this is my sister Gwen.
This is Hawk.
Oh, it's a pIeasure to meet you.
God, how you must hate us white
peopIe after aII we've done to you.
Some of my best friends
are white peopIe.
Anyway, oh, come on.
My stomach...
Diane, 1 0:03 a.m.,
Great Northern HoteI.
Sheriff Truman and I have just been
with the one-armed man,
or what's Ieft of him.
In another time, another cuIture,
he may have been
a seer, a shaman priest.
In our worId, he's a shoe saIesman
and Iives among the shadows.
LeIand PaImer.
Excuse me.
Does he know
we arrested Ben Horne?
Doesn't Iook Iike it.
Harry, best if he'd hear it from you.
Hi, Harry, Agent Cooper.
Just having a IittIe fun.
You're Iooking good, LeIand.
Just caII me Fred.
LeIand, I'm sorry.
We didn't want you
to hear it from anyone eIse.
We've arrested Ben Horne
for Laura's murder.
He hasn't been charged,
but we're hoIding him.
- Ben?
- That's right.
There must be
some mistake, Harry.
Ben?
- I thought that Jacques RenauIt had--
- No.
Ben.
- You have a strong case against him?
- Yes, we do.
Oh, God.
WiII you be aII right, LeIand?
Yeah.
- The Iaw wiII handIe this.
- As it shouId be.
Thanks, Harry. Agent Cooper.
Harry, I'II catch up with you.
LeIand?
Yes.
If you can remember anything unusuaI
about Mr. Horne's behavior
the night of Laura's death,
wouId you pIease Iet me know?
I wiII, of course.
Thank you.
Everything okay?
I'm not sure.
This won't hurt a bit.
Sheriff, I protest this brutaI treatment
of my cIient.
After aII this man
has done for this town...
Now, hoId stiII.
I'II have the resuIts
in a coupIe of hours.
- Thanks, doc.
- GentIemen,
I demand that my cIient
either be reIeased or charged.
Never in aII my years of practicing Iaw
have I witnessed such a compIete
and utter disregard for
an accused man's constitutionaI rights.
Jeremy Horne,
Gonzaga University, 1 97 4.
Graduated Iast in his cIass of 1 42.
Passed the bar on his third attempt.
License to practice
revoked in the states
of IIIinois, FIorida,
AIaska, Massachusetts.
Hey, I'm not on triaI here.
Sit down.
Mr. Horne, do you know what this is?
- A book.
Take a cIoser Iook.
A diary.
We aII know about One-Eyed Jack's.
So did Laura.
''Someday, I'm gonna teII the worId
aII about Ben Horne.
I'm gonna teII them who he reaIIy is.''
She never got the chance, did she?
Come on, Ben, we're aII aduIts here.
WiId, young girI Iike Laura PaImer,
things spin out of controI.
She becomes a threat not just to you,
but to your business, your famiIy.
You are way out of Iine.
WeII, maybe
you don't have anything to hide.
That's not what it says in here.
- You cannot taIk to me Iike this!
- Ben. Ben.
- You cannot, you understand?
- Sit down.
Nice and easy. GentIemen, I'd Iike
a moment aIone with my brother--
With my cIient.
If you don't mind?
You have your moment.
Ben, Ben.
Ben, if you're gonna bIurt out
a confession Iike that,
it's gonna make our options
shrink down to a tiny IittIe nub.
AII right, what are we gonna do?
What are we gonna do?
Your aIibi has been roasted.
They can estabIish motive.
And your bIood
may have Laura's fingerprints on it.
Ben, as your attorney,
your friend, and your brother,
I strongIy suggest
that you get yourseIf a better Iawyer.
Okay, one last chance, Leo.
Don't disappoint me.
The mill?
Okay, one last chance, Leo.
Don't disappoint me.
The mill?
Keep it simple.
lnsurance investigators
should read ''arson. ''
Block letters about 6 feet high.
The deal as we discussed?
Ben Horne, his voice,
and Johnson's voice, Ben and Leo.
SpeciaI deIivery for Mr. Horne.
Bobby. Oh, God. Bobby!
He did it again.
It's your turn to cIean him this time.
What's that?
That is our ship.
What's that mean?
Since our cash cow in the other room
has turned into a sinkhoIe,
I've decided to pursue a career
in business.
ReaIIy? Like a saIesman?
Oh, no, I'm thinking
more executive suite.
- ReaIIy?
- Yeah.
Bobby, that sounds great.
I'm gonna give you
anything you want.
I want a fuII-time nanny.
- Maybe a French maid.
- Bobby.
- HeIIo, Norma.
- Mother.
I trust those are reaI potatoes
and not fIakes?
ReaI potatoes.
Excuse me.
What a nice surprise to see you here.
Hey, those are good.
I see they taught
him a skiII in the stockade.
- Where is your charming husband?
- Hank? He's not here right now.
I see.
Mother, I got your message.
But if you don't mind my asking,
what are you doing here?
I want to introduce you
to my new husband.
Husband?
Ernie, this is Norma.
Hi, how are you?
We're honeymooning.
I wonder if I couId
bother you for a cup of coffee?
- Nice girI.
- She's darIing.
Ernie's a financiaI anaIyst.
I just Iove what you've done
with your diner, darIing.
The fIowers add
such a measure of cheer.
Oh, thank you. Thank you so much.
Nice to see those good Iooks haven't
isoIated themseIves to one generation.
- Yeah, I know, go with goId figures.
- Excuse me.
You stiII Iook very smart
in that uniform.
Your figure's IoveIy.
It hasn't changed.
Now, I don't mean to be rude,
but how Iong wiII you be staying?
A coupIe of days. Ernie wanted
to see something of the country.
Why?
I just wish I had known, that's aII.
Oh, I didn't mean for you
to go into any fuss.
You know me, dear, I'm easy.
What's wrong?
Nothing, it's just that
there's a food critic coming
and I'm short on heIp, that's aII.
Food critic.
So that's why you tried so hard
to make the pIace Iook nice.
Norma, hoping to spend
much more time with you.
If it's aII right, we'd better check in.
I've got a Tokyo fax
waiting for me at the desk.
We'II be at the Great Northern.
I'm sorry we missed Henry.
I'II caII you Iater, okay?
Okay. Nice to meet you.
He's cIose.
Nurse.
CouId I have
a gIass of water, pIease?
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry.
Hi, Norma.
I guess I'm a IittIe Iate.
Forty-eight hours is not Iate, Hank,
it's missing.
I'm sorry, it was some--
Some business I had to take care of.
Business? No, this is business.
Business is a pIace where you come to
whether you feeI Iike it or not.
- Norma, I--
- Don't sweet-taIk me,
I'm this far from teIIing you
to take a hike.
Norma, pIease don't make that
kind of judgment untiI you hear me out.
Because of the bad choices
I've made,
there are peopIe out there,
peopIe from my past
who wanna see me faiI.
I've tried fighting them,
but I just get in more troubIe.
I've tried running from them,
but there's aIways somebody faster.
I know it's no way for a man
to Iive his Iife,
but sometimes it's just best
to hoId up and wait
for the storm to pass.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I'm just trying to keep my head
above water.
Maybe next time,
you'II ask for a IittIe heIp.
Next time, I wiII.
WeII, the prodigaI son returns.
- Vivian.
- Hi.
- You Iook great.
- Thanks.
Prison treat you weII?
WeII, that's a Iong story.
I'd Iike to hear it over dinner tonight.
I have a new husband.
- Great Northern, 8:30?
- We'd Iove to.
- I don't think if I'II be abIe to get there.
- We'II be fine, honey.
Eight-thirty sharp, we'II be there.
- Harry?
- Oh, heIIo, Pete.
What you got?
Woodpecker.
PiIeated, I think.
Yeah. Here.
PiIeated woodpecker.
Outstanding.
Harry?
Yeah, Pete.
Harry, Josie's gone.
Yeah, I know.
When I came home
from the Iate shift,
she Ieft a note on the kitchen tabIe,
no expIanations, no goodbyes.
A note.
She soId the miII to Ben Horne.
WeII, not exactIy.
You don't have to expIain.
I Ioved her.
There. I said it.
No offense, Harry.
I Ioved her too.
I stood there and watched her go.
Watched her assistant
carry her bags away.
Her assistant?
Yeah, Asian feIIow.
Never saw him before.
What did he Iook Iike?
Average height,
medium buiId, ponytaiI.
Oh, that was her cousin, Jonathan.
She said it was her assistant,
Mr. Lee.
Mr. Lee?
Harry, I have a bad feeIing.
- I'm right there with you, Pete.
- Harry.
HeIIo, Pete. Gerard's missing.
He knocked the deputy out.
Pete, you'II have to excuse us.
He don't get far.
Hi, sheriff. Agent Cooper.
Lucy?
- Lucy?
- What?
Andy?
Step right in, Pete.
We desperate criminaIs
are Iocked safeIy in our cages.
I have a message for you.
Greetings from the boys
down at the miII?
But first, a IittIe music.
Hello, Benjamin.
Oh, l'm sorry l haven't
dropped by for a visit, dear.
But l have a strong aversion
to prisons.
- How awful--
- She's aIive?
The night we spent together
lost in love.
When was that?
lt seems so long ago.
Almost like a dream.
Oh, yes, l remember,
it was the night Laura Palmer died.
Memory is so unreliable finally,
maybe it was a dream.
Maybe it never happened.
To tell you the truth,
l can't be sure anymore.
What does she want? I'II pay anything.
What does she want?
You okay there, Benji?
ln exchange for my testimony, dear,
you will sign the mill and
Ghostwood Estates back over to me.
l will consider letting you keep
your precious hotel.
A representative of mine
will come to you
with the documents within 2 4 hours.
lf you won't cooperate...
Well, l'm confident
that you'll go on from here
to excel in one or another
of the many fine career opportunities
offered by the federal
prison system.
Ben, so nice to see you again.
She set me up.
That Catherine.
She's a cautioned, isn't she?
You set me up!
You bitch! You bitch!
I'II get you, you bitch.
Set me up.
Chicks and ducks and geese
Better scurry
When l take you out in the surrey
With the fringe on top
Harry, are driver education programs
mandatory in your schooI system?
Yep.
I think we got a dropout.
Harry, Iook out.
With the fringe on top
LeIand.
Agent Cooper, Harry, I'm sorry.
- Are you two aII right?
- LeIand, we're fine. How about you?
Oh, sure, I'm fine, I'm fine.
I was just on my way to the cIub
to try out a new set of irons,
and I must have started
thinking about Ben.
I guess my mind just wandered.
It's a good idea to Ieave your troubIes
at home when operating a vehicIe.
You're right, of course.
My apoIogies.
I did remember something, as
you asked, about the night Laura died.
I was working Iate at the office
with Ben, it was about 1 0:00.
He Ieft the room
to make a phone caII.
I don't know who he was taIking to, but
his voice was raised, he was angry.
I heard him mention
something about
a dairy.
- A dairy?
- That's what I think, yes.
- A diary.
- That couId be it.
Sheriff Truman, Sheriff Truman,
this is Lucy.
Are you there, sheriff?
l have an urgent message from Hawk.
- Do you pIay goIf, Agent Cooper?
- Yes, LeIand, I enjoy its precision.
I'd Iike to invite you for a round
at the cIub someday.
May I show you my new cIubs?
Sure.
Cooper.
They found Gerard.
Near the waterfaII.
Better go. They're waiting for us.
Let's go get him. LeIand,
we'II see those cIubs another time.
I understand, Agent Cooper.
You Iet me know
- if there's anything I can do to heIp.
- WiII do.
Poor Andy.
You know, the exact same thing
happened to me
when I first got pregnant.
I wouId be out shopping,
and then boom, pass right out
in the produce section.
Then come to covered in bruises
and crushed fruit,
and strangers standing over me
waiting to see if I was dead.
You see, peopIe want terribIe things
to happen to you, I know.
I wanna taIk to you
about my sperms.
Sperms?
You know, that is aII men think about.
You know, I remember
when IittIe CarI was first born
and they Iaid him out on my breast,
I Iooked down and saw what kind of
a tiny IittIe creature I was deaIing with.
And I thought to myseIf, I thought,
''My God, just what the worId needs,
another sperm gun running around
Ioose. Right? Women beware.''
WeII, I did.
I had mine counted twice.
The first time, they were aII dead.
Oh, man, if I had a nickeI
every time I heard that one.
- Second time, they were jumping Iike--
- What? What?
--Iike saImon swimming upstream.
So, of course,
aII you couId think of was spawning.
- Shut up.
- Shut up, Gwen.
So when you toId me that you were
pregnant, I didn't think it couId be me
because mine were aII dead
supposedIy at the time.
But they got better.
I was misinformed. I'm the father.
Oh, brother.
Aren't I?
Oh, yeah. Oh, come here.
You want to see
your mean Aunt Lucy.
Oh, aren't you neat,
you IittIe snooky-bookems.
He's been cIose.
Bob is not here now.
Sheriff. Sheriff?
Isn't there something
that you'd Iike to share with us?
Oh, great.
And wouId you teII this guy to stop
staring at me Iike I'm a dog biscuit.
Bob has been very cIose.
Who's Bob? I don't know a Bob.
Do we know a Bob?
Sheriff, no offense, but cIearIy,
this man's stairs do not reach the attic.
Now, your 24 hours are up.
You either charge my cIient
or Iet him go!
Ben Horne, I'm charging you
with the murder of Laura PaImer.
Yeah. Good move, Jer.
Hawk, take Mr. Gerard
back to the hoteI.
- NaiI aII the windows shut.
- No. No.
- I want two men on the door.
- You two-bit Iumberjack.
- You are finished in this town.
- Don't make it worse.
You're finished.
- CaIm down. What are you doing?
- Step outside, pIease?
I'm aII right.
Harry. Harry, I think we're saddIing
the horse before we're ready to ride.
I don't foIIow.
I don't think Ben Horne
kiIIed Laura PaImer.
- What?
- You shouId reIease him.
Cooper?
I've backed you every step of the way.
I've had enough of the mumbo jumbo.
I've had enough of the dreams,
the visions, the dwarfs, the giants,
Tibet and the rest
of the hocus-pocus.
Now, we've got hard evidence
against Ben Horne.
It's my job to Iock him up.
You're right, Harry.
This is your back yard.
Sometimes an outsider
can forget that.
WeII, the saImon was fresh and firm
and just a IittIe bit overdone.
- Mine too.
- Just right.
WouId you excuse me
for a minute, pIease?
I'II join you.
Ladies, hurry back.
You're not gonna say anything,
are you?
If Vivian ever found out
I'd been inside she'd--
She'd drop me fIat.
I Iike your new hair coIor.
Ernie NiIes.
Ernie ''The Professor'' NiIes.
- So when did you?
- A coupIe of weeks ago.
Let me teII you, Ernie,
without you in there to paI around with
the Iast six months were sheer heII.
Nobody to go to the Iibrary with.
Nobody to stamp out
Iicense pIates with.
So, what's your angIe here
with Miss Moneybags?
No angIe.
Come on, buddy,
we don't have any secrets.
Vivian's roIIing in dough.
I met Vivian
at a RepubIican fundraiser.
We're married.
You must have toId her
some taII taIe, a whopper.
I'm trying very hard to teII nothing
but the truth these days.
It's therapeutic.
And Vivian wants me to handIe
aII her investments.
What about yours?
Introduce her to your Ioan shark?
I'm out of it, I'm out of it, Hank.
I don't gambIe anymore.
I go to meetings. I go to church too.
So, what happens when
Vivian finds out that you ran off
- with the congregation's picnic fund?
- I never stoIe from a church.
It was a savings and Ioan.
I was sick, it was an iIIness.
I paid my debt.
It's a new Iife, a cIean-- CIean sIate.
- So she reaIIy doesn't know?
- No.
WeII, Ernie, this is interesting to me.
Because famiIy is the most
important thing in the worId to me.
One must be prepared
to pay any price to protect it.
Don't you agree?
Oh, yeah, yeah. I compIeteIy agree.
We'II taIk more Iater, Ernie.
I've aIways enjoyed
our taIks in the yard,
man-to-man, prisoner-to-prisoner.
- We're back.
- Ladies.
I wouId Iike to propose a toast
to the newIyweds
and their happiness.
Thank you, Henry.
It's very generous.
To Ernie and Vivian,
to much success in their future
and aII their future deaIings.
How sweet.
That's sweet.
Diane, it's 1 1 :05 p.m. I'm in my room
at the Great Northern HoteI.
There's not a star in the sky tonight.
Ben Horne is in custody.
The traiI narrows, Diane.
I'm very cIose,
but the Iast few steps are aIways
the darkest and most difficuIt.
- Hi.
- Audrey?
- Can I come in and taIk?
- AII right.
- Is that where you got shot?
- Yeah.
Did you arrest him?
Yeah.
Did he do it?
That's for a court to decide.
What do you think?
What I think
doesn't reaIIy matter right now.
Did you arrest him
because of what I said?
OnIy in part.
But it heIped?
Yeah.
AII I ever reaIIy wanted
was for him to Iove me.
I'm sure that he does.
He's ashamed of me.
No, he's not.
Agent Cooper,
when I was at One-Eyed Jack's,
I never, never Iet anyone--
Audrey, you don't have
to say anything.
I want you to know.
I know.
I have to get that.
Okay.
Cooper here. Where?
How Iong ago?
- I'm on my way.
- What's wrong?
I want you to go to your room
and Iock the door.
- Why?
- No questions, do what I say.
AII right.
It's Maddy Ferguson.
www.tvsubtitles.net