Agent Cooper.
Can you hear me? It's Andy.
Agent Cooper, it's Andy.
Can you hear me?
Agent Cooper?
Room service.
How are you doing down there?
Warm milk.
Agent Cooper?
Would you put it on the table, please?
- And would you call a doctor?
- Sure.
Are you aII right? Can you hear me?
Agent Cooper.
Agent Cooper, it's Andy.
Can you hear me?
Are you aII right?
Agent Cooper. Agent Cooper.
Agent Cooper.
It's Andy.
It's An--
l hung it up for you.
What's that?
Hung it up for you.
Did you call the doctor?
The doctor?
lt's hung up.
The phone.
Thank you.
Sure.
No problem.
Does this include a gratuity?
Yes, sir.
Thank you. Thank you kindly.
The milk will get cool on you.
- Pretty soon.
- Okay.
l've heard about you.
l heard about you.
l will tell you three things.
lf l tell them to you
and they come true,
then will you believe me?
Who's that?
Think of me as a friend.
Where do you come from?
The question is,
where have you gone?
The first thing l will tell you is,
there's a man
in a smiling bag.
Man in a smiling bag.
Second thing is,
the owls are not what they seem.
Third thing is,
without chemicals, he points.
What do these things mean?
This is all l am permitted to say.
Give me your ring.
l will return it to you
when you find these things to be true.
We want to help you.
Who's ''we''?
One last thing.
Leo locked inside hungry horse.
There's a clue at Leo's house.
You will require medical attention.
Knock, knock, knock.
Come on.
Let's have a look at the new girl.
Vixen.
What room is Ben in?
The little flower room.
- Why is he holding out on me?
- What?
- What's that, Blackie?
Who's holding out on who?
Please.
Oh, Blackie.
You used to be so pretty.
Blackie, Blackie.
Bastard.
l think you should go now.
- Do you, Prudence?
- Yes, l do. l really do.
All right.
lf you insist.
Gotcha.
l will huff
and puff,
and blow your house down.
Oh, my, my.
Aren't you something?
l've got to see you. l must see you.
Go away. l'm shy.
Didn't they tell you who l was?
The owner?
That's right.
Ben, it's Jer.
We got a situation.
- So have l.
- Brother Ben, we got a S-N-A-G.
- Alas, l do have a situation.
- Come on, Ben.
Coming, Jer.
l like you.
You know how to interest a man.
That's half the battle.
Next time,
we will play a different game.
l'll make the rules.
You'll like it. Fun game.
Everybody wins.
Diane.
My recorder is on the table.
l'm unable to reach it at this time.
l can only hope
that l inadvertently pressed
the voice activation button.
l'm lying on the floor of my room.
l've been shot.
There's a great deal of pain
and a fair amount of blood.
Fortunately, l was wearing
my bulletproof vest last night,
per bureau regulations
when working undercover.
l remember folding the vest up,
trying to chase down a wood tick.
lf you can imagine the impact
on your chest
of three bowling balls dropped
from a height of about 9 feet,
you might begin
to approximate the sensation.
All things considered,
being shot is not as bad
as l always thought it might be.
As long as you can keep
the fear from your mind.
But l guess you could say that
about almost anything in life.
lt's not so bad as long as you can keep
the fear from your mind.
Oh, my God.
The ring is gone.
At a time like this, curiously,
you begin to think
of the things you regret
or the things you might miss.
l would like, in general, to treat people
with much more care and respect.
l would like to climb a tall hill.
Not too tall.
Sit in the cool grass.
Not too cool.
And feel the sun on my face.
l wish l could have cracked
the Lindbergh kidnapping case.
l would very much like
to make love to a beautiful woman
who l had genuine affection for.
And of course, it goes without saying
that l would like to visit Tibet.
l wish they could get their country back
and the Dalai Lama could return.
Oh, l would like that very much.
All in all,
a very interesting experience.
They're here.
My skin was itching.
Wood tick was crawling.
l lifted my bulletproof vest.
Three slugs.
Point-blank range.
That explains this.
Hell of a way to kill a tick.
Did you get a look at the gunman?
l saw a masked face, muzzle flash.
Lucy, you better bring Agent Cooper
up-to-date.
Leo Johnson was shot.
Jacques Renault was strangled.
The mill burned.
Shelly and Pete got smoke inhalation.
Catherine and Josie are missing.
Nadine is in a coma
from taking sleeping pills.
- How long have l been out?
- lt's 7:45 in the morning.
We haven't had this much action
in one night
since the Elk's Club fire of '59.
Harry, we need to get a search warrant
for Leo Johnson's house.
No need. Leo was shot
in his own living room.
Deputy Brennan found him.
- You're not going anywhere.
- Doc. When the will is invoked,
the recuperative powers of the physical
body are simply extraordinary.
Just give me a couple of hours
to get dressed.
I'm standing just in front of
where a massive Iog-storage area
of the Packard Saw MiII
burned to the ground,
under what fire department
investigators are caIIing
''mysterious circumstances. ''
Now, poIice officiaIs have toId me
that they have, as of yet,
- Bobby.
- uncovered no apparent Iink
between these two
seemingIy unreIated
- Bobby.
- tragedies.
Reporting Iive
from the Packard Saw MiII...
Cooper, this is totally
against my recommendations.
lt's all right, doc. Duly noted.
You got two busted ribs,
your cartilage is a mess.
Who knows what else is wrong?
What's that?
Jacques Renault.
ls that bag smiling?
Smiling?
What's there to smile about?
Do you miss Beth?
What?
Have you been missing your mom?
- Aunt Sarah?
- Yeah?
l had the strangest dream last night.
About what?
The rug.
Right here.
Right from this angle
where l'm sitting.
Was Laura in it?
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
Now, if the words sound queer
And funny to your ear
A IittIe bit jumbIed and jivey
Say, ''Mares eat oats
And does eat oats
And IittIe Iambs eat ivy''
Leland?
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
Morning, dears.
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
Oh, Leland.
Uncle Leland's hair turned white.
Leland, come back here.
Oh, God.
Okay. Agenda.
One.
l want a location on Catherine.
Keep our distance, just make sure
she's ready to take the fall.
Two.
l want a complete medical
on Leo Johnson
and his prospects for recovery
and a satisfactory explanation
from Hank Jennings
why Leo isn't being measured
for a plot in Ghostwood Memorial Park.
Well begun is half done.
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
Oh, Mairzy Doats and Dozy Doats
And IiddIe Iamzy divey
A kiddIey divey too, wouIdn't you?
Now, if the words sound queer
And funny to your ear
A IittIe bit jumbIed and jivey
Say, ''Mares eat oats
And does eat oats
And IittIe Iambs eat ivy''
l'm back.
Back and ready.
But the bullet came from outside.
How do you figure?
Sheriff, a picture is forming.
Big ax on the couch.
These same geese were flying
that evening.
Leo was trying to turn someone
into kindling.
That person hit the TV, moved it.
You can see the depression
in the carpet.
Shelly?
Shelly Johnson's about 99 pounds
soaking wet.
This is a big TV.
Leo advanced, ax raised.
Then what happened?
Bullet came through the window,
knocked Leo back onto the couch.
Do you think it was Shelly
who pulled the trigger?
Sheriff, get your mind off Shelly,
for a moment.
We won't know about Shelly until we
find out what time she got to the mill.
Surprise. FIesh WorId.
Hey, what issue is this?
Still no cocaine.
Here or in the truck.
But l found this in the truck.
Leo's duster.
- Reeks of gasoline.
- The mill.
Good work, Hawk.
Harry, do you know who it is?
- Harry.
- What's that?
- Harry, do you know who it is?
- lt's Andy.
He seems pretty upset
about something.
Harry, it's Agent Rosenflower.
Andy, are you all right?
Hey, Andy.
Are you all right?
And it's another great moment
in law enforcement history.
Hey, Albert.
Looks like you were more right
than you know.
Looks like a new pair of boots
and a lot of cocaine.
Andy.
Good work.
Hot damn that pie is good!
Here's Laura's glasses
that you wanted.
Thanks.
Donna, do you see these glasses
that l'm wearing?
Yeah.
l hate them.
l'm never wearing these again.
Okay.
ls it true about James?
He spent the night in jail.
Do you think
it's because of what we did?
Look, we don't know
if we did anything.
My dad said Jacoby got sick
because he was attacked.
All we did was send him a tape.
Maybe he wouldn't have been attacked
if we hadn't.
Maybe. Maybe the sun won't come
up tomorrow if you wash your hair.
Think like that and you're gonna
go crazy. What's done is done.
The only way this won't come back
to haunt us
is if we keep quiet
about what happened last night.
l can assure you
James is doing the same thing.
Get the picture?
Loud and clear.
Uncle Leland's hair turned white.
Really?
White as a sheet.
Weird.
Donna, l have something for you.
Came here to the Double R
yesterday.
Thanks, Norma.
- God.
- What is it?
''Look into the Meals on Wheels.''
How simple can l make it, Cooper?
FBl agent gets shot,
FBl agent investigates.
l'm in proximity, work in the Seattle lab,
l'm familiar with the underlying case.
- Does that hurt?
- Yes.
Albert, the point is, you're not gonna
win any local popularity contests.
No, the point is
Gordon Cole ordered me back here.
Breathe.
Again.
Okay.
You were shot by a right-handed
person, 5'6'' to 5'1 0'' tall,
at a distance of less than 3 feet.
l'll have ballistics this afternoon.
- You're still blank on the other details?
- Yes.
What was your vest doing
riding up like that?
Wood tick.
Meanwhile, one of your principal
suspects is killed in his hospital bed,
the other is shot in his living room.
Vigilante justice
or just clean country living?
Albert, where does this attitude of
general unpleasantness come from?
l'll have to get back to you on that.
lf you don't want two black eyes
on a regular basis,
l suggest you make
some kind of peace with rural life.
Great. After the square dance,
maybe we can all take a hayride.
Come in.
Andy, how's the nose?
Not a mark on it,
only blood squirted out.
Where do they keep his water dish?
Albert.
Agent Cooper, guess what.
l have the answer to the riddle
that you told me this morning.
l called Hungry Horse, Montana.
The word ''locked.''
Leo Johnson was locked in a jail
in Hungry Horse, Montana.
When, Andy?
''February 9, 1 988.''
Teresa Banks.
Looks like Leo has an alibi for the night
Teresa Banks was murdered.
Good work, Andy.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
- ls Sheriff Truman here?
- He is, but he is busy at the moment.
May l help you?
l'm afraid l don't have an appointment.
The sheriff asked me to stop by
at my convenience.
This is the first convenient moment.
May l ask what this is regarding?
l'm here to sell him some shoes.
Shoes?
Here comes Mom
with miIk and cookies.
Later, Lawrence.
Bye-bye.
You got this tape
from Dr. Jacoby's office?
Yeah.
That's breaking and entering, James.
The door was open.
How did you know
Jacoby wouldn't be there?
l knocked, nobody answered.
- You were alone?
- Yeah.
Okay. l know
you were trying to help,
but there's some people
who might not see it that way.
Especially with 3 ounces of cocaine
in your gas tank.
You know l didn't put that there.
l think it was probably
Mike and Bobby.
- Yeah.
- Harry,
Laura talks on her tape
about a mystery man.
A red Corvette. Leo Johnson.
l think it was somebody else.
Not Jacques Renault either.
- Why do you say that?
- l never put it together
until l heard the tape. Where she says,
''This guy can really light my fire.''
Well, l remember this one night when
we first started seeing each other.
She was still doing drugs then.
Well, we were in the woods and
she started saying this scary poem,
over and over, about fire.
And then she said,
''Would you like to play with fire,
little boy?''
''Would you like to play with Bob?''
- What did she mean by that?
- l don't know.
Laura said a lot of nutty stuff.
Half the time,
it just went right by you.
This stuck, though.
James, l'll get right to the point.
l know you have the other half
of Laura Palmer's necklace.
l want it. Give it to me.
How?
Well, this was in Jacoby's office.
lt was in a coconut.
A coconut?
Hawk, take James back to his cell.
Jacoby?
How did you know
he had the necklace?
Laura and James were in love.
l figured he had to have
the other half of the necklace,
but if he had the other half,
he would have given it to us
to help with the case.
Then it dawned on me.
Something or someone
frightened him off.
He had to have it,
so l asked him for it.
Jacoby?
l didn't figure he had anything
to do with this at all.
Sometimes you just get lucky.
Donna?
Hi, Lucy.
l'm here to see James.
How are you doing?
Did you tell them anything?
They haven't asked me anything.
When did you start smoking?
l smoke every once in a while.
Helps relieve tension.
When did you get so tense?
When l started smoking.
Did you tell them anything?
l didn't tell them
about you or Maddy.
Do they think Leo killed Laura?
l don't know what they think.
How is Maddy?
She's fine.
She hasn't said anything either.
So don't you wanna kiss me?
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
Or is it just not okay
for me to want you?
Get out soon, James.
Lucy.
Andy.
ln these boxes
is every edition of FIesh WorId
published for the past three years.
This is a picture of Teresa Banks,
the first victim,
who was found murdered a year ago
in the southern part of the state.
Now, Laura and Ronette's photographs
appeared in ads in the magazines.
You want us to look for a picture
of Teresa Banks.
Andy, you're way ahead of me.
Lucy, Sheriff Truman and l
will be at the hospital.
Behave yourselves.
Diane, just received the back issues
of FIesh WorId. Good work.
lt's nice to see some cooperation
with the law,
especially from a company
that preys on human weaknesses.
Lucy, l sure feel uncomfortable
being in this situation with you.
Why? We're both professionals.
ls he on something?
Only what you prescribed.
l think he did take
a little bit of his food.
My God, could that be it?
Agent Cooper.
Why don't you tell the psychiatrist
about your broken ribs
and torn cartilage.
Well, well, well.
What happened to you?
l don't want any baloney, magic tricks
or psychological mumbo jumbo.
l want you to tell us
how you came into possession of this
or l am gonna have to place you
under arrest for obstruction of justice.
Look, l told you.
The night after Laura died,
l followed a man in a red Corvette.
Leo Johnson.
Correct.
Then he eluded me somewhere
near the old sawmill road.
As l sat there, cursing my--
My lack of horsepower,
a motorcycle drove by.
Followed by a police cruiser.
But you lost them.
They went into the woods.
l saw them.
l followed them in there on foot.
- James and Donna?
- Yes, they...
They spoke intently for a while, but
l couldn't hear what they were saying.
I remember it was...
It was a coId night in the woods.
FinaIIy, they...
They buried something in the ground,
under a rock.
lll-advisedly, perhaps,
l took it as a keepsake.
lt was her, you see.
The necklace.
A divided heart.
Laura was--
Was, in fact...
Well, she was living a double life.
Two people.
Yeah, but then...
Then when l saw her
that last time, she...
l don't know, she seemed
to have reached a kind of--
A peace with herself.
Now l believe that
what she had in fact arrived at
was a decision to end her life.
Are you saying Laura wanted to die?
Doctor,
Laura Palmer
did not commit suicide.
No, no.
But maybe she allowed herself
to be killed.
One more thing.
You were in intensive care last night
when Jacques Renault was killed.
Yeah, yes.
But l mean, come on, fellows.
l was heavily sedated and...
Did you see anything? Hear anything?
l remember hearing
a fire alarm go off, but...
lt's...
lt's all like a...
Like a dream.
There was a smell.
Yeah, there was a peculiar smell.
lt's usual in case of strangulation
for the victim to void his bowels.
No.
No, that wasn't it, this...
This was a smell like...
Like oil.
Scorched engine oil.
Dr. BradIey, caII the operator.
Dr. BradIey,
caII the operator, pIease.
Hey, sleeping beauty.
Bobby.
What are you doing here?
What if someone sees you?
l don't care.
l do not care anymore.
Leo's in the hospital.
Somebody shot him.
Yeah, l know. l mean, l heard
there's cops outside his room.
- Really?
- l hear they're gonna bust him.
He must have got caught
doing something, poor bastard.
What happened to you?
Bobby, l'm so afraid.
Leo tried to kill me.
He knows about us.
He took me up to the mill,
and he tied me up
and started the fire.
Bobby,
he told me he was gonna kill you.
Fat chance.
l won't let him hurt us anymore.
Are you all right?
Doctors seem to think so.
You know, Shelly,
hospitals are dangerous places.
First of all, they're crawling
with sick people.
And second of all,
that food can kill you.
So if you wanna
get out of here pronto,
you're gonna have to let Bobby
be your doctor.
So let's just have a look here,
Miss Shelly.
Oh, you seem to be
coming along splendidly.
Deep breath.
l'd say you're on your way
to a complete recovery.
You better go.
You're my girl.
Bobby.
l love you.
l guess l love you too.
Yeah, l guess l love you too.
Bobby Briggs.
- What's he doing here?
- He doesn't look sick.
Sheriff Truman, to see this kind
of investigative genius at work,
it's just a real treat for me.
Ed.
How are you doing?
l heard you stopped a couple.
l'm okay. How's Nadine?
Well, she's in a coma.
They say there's nothing we could do.
She has to wanna come back.
How are you holding up?
Well, all l can do is sit here,
thinking about the things
l should have said or done.
Ed, don't be too hard on yourself.
l never believed in fate,
Agent Cooper.
l always felt
you make your own way, you take care
of your own, you pick up after yourself.
Farmer's AImanac?
Albert, l would like
to speak to Ed.
Albert, l'll buy you a cup of coffee.
Take a seat, Ed.
l saw this coming.
l didn't wanna believe it.
What's worse is l'm sitting thinking
that maybe there's a part of me
that didn't wanna stop her.
And that's a full load.
When did you get married, Ed?
Right out of high school.
Norma and l had been together
about four years.
Everybody figured we'd get hitched.
That'd be that.
l barely knew Nadine to say hello to.
That spring, one bad weekend,
Norma ran off with Hank.
l was so twisted up inside,
l couldn't see straight.
When l opened my eyes,
there was Nadine,
right in front of me.
There was something so sweet,
so helpless about her.
We drove all night.
Ended up in some little town
in Montana, out past Great Falls,
and l asked her to marry me.
Half joking, half drunk, half crazy.
lt was light before we found
a justice of the peace.
And Norma...
Well, she hadn't even
slept with Hank.
The look on her face
when she found out...
Nadine and l, we went up to my dad's
old cabin up in Eagle Pass.
Honeymoon.
l was hoping maybe we'd get around
to talking about a divorce,
annulment, something.
But Nadine was so happy.
And you know, by golly,
l shot out Nadine's eye
on that honeymoon.
What do you mean, Ed?
The first day,
we were hunting pheasant.
Nadine's a crack shot
and we already had a couple of birds.
And l felt good shooting.
Listening to the sound echoing,
roll down those hills.
l fired.
A piece of buckshot skipped off a rock
and caught Nadine square in the eye.
Man, that's a tough one.
She laid across my lap
as we drove back to town.
She never cried.
She never blamed me.
She never hated me for it.
Couple of months later,
Norma married Hank.
So l don't believe in fate.
You make your bed, you sleep in it.
Sorry.
Ed, someone here to see you.
A man in a smiling bag.
Take James right back to the station
when you're done here.
Poor Ed.
Poor Nadine.
- Yeah.
Albert, why don't you
take this opportunity
to check in
at The Great Northern.
Nurse, l really mean it,
you better speak to that kitchen.
Harry, when Albert finishes up
at The Great Northern,
we'll meet back at the station.
l'm ready to lay the whole thing out.
Rocks and bottles?
Chalk and blackboard
will be just fine.
- Jelly doughnuts?
- Harry, that goes without saying.
l'll come back later
and l'll bring some soup.
The food in these places will kill you
quicker than most diseases.
So l hear.
Now, you know
l have a sweet tooth too.
l've got
a chocolate-peanut butter pie.
Norma, l'm serious.
Bring the whole pie.
l'll bring you two.
Okay.
- Feel better, sweetie.
- Bye.
Bye.
Son.
Dad.
Would you...
...care to join me?
Okay.
How was school today?
School?
Fine.
That's good.
How was work?
Work? Work was good.
- Dad?
- Yes, son.
What is it that you do, exactly?
That's classified.
Bobby, would you care
for a piece of pie?
The huckleberries are particularly
delicious today.
Particularly fresh and delicious.
No, thanks.
Bobby,
may l share something with you?
Okay.
A vision l had in my sleep last night.
As distinguished from a dream,
which is mere sorting
and cataloging
of the day's events
by the subconscious.
This was a vision.
Fresh and clear
as a mountain stream.
The mind revealing itself to itself.
ln my vision,
l was on the veranda
of a vast estate,
a palazzo
of some fantastic proportion.
There seemed to emanate from it
a light from within this
gleaming, radiant marble.
l'd known this place. l had, in fact,
been born and raised there.
This was my first return.
A reunion with the deepest
well springs of my being.
Wandering about, l noticed happily
that the house had been
immaculately maintained.
There had been added a number
of additional rooms,
but in a way that blended so seamlessly
with the original construction,
one would never detect
any difference.
Returning to the house's
grand foyer,
there came a knock at the door.
My son was standing there.
He was happy and carefree.
Clearly living a life
of deep harmony and joy.
We embraced.
A warm and loving embrace,
nothing withheld.
We were, in this moment, one.
My vision ended and l awoke
with a tremendous feeling
of optimism and confidence
in you and your future.
That was my vision of you.
Really?
l'm so glad to have had this opportunity
to share it with you.
l wish you nothing
but the very best in all things.
Thank you, Dad.
- See you later. Call.
- Okay.
Major?
How was the pie?
Exceptional, as always.
How is Shelly?
l can't talk right now.
Well, how did she like the flowers?
The night Laura Palmer was killed, it
appears she made two appointments.
ln her diary she had written,
''Nervous about meeting J tonight.''
l now believe this was a reference
to James Hurley.
She was nervous
because she planned to tell him
she didn't wanna see him anymore.
Before she snuck out of the house,
she received a phone call.
We believe it was Leo Johnson
making the second appointment
for sometime later that night.
Laura met James,
was with him until 1 2:30,
when, at the intersection
of Sparkwood and 21 ,
she jumped from the bike
and ran into the woods.
We believe she met up there
with Jacques Renault,
Leo Johnson and Ronette Pulaski.
Together, they drove to the foot
of the trail leading to Jacques's cabin.
They climbed the trail, they were heard
passing by the cabin of the Log Lady.
They reached Jacques Renault's cabin
at approximately 1 a.m.
Drugs and alcohol were consumed.
Laura was tied up
and had sexual relations
with both Leo and Jacques.
Waldo the bird was let out of his cage
and attacked Laura.
Leo and Jacques fought.
Jacques went outside and passed out.
When he came to,
Leo and the girls were gone.
We believe Leo hiked back down
the trail to his Corvette alone,
leaving the girls behind.
The reason being,
there was a third man.
Deputy Hawk found evidence
of a third man
outside the window
of Jacques's cabin.
The third man took Laura and Ronette
to the train where they were tied up.
Laura for the second time,
Ronette for the first.
Using a blunt object,
the killer hit Ronette
and knocked her unconscious.
He must have been so intent
on killing Laura,
he didn't realize that Ronette
regained consciousness and escaped.
Either he didn't know
or he didn't care.
He made a small mound of dirt
and put the half-heart necklace
of Laura's on top.
He then placed a small cut out letter R
under the nail of her left ring finger.
You'll recall that he placed the letter T
under the fingernail of Teresa Banks.
He left a note written in blood,
''Fire walk with me.''
Here's the interesting thing.
The blood on the note was tested.
lt doesn't match Leo's,
Jacques's, Laura's or Ronette's.
So we surmise the killer wrote the note
in his own blood.
lt's a rare type, AB negative.
The towel that Deputy Hawk found
five miles down the tracks
was soaked in blood of that type.
He also found, near the towel,
scraps of faded paper.
These scraps may have been left
by the killer.
They'll be sent back
to Washington D.C. for testing.
l know, Andy.
l know, l know, l know.
lt's what we call
a real three-hankie crime.
Albert Rozerfeld,
l don't like the way you talk smart
about Sheriff Truman or anybody.
You just shut your mouth!
Laura Palmer is dead.
Jacques Renault is dead.
Ronette Pulaski and Leo Johnson
are in comas.
Waldo the bird is dead.
This leaves only the third man.
- You want this door closed?
- Yeah, yeah. We'll frost our rooms.
- l sure do appreciate the ride, Harry.
- No problem.
l always appreciate
your company, Pete.
Boy, this smoke inhalation
is nasty business.
l feel like somebody taped my lips
to the tailpipe of a bus.
Take her easy.
- So where the hell is Josie?
- Oh, well, maybe this will tell us.
''Dear Pete,
l had to leave the town
on an emergency
of business to Seattle.
l will phone you when l arrive.
Hope you did a good day
at the mill.
There is ginger beer in the refrig.
Love, Josie.'' There you go.
- ls there a phone number in there?
- No.
- Does she say where she's staying?
- No, no, she goes off to Seattle
once every three months or so.
You want my opinion, l think she goes
over there to indulge a secret vice.
- What's that?
- Shopping.
Comes back
with half a department store.
Pete,
we haven't found Catherine.
Yeah.
l figured.
l know you wanna hope for the best,
but you ought to prepare for the worst.
Oh, dear.
l always figured
l'd be the one to go first.
l mean, if you was laying odds
on the last person standing
after an atomic war,
l'd have bet on her.
Yeah, she was a tiger, all right.
No use mincing words,
she was plain hell to live with.
Plain hell.
But...
...once, there was a little bit
of heaven there too.
Oh, l'm sure there was.
Oh, God.
This will take a little while
to sink in, l suppose.
l suppose it will.
God help her miserable soul.
l loved her.
Blue Pine Lodge.
Could l speak to Josie Packard,
please?
- WeII, she's not here right now.
- Can you tell me when she'll be back?
Well, she's out of town.
Who's calling?
l'd like to place
an international call, please.
Collect to Hong Kong.
Doesn't that sound...?
l mean, l ate it,
but l didn't really know what it was.
l read about it in this French magazine,
and they take the entire head and dip it
in a kind of blancmange pudding.
And then they roll it in oats and stuff it
full of walnuts and hot rocks
- and a spice cookie.
- Mr. Horne, Mr. Horne.
- They wrap it in papiIIon.
They seal the edges
with a sugar glaze
- and bake it under glass.
- Mr. Horne, Mr. Horne.
That sounds incredible.
lt is to die for.
Have you seen Audrey today?
No, l haven't.
Hank Jennings.
Jerry and Benjamin Horne.
Where's Josie?
She left last night.
Prearranged?
She wanted to put a little distance
between her and the smell of smoke.
Sound strategy.
Next business, Leo Johnson.
He's in a coma.
Looks like brain damage.
With Leo, how could they tell?
Why isn't he dead?
l caught him center shot with a .44.
Couldn't risk going inside.
Neighborhood was hot.
l had to sneak past patrols as it was.
Anybody see you?
Negative.
He was chopping wood.
Chopping wood? lnside?
- Yeah, you know Leo.
- Wait a minute.
- Chopping wood inside?
- Yeah.
You know Leo.
All right. What's next?
Catherine.
Dead?
My phone call put her in the drying
shed when the place went up.
Sounds like buried
with the wreckage.
Heat like that,
they'll be lucky to find teeth.
And they were such pretty teeth.
Marvelous.
Gentlemen,
if they don't hang the arson
on the late lamented Catherine
and her co-conspirator Leo,
l'll give up sex.
That's confidence.
What do we do with the ledger?
Hank,
you leave the creative thinking
to the brothers Horne.
You're a bicep.
Relax until we say, ''Flex.''
Now, that really makes me mad.
You guys.
Come in.
Why is the door to my room locked?
And who's the refrigerator?
The owner was a little disappointed
in your performance last night.
Well, the owner isn't exactly my type.
And what is your type exactly?
Not you. No offense.
Hey.
Let's get one thing straight
between us, princess.
Okay.
l don't wanna hear another complaint
about you.
When you work for me,
everybody's your type.
Norma?
Hi, it's Donna.
l'm calling about Meals on Wheels.
l'm gonna take over Laura's route
if that's okay with you.
Okay.
Great.
Listen, can l use the Double R
station wagon?
All right.
Great.
Then l'll see you tomorrow at 9.
Gersten's gonna tell us
about tonight's proceedings.
She has some very good news.
We're all very proud of her.
Good evening.
l'm Gersten Hayward
and l'd like to welcome you all
to the Hayward Supper Club.
l'm going to be playing
various selections
of music for you this evening.
My good news is
that l was chosen
to be the fairy princess
in my school play.
This is my special dress.
Also, l got the highest scores
in mathematics and English
this mid-season term.
Just as my sisters Harriet
and Donna did before me.
So now l don't have to worry
about being ashamed anymore.
Before l play,
Harriet would like to read a poem
about your daughter
and our friend Laura.
It was Laura
And I saw her gIowing
In the dark woods
I saw her smiIing
We were crying and I saw her
Laughing
In our sadness
I saw her dancing
It was Laura Iiving in my dreams
It was Laura
The gIow was Iife
Her smiIe was to say
It was aII right to cry
The woods was our sadness
The dance was her caIIing
It was Laura
And she came to kiss me goodbye
That was wonderful. Thank you.
Gersten.
Now l'm going to play Mendelssohn's
''Rondo Capriccioso, Opus 1 4.''
l got the list and map
for Meals on Wheels.
l'm going to start tomorrow.
Aces.
Long day, Will?
l feel like l've sat through
back-to-back operas.
ln med school, we learned to live
on three hours a night and cat naps.
lt's terrible about the mill.
Yeah. They say more
than 1 50 jobs may be lost.
Awful. Just awful.
l suppose this will open the door
for Ben Horne
and his big development plans.
Well, as his lawyer, and yours,
of course l can't comment.
Well, as your doctor, Leland,
what the hell happened to your hair?
lt is strange, isn't it?
Well, l just...
l woke up this morning,
looked in the mirror and there it was.
lt had literally changed overnight.
Well, considering
all you've been through...
You know, the funny thing about it is,
seeing it, l realized that l had
turned a corner somehow.
l feel a great deal
of sadness still, yes,
but it wasn't as overwhelming to me.
l physically felt as if a great weight
had been lifted from my heart.
- Perhaps it has.
Perhaps it has.
God, l feel like singing.
That would be very nice.
No, l really feel like singing a song.
- Leland?
- Come on, everybody. Get happy.
- ''Get Happy.''
- ''Get Happy''?
Forget your troubIes
And just get happy
You gotta pack aII your cares away
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
Get ready for the judgment day
The sun is shinin'
Come on, get happy
The Lord is waitin' to take your hand
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
We're going to that promised Iand
We're headin' cross the river
Wash your sins away in the tide
It's, oh, so peacefuI on the other side
Forget your troubIes
Come on, get happy
You better chase aII your cares away
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
Get ready for the judgment day
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
Get ready for the judgment day
Sing haIIeIujah
Come on, get happy
Get ready for the judgment d--
Donna, get my bag.
Leland?
- Dad, is he okay?
- l'm sure it's nothing serious.
Oh, God.
l feel happy.
''Begin the Beguine.''
Diane, it's 1 1 :55 p.m.,
approximately 1 9 hours
since the shooting incident
which nearly caused me
to make a premature purchase
of the proverbial farm.
l'm dog-tired.
A man can only go so long
without submitting to a period of rest.
For as we know from experiments
conducted on American Gls
during the Korean War,
sleep deprivation is a one-way ticket
to temporary psychosis.
And l'm working on a three-day jag.
l got so goofy last night, Diane,
lying here wondering
whether l was going to live or die,
that l thought l saw
a giant in my room.
Or perhaps that's a story
l'll save for another time.
This is me, Dale,
room 31 5 at The Great Northern Hotel,
signing off.
Special agent.
Special agent. Special agent.
Special agent, are you there?
l left you a note.
Didn't you get my note?
l slipped it under your door.
You must have seen it.
Well, l'm up here
at One-Eyed Jack's.
To be perfectly honest,
l think l'm in a little over my head.
Not that l can't handle it.
l mean, if l'm gonna help you out
with your investigations,
l'm sure l'll be put into situations
a lot more dangerous than this
on a fairly regular basis.
But it's just...
...you know, my first time out.
l could use a little expert guidance.
So you know,
there is a connection
between Horne's Department Store
and One-Eyed Jack's.
lt's my father, he owns the place.
Little ball of sleaze named Battis
helps to recruit some of the girls
from the perfume counter.
Tomorrow l'm gonna try to find out
if Laura and Ronette came up here.
l hope you won't think any less of me
for trying to help you.
You know, l promise l only did it
with the best of intentions.
And if there's any way...
lf there's any way in the world
that you can hear me right now,
please help me.
Help me. Help me.
Sorry to wake you.
l am not dreaming.
l forgot to tell you something.
You were right
about the smiling bag.
The things l tell you
will not be wrong.
Better to listen than to talk.
l believe you.
Don't search
for all the answers at once.
A path is formed
by laying one stone at a time.
One person saw the third man.
Three have seen him, yes,
but not his body.
One only known to you.
Ready now to talk.
One more thing.
You forgot something.
What?
Laura! Laura!
Laura!
www.tvsubtitles.net