Previously on "Twin Peaks"...
She's dead.
Wrapped in plastic.
Laura Palmer.
Diane. 11:30 am February 24th.
Entering the town of Twin Peaks.
I'll be meeting Sheriff Harry S Truman.
Shouldn't be too hard to remember that.
This is Special Agent Dale Cooper.
- FBI.
- Right.
There are irrefutable similarities that,
for obvious reasons, I cannot discuss,
that suggest
Laura Palmer was the second
and Ronnette Pulaski would've been
the third victim of the same killer.
Did you shoot this video, Bobby?
- No.
- If you didn't, then who did?
Dr Lawrence Jacoby, Agent Cooper.
Laura was a patient of mine.
Here's something
we haven't seen before.
A mound of dirt 1.5 feet in diameter.
On top is a gold necklace with a gold
heart... Correction, half a gold heart.
Sheriff, we've got to find out
who's got the other half.
- Give me the other half.
- No, we'll bury it.
Donna, who are you protecting?
There's a chance that the person
who committed these crimes
is from this town.
Possibly even someone you know.
Diane. 6:18 am Room 315,
Great Northern Hotel
up here in Twin Peaks.
Slept pretty well.
Non-smoking room, no tobacco smell.
That's a nice consideration
for the business traveller.
A hint of Douglas fir needles in the air.
As Sheriff Truman indicated, everything
this hotel promised, they delivered.
Clean, reasonably-priced
accommodations.
Telephone works, bathroom in tip-top
shape: no drips, plenty of hot water
and good steady pressure that could
be a side-benefit of the waterfall outside.
Mattress firm but not too firm. No lumps,
like that time I told you about in El Paso.
What a nightmare that was!
But I've told you that story
once or twice, haven't l, Diane?
Haven't tried the TV yet. Looks like
cable, probably no reception problems.
But the true test of any hotel
is that morning cup of coffee,
which I'll get back to you about.
Diane, it struck me again
earlier this morning,
there are two things
that continue to trouble me,
not only as an agent of the Bureau,
but as a human being.
What really went on between
Marilyn Monroe and the Kennedys?
And who really pulled
the trigger on JFK?
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You know, this is, excuse me,
a damn fine cup of coffee.
I've had I can't say how many
cups of coffee in my life.
This is one of the best.
I'd like two eggs over hard. It's hard on
the arteries, but old habits die hard.
About as hard as I want those eggs.
Bacon, super crispy.
Almost burned. Cremated.
That's great.
And I'll have the grapefruit juice,
just as long as those grapefruits...
are freshly squeezed.
Audrey Horne.
Federal Bureau of Investigation
Special Agent Dale Cooper.
Can I sit here?
Unless I miss my guess,
your father is Benjamin Horne,
the owner of this establishment, so I
imagine you can sit anywhere you like.
- I'd also add, it would be my pleasure.
- Thank you.
You're here investigating
the murder of Laura Palmer.
Were you friends?
Not exactly. Laura tutored my older
brother Johnny three times a week.
Johnny's 27
and he's in the third grade.
He's got emotional problems.
It runs in the family.
Do you like my ring?
Very nice.
You know, sometimes
I get so flushed, it's interesting.
Do your palms ever itch?
Morning, Deputy.
Hey, Lucy.
Agent Cooper,
I got a jelly for you specially.
The Sheriff's in the conference room.
It's the door across from the...
I'll look for him in the conference room.
Hey, three for three.
Let's get James Hurley from cell four
and talk to him. He loved Laura Palmer.
I bet she told him whatever dirt
she knew about Mike and Bobby.
Then let's chat
with those two perpetrators.
Let's run a top-to-bottom
on Bobby's vehicle.
Also check Laura Palmer's
autopsy and see what that brings.
We'll talk to Mr and Mrs Palmer, but let's
give them time to deal with their grief.
We've got our day mapped out.
Let's meet in three minutes.
I really must urinate.
By the way, the coffee
at the Great Northern, incredible.
Harry, as you know, I delivered Laura.
I've known her all her life.
She was my daughter's best friend.
I couldn't face doing
the post-mortem,
so I called
Joe Fielding in from Fairvale.
He did the work, I assisted.
This is what he found.
Time of death estimated to be between
midnight and 4:00 am.
What killed her is loss of blood.
Numerous shallow wounds.
No single one serious
enough to have caused death.
Bite marks on her shoulders,
also on her tongue,
probably self-inflicted.
Lesions on wrists, ankles, upper arms,
where she was bound.
We're waiting on the tox ological
tests for drug use.
Within the last...
12 hours, she'd had sexual relations
with at least three men.
You've examined
Ronnette Pulaski, as well?
Yes, sir.
There's no question in my mind
the same perpetrator
attacked both of them in that train car.
Doc, when, if ever,
will Ronnette be able to talk to us?
She had a severe head injury.
It's still early to tell.
Add to that the psychological impact
of the fear,
probably witnessing what was
happening to Laura before she...
So beautifuI.
Who would do a thing like that?
Leo.
Leo, honey, I have to go to work now
and Norma should be here any sec.
Leo.
Did you clean my boots?
Yeah, I did the laundry too.
All of it?
Well, yeah.
No, you didn't.
- OK, Leo, when I get home, I'll do it.
- Now, Shelly.
OK.
Blood.
Shelly, Norma's here.
Shelly, did you hear me say
Norma's here?
Yeah, I heard you, Leo.
I'm going to come by the diner today.
Be a good girl
and save me a piece of pie.
Sure, Leo.
James, you were arrested for suspicion
of the murder of Laura Palmer.
You have no previous
criminal record, correct?
Nothing, no, sir.
Did you shoot this video?
It's your cycle, isn't it?
Yes, sir. The three of us went
up there two Sundays ago.
James, you were in love with Laura.
The two of you were
seeing each other secretly.
No one else at school
or any of her friends knew about it.
She was the homecoming queen,
dating the captain of the football team,
how long did you think you
could keep this relationship secret?
It was secret
because that's the way she wanted it.
Why? Was she afraid of Bobby?
- I think so.
- So she was using cocaine?
- Yes.
- Did you ever use cocaine with her?
No. I tried to get her to stop.
And she did. For a while.
Why did she start again?
- Something happened two days ago.
- What? What happened?
I don't know.
I think something scared her because
she wouldn't see me or talk to me.
When did you last see her?
The night she died.
She snuck out of her house about 9:30.
About 12:30, I stopped the bike
at the light at Sparkwood and 21.
And she jumped off and ran away.
I didn't see her again.
Did you have a fight?
Not exactly. But she said
she couldn't see me anymore.
Why?
She didn't say.
Recognise this?
Yes, sir.
James, what happened on February 5th,
and who has the other half of this heart?
James, guess why I'm so happy today.
Because your skin is so soft
and you smell so good?
- No.
- Why?
Because I really believe
that you love me.
Now my heart belongs to you.
I don't know.
Damn it.
Where's that shirt?
No!
Hey, Bopper, since when does Leo
Johnson call me at my parents' house?
- Leo called you?
- Yesterday. He was looking for you.
He wanted to know where
the other half of the money was.
What did you tell him, Snake?
As far as I knew,
he didn't have any yet,
'cause I thought we were
supposed to give it to him today.
Yeah, well, I gave him half already.
When did you see him?
- Hey, I saw him the other night, OK?
- What night?
The night Laura died.
I saw Leo,
because I had this money burning
a $10,000 hole in my pocket.
What about the other half?
- It's in Laura's safe deposit box.
- So you didn't get it back from her?
She was supposed to hand it over
today, then she checked out.
So how are we supposed
to get ten grand for Leo?
Maybe we could
sell light bulbs door-to-door.
That's great. That's just...great.
- This isn't funny, Bobby.
- I'm not laughing.
We're lucky we're in jail. You know
what Leo will do when we get out.
Shut up.
Don't mention one word about Leo
Johnson. You do not know...
Leo Johnson.
Help me.
Mom.
Hi, honey.
Why didn't you wake me?
I had to go to the Sheriff's office.
They called and said they could
wait until tomorrowto see you.
We thought you needed your rest.
You woke us crying in your sleep
last night. Do you remember?
No. Really?
I feel so badly for you. I'm so sorry.
Mom, it's so strange.
I know I should be sad
and I am, part of me is.
But it's like...
it's like I'm having
the most beautifuI dream
and the most terrible nightmare
all at once.
Your father said you saw
a boy named James Hurley last night.
- Is this to do with him?
- Can this be between you and me?
Of course.
James and Laura were seeing each
other the last two months.
I was the only one who knew about it.
James was so good for her.
You don't know howtroubled Laura
was. Last night I had to see him.
We were the two closest people
in the world to her.
- But I feel so bad now.
- Why, angel?
Because we realised...
that all this time...
we were the ones falling in love.
So I feel like
I've betrayed my best friend.
And if it's true...
then why am I so happy?
Oh, honey.
What do you want to do? Should we
see these guys separately or together?
- No, we can see them together.
- OK.
Hey, Ed, how's that coconut?
It's kind of tender,
but my pride hurts worse.
- This is Special Agent Dale Cooper.
- Pleasure.
- Any relation to James?
- I'm his uncle. He works in my garage.
His mother's away.
I'm looking after him.
- You plan on holding him?
- No.
- We can release him into your custody.
- Is James being charged?
I had one small doubt which
he cleared up. He didn't kill anybody.
But tell him to be careful,
we're releasing Mike and Bobby also.
- Will do.
- Agent Cooper.
I've got a call for you from a Mr Albert
Rosenfield. Sounds long distance.
- Excuse me.
- Sure.
It has that open air sound, you know,
like wind blowing through trees.
Yes.
About last night at the Roadhouse,
something's not right.
Seeing the bandage I thought maybe
Nadine caught wind of you and Norma.
If Nadine found out, I'd be playing
harp for the Heavenly All-Stars.
- True.
- I was with Norma.
But I was also on my stake-out.
I remember Mike and Bobby
grabbing Donna.
I got up to walk over,
and I got light-headed.
I was out on my feet before I got there.
I don't remember getting hit.
- What do you mean?
- I think my beer was drugged.
Jacques Renault was tending bar.
All right, Albert. You can
have the body all day tomorrow.
No, I can't do it. They're going
to put her in the ground on Monday.
If you come up through Lewis Fork,
I can recommend a place for lunch:
The Lamplighter Inn.
They got a cherry pie there
that'll kill you.
- Hi, Nadine.
- What are you doing here, Norma?
I might ask you the same.
And I'll tell you. I've gotten
all new drapes for my house.
Ed bought 'em for me
yesterday at Gentleman Jim's,
and we installed them together.
They're a beige sheer.
I was up all last night.
Do you know what I was doing?
No, I don't.
I was inventing a noiseless,
completely silent drape runner.
Do you know what makes it work?
The thing I thought
of at four this morning
when I was waiting for my husband
to be released from intensive care?
Cotton balls.
By God, those things
will be quiet now.
Did you have to post bail?
No. I had a talk with Harry.
There's no charge.
Mom still out of town?
Yeah, she's still out of town.
Let's get out of here.
I'll need help from the Bookhouse Boys.
Somebody's got to watch my back.
Already got it covered.
Hi, Mike, Bobby.
Before we start,
have you two got your story straight?
If we tell the truth, we don't
have to get our stories straight.
Besides, the Sheriff told us we're just in
here for fighting and it was self-defence.
Right. Well, I guess you can go then.
Now?
Oh, fellas, one more thing.
Pray for the safety of James Hurley,
because if anything happens to him,
we're coming for you.
Sheriff, what are you sitting around for?
We've got people to see.
- I'd better start studying medicine.
- Why?
Because I'm beginning
to feel a bit like Doctor Watson.
On top of the morning to you, Pete.
No, Josie, the expression
is "top of the morning".
And it's just barely morning.
Pete, I want to thank you for yesterday.
For standing up to me with Catherine.
Forget it. Catherine was wrong yesterday.
Period.
Thank you, anyway.
- Hello.
- Pete, it's Harry.
I've got Agent Cooper with me,
we're here to see Mrs Packard.
I will make a fresh pot of coffee.
- Hi, Sheriff.
- Mrs Packard.
Dale Cooper, FBI. Remember him
from last night's town meeting?
Pleased to meet you, ma'am.
Agent Cooper,
you remember Pete Martell.
You bet.
Can we offer you a cup of joe?
- You said the magic word.
- I'd love a cup.
I'll pour that for you.
Mr Cooper, how do you take it?
Black as midnight on a moonless night.
- Pretty black.
- Please sit down.
Thank you.
Mrs Packard,
I'll come straight to the point.
You hired Laura Palmer
to help you with your English, correct?
- Yes.
- When did you last see her?
Thursday afternoon.
About the time the mill blew five.
- That would be five o'clock?
- Yes.
- When did she leave?
- In an hour, when the lesson finished.
- I didn't see her again.
- How did she seem on Thursday?
Something was bothering her,
but we didn't have a heart-to-heart on it.
Something she said, though,
that stuck on my mind.
She said, "I think now I understand how
you feel about your husband's death."
Did she say
what that was in reference to?
No, but after what happened to her,
I can't help hearing it in my head,
like some haunting melody.
- Excuse me.
- Certainly.
So, Harry,
how long you been seeing her?
How did you know?
Body language.
Jeez Louise!
Not long, six weeks.
Andrew died a year and a half ago.
Don't drink that.
You'd never guess.
There was a fish in the percolator.
Sorry.
Yes, Catherine, I'm listening.
You should know what your sentimental
shenanigans cost us yesterday.
You do know what shenanigans are?
Shutting down the mill
cost us $87,000 and change.
You really think that would've made
brother Andrew happy?
Jocelyn... Mrs Packard.
What is "shenanigans"?
Nonsense, mischief,
often a deceitful or treacherous trick.
- Why do you always have to rush off?
- It's been over an hour.
There was a time when
we used to take the whole afternoon.
In the sweetness of passing time,
this hour will soon seem like a day.
Sing it to somebody else.
I'm no pea-brained chambermaid
looking for a tumble in the broom closet.
Sorry, didn't mean to offend
your delicate sensibilities.
Oh, no, my mistake. I'd gotten used to
our conducting business and pleasure.
Sweetheart, it's all the same to me.
Don't sweetheart me, you old dog.
I'm no schoolgirl, either.
What's the next step?
Do we escalate?
We may not have to do anything.
A few more local tragedies,
and Josie might just run the old mill
into the ground by herself.
At the rate we're going, it's going to be
years before the mill's bankrupt.
I don't want to wait any longer.
Besides, my knothead husband
may peek in the ledger
and sniff out the creative arithmetic.
Maybe it's time to start a little fire.
Are you talking business or pleasure?
I'm talking about the Packard sawmill.
All that dry timber lying around...
A stray spark...
one night...
Some night when Pete's off
on a toot with Smokey the bear.
Now I remember how all those hours...
turned into days.
Sarah, darling,
I'm sorry to disturb you, sweetheart,
but Donna Hayward is here.
Take this now.
I'll send her in.
- Try not to upset her.
- OK.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
I miss her so much.
- Do you miss her?
- Yes, I miss her so much.
I miss her so much.
Laura! Oh, Laura, my baby.
Oh, Laura, my baby.
- Sarah! Sarah!
- Leland! Leland!
It's all right, sweetheart, it's all right.
Calm down.
Calm down, sweetheart, please.
So neither of you saw
Ronnette after school that day?
That's right.
As far as you know,
she went to her job?
Yes, Horne's department store
downtown.
What did she do
at the department store?
She was a...
a salesgirl at the perfume counter.
She used to joke it was the sweetest
smelling job she'd ever had.
Excuse me.
How many times have I asked you not
to disturb the guests with this racket?
About 4,000.
Audrey.
Julie tells me that you were in
with the Norwegians,
just before they all suddenly decided,
en masse,
to return to the old country...
without signing the contracts.
Is that true?
Yes.
You wouldn't have done
or said anything
that might have precipitated their
evacuation, would you?
I mean, I'm assuming
that this was just a coincidence.
Daddy, I did go in there to check out
that ridiculous smorgasbord.
And while I was in there,
I happened to mention that I was sad.
About what?
About my dear, close friend
Laura being brutally murdered.
Do you realise
the kind of money that your little
performance just cost this family?
If you ever pull another stunt like that,
you'll be scrubbing bidets
in a Bulgarian convent.
Oh, Daddy, I'm so afraid.
Laura died two days ago.
I lost you years ago.
For what we are about to receive,
may the Lord make us truly thankful.
I was hoping we'd have the chance
to discuss the recent events.
Not necessarily
the physical events themselves,
but rather the thoughts and feelings
surrounding them.
Rebellion in a young man your age
is a necessary fact of life,
candidly, a sign of strength.
In other words, Robert,
I respect your rebellious nature.
But, as your father, I'm obligated
to contain that fire of contrariness
within the bounds established by society
and within our own family structure.
I note your reluctance
to enter into a dialogue with me.
There are times when silence is golden.
Silence can be taken many ways.
As a sign of intelligence. The quieter
we become, the more we hear.
Now, I am a tolerant man,
but my patience has its limits.
"To have his path made clear is
the aspiration of every human being
"in our beclouded
and tempestuous existence."
Robert, you and I are going
to work to make yours real clear.
We're here for you, Bobby.
Anything to go with that, Sheriff?
Agent Cooper might want to try
a slice of that pie.
- Cherry pie?
- Best in the Tri-Counties.
- Could you ask Norma to stop by?
- Sure thing.
Nothing's a sure thing, Shelly.
I can't get rid of the taste
of that fish-filtered coffee.
Me neither.
Shelly Johnson with a "J"?
Husband's a trucker, Leo.
Minor rap sheet.
- Log lady.
- Right.
Hi.
Can I ask her about her log?
Many have.
- Evening.
- Norma.
I'd like you to meet
Special Agent Dale Cooper.
- FBI.
- Norma Jennings.
Did Laura Palmer help you
with the meals-on-wheels programme,
delivering to the elderly?
Yeah, Laura helped
organise that programme.
Do you have a list of
the people on her route?
- I can get them.
- Would you?
And two more pieces
of this incredible pie.
OK.
Man, oh, man, you must have
the metabolism of a bumblebee.
For your information, I heard you
speaking about Laura Palmer...
Yes?
One day, my log
will have something to say about this.
My log saw something that night.
Really? What did it see?
Ask it.
I thought so.
Thanks, Norma.
See you tomorrow.
Hi, Leo. I brought you some pie.
Where's my shirt?
What shirt?
My favourite blue shirt.
It's the second this year.
I'm going to teach you a lesson
about looking after my property.
- This is going to hurt you.
- Please, Leo. No. No.
I'll get it.
Come on.
Mom, Dad,
this is James, James Hurley.
- How do you do, James?
- Sir.
- Mrs Hayward.
- Nice to meet you, James.
Well, I hope you're hungry.
Eileen's been cooking up a storm.
Yes, sir.
Like a drink?
We have some soft drinks, some
fruit punch and some sparkling cider.
Fruit punch,
that would be good, thank you.
- I'll get it.
- OK.
Why don't you fellas sit down
at the table and I'll check on the roast.
- Your fruit punch.
- Thanks, Donna.
I don't believe I know your parents.
No, sir. My dad died when
I was 10, and my mom travels a lot.
She writes for the paper sometimes.
Ed Hurley down at the gas farm
is James's uncle.
His wife's the lady with the patch.
Yes, sir. That's my aunt Nadine.
She's a real character.
Bill, could you give me a hand, please.
Excuse me.
- We can talk after dinner.
- It's good to see you.
It's good to see you, too.
That bastard.
First your girlfriend, then mine.
Too bad we can only kill him once.
Hey, what's up, Doc? It's Laura Palmer,
in case you haven't guessed.
I'm making you another tape,
which, as you already know, I've
mailed you in one of your envelopes.
It's Thursday the 23rd,
and I am so bored.
Actually, I'm in kind of a weird mood.
God, James is sweet,
but he's so dumb.
I should've met you a long time ago,
Doctor Jacoby,
'cause right now
I can take just so much of sweet.
I just know I'm going to get lost in those
woods again tonight. I just know it.
Remember me telling you
about that mystery man, well...
www.tvsubtitles.net