Previously on "Twin Peaks"...
I shot him, Bobby.
I know I did.
- What happened?
- Somebody shot Waldo.
Leo, no!
This was hidden in the desk.
- Then we can proceed.
- Is it set for tonight?
Yes...
- What policy is this?
- Your new life insurance.
Are you suggesting that there's
something...irregular at work here?
- Rejected, that's what he said.
- Nadine, don't you give up.
Sign here.
Welcome to One-Eyed Jacks, Hester.
Place your bets.
- Jacques, is it?
- That's me.
Say goodbye, James.
What's up, Doc?
I want to see you.
- Where do we look?
- I don't know. Everywhere.
Where shall we start?
Maybe this is something.
Umbrellas?
"The Kahala Hilton, July 1969,
men on the moon..."
"August 9th, 197 4,"
"I first lay eyes on Mimsy."
- Weird!
- Yeah.
- James!
- What d'you do?
- I just hit a button.
- Hit it again.
There's gotta be
a way to turn it off.
My little coconut.
James!
Laura said something
on her tape about a coconut.
Oh, my God, the necklace!
OK, Laura...
this is where you shot that video.
Now just tell me...
Tell me why you sent me
to Sparkwood and 21?
Oh, my God!
No!
- Red, 36.
- Sorry, I guess our date's off.
- 77.
- Pay red.
No, let it ride.
Excuse me, can I get...?
Sir, are you absolutely sure
you want another card?
Yes, please.
Twenty-one! Can you beat that?
Mother always said I was born lucky.
Maybe later.
Thanks for asking.
This is for you.
I'm a friend of Leo's.
Who's Leo?
Buy you a cocktail, Jacques?
Come in.
T urn around.
Yes...
Very nice.
Come over here.
- Something wrong?
- Uh-uh.
This is a good night
for you to break in.
The owner's coming by, he likes
to spend time with the new girls.
- Who's that?
- No names, child.
You don't offer, and you don't ask.
Yes, ma'am.
Pick a card.
- How long you been dealing Blackjack?
- Long enough to spot a card counter.
You let card counters
buy you a drink?
I don't see tips like that everyday.
- Leo ever mention me to you?
- I don't know, Mr. Who are you?
I can't believe
Leo never told you about me.
- Maybe he did, I don't know.
- Leo played you like a violin.
He had you taking all the risk and
never cut you a piece of the action.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Take that chip out of your pocket
and take a look. Go ahead.
That chip has a special significance.
A very special night
you spent up at your cabin.
Here's a clue.
"Laura! Laura!"
Come on, take it easy.
Take it easy!
How do you think a low-rent hump
like Leo has been financing this?
You...
I'm the bank.
- He never mentioned your name.
- Course not.
Leo buys with my cash,
and you mule it across the border.
- He tell you who's distributing Stateside?
- No.
- Some high school kid...
- That's right.
We're in sync now, Jacques,
can you feel it? Can you?
- Yeah, yeah, sure.
- Good.
'Cause I've got a job for you tonight.
No Leo. No middleman.
It's ten grand.
Half now, half on completion.
How's that sound?
Sounds good.
What are we doing?
Meet me at the plant
on Black Lake in two hours.
- Is that going to be a problem?
- No. No problem.
Good.
One more question, Jacques.
Leo told me all about that night
at the cabin with the girls.
I'm curious about the chip.
How'd that happen?
- It was that crazy bird.
- Bird?
It had a thing for Laura,
saying her name all the time,
like he's in love or something.
So we're all partying.
The girls are getting high,
everybody's crazy...
- You, Laura and Ronnette.
- Leo lets Waldo out of the cage...
The birdie lands on her shoulder.
Laura's all tied up.
Oh, she liked that.
The birdy starts pecking
on her shoulder, like love pecks.
Know what I mean? So Leo...
he's doing a number on her, and
she's screaming about that damn bird.
So Leo takes out a chip,
puts it in her mouth and says,
"Bite the bullet, baby."
"Bite the bullet."
Thanks for clearing that up.
Yeah, no problem.
- See you on the other side.
- Can do, Cappy.
Got a trout on the line, Hawk.
This one's a keeper.
- I'm just gonna sit here, OK?
- Come here, sweetie.
Look, we got all night, baby!
Aren't you...?
Yeah. I'm just gonna put this...
Yes...
You made me do this, Shelly.
You made me!
Is Lucy talking to you yet?
As we say in the law enforcement
game, "It's a cold trail."
Ah, women!
Harry? Hawk here. The trout's
heading upstream towards the net.
Hawk, hold the line.
We'll set the hook.
- You got a 20 on Agent Cooper?
- He's downstream ten minutes.
He'll probably miss the catch,
but he'll be there when we grill him.
Copy that. We'll make our move as
soon as the big fish shows his fins.
Ready, Andy?
Ready, Harry.
Keep your hands
where I can see them!
- Put them on the roof of the car!
- You heard him!
Get in there and cuff him.
Don't move!
You're under arrest for the attempted
murder of Ronnette Pulaski
and the murder of Laura Palmer.
Give me your other hand.
- He's got my gun!
- Harry, look out!
Andy...?
- Are you OK, Harry?
- Yeah.
- Better call that ambulance.
...held against you in a court of law,
you have a right to an attorney...
Hello?
All clear.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
Hey, what's up, Doc?
It's Laura,
in case you haven't guessed.
It's Thursday 23rd, and I'm so bored.
Actually, I'm in kind of a weird mood.
God, James is sweet,
but he's so dumb.
And right now I can only take
so much of sweet!
Hey, remember that
mystery man I told you about?
Well, if I tell you his name,
then you're going to be in trouble.
He wouldn't be a mystery man anymore,
but you might be history, man!
I think a couple of times
he's tried to kill me.
But guess what?
As you know, I sure got off on it.
Isn't sex weird?
This guy can really light
my F-l-R-E.
As in red Corvette.
Uh-oh!
Here comes Mom
with milk and cookies.
- Donna?
- Dad!
Bye-bye.
I've got an emergency
at the hospital.
See if your mother needs anything.
I'll call later.
James...
It's OK, I'm glad I heard her say it.
I'm glad.
I might have gone my whole life...
- I'm sorry you had to hear that.
- I'm OK.
Jacoby didn't kill her.
He was trying to help her.
Then how did he get the necklace?
Do you hear that?
You've got one hour to think
about what you've done to me.
And think about it!
'Cause by then
Bobby Briggs is gonna be dead!
You broke my heart!
Goodbye.
It's all here.
Very generous, Josie.
Sitting in that concrete box
all that time,
90 grand seemed like
all the money in creation.
It kept me going.
It's a funny thing.
Back in the world...I don't know...
...it seems kind of light.
We had an agreement.
I've been going over this
in my mind and...
If you could follow my thinking...
We're all born into life,
we have a certain number of years
to breathe and have our being.
That's from a book on Oriental
philosophy I read in the joint.
Maybe somebody, somewhere,
knows how much time we have.
I don't. Do you?
So, when a man gives up a portion
of his life, 18 months for instance,
how does he place a value on that time?
18 months...90,000...
What's that? 5,000 a month?
Not bad if you live another 50 years,
but what if you've only another 20?
Or ten?
Or some unforeseen event
kills you tomorrow?
Like the boating accident
that killed your late husband, Andrew.
Or say you just got out of prison,
where you went in
for vehicular manslaughter,
as part of an agreement to avoid
being implicated in a greater crime,
murder,
for which, in fact,
you were responsible.
But nowthere's this threat,
this possible threat,
that this fact could be discovered.
And in one stroke,
10, 15 or 20 more years of your life
could be cut right out
from underneath you.
So I've been asking myself,
what does that do to the market
value of 18 months?
We had an agreement.
And we still do, sweetheart.
Signed, sealed, delivered.
And I want to take care
of everything we agreed to.
You want a lot for your money,
and I want a lot for my time.
There's a saying in the joint.
It's not Oriental philosophy,
but it has a similar logic that
appeals to my...spiritual nature.
"Once you're in business with
somebody, you're in business for life."
Like a marriage.
Partner.
Damn!
Where is it?
Catherine...?
The account ledger, have you seen it?
Don't you keep it
in that little safe at home?
It's not in the safe at home,
it's not anywhere!
- Tell me you didn't take it.
- I didn't take it.
Pete, tell me the truth.
You're not helping her
to pull something here.
- Who?
- Josie.
No!
- Pull what here?
- Oh, Peter.
Forget everything we've ever done
to hurt each other.
- Just like that!
- Temporarily.
Our marriage is
a living train wreck, but...
there used to be something
caring between us.
The fella who caught my eye.
The lumberjack who could
scamper up a tree like a cat.
The boss's sister
from that big house on the hill.
A summer's indiscretion
and here we are.
Catherine!
Oh, Pete!
I never should have taken you
to that house on the hill.
Well, I have no complaints
about the house.
As for me,
taking my pleasure
in lashing out at the one person
who was decent enough to stand
by me through all my foolishness.
I knowthings haven't been
easy for you.
Peter...
Somewhere under all that scar tissue,
there's the faintest flicker
of what we once felt.
I'm asking you to feel that now.
Why...exactly?
Because I'm in trouble.
Given what I've become
and how I've treated people,
there's no one else I can turn to.
I need your help.
Catherine!
So Fred starts to cuff him,
and Harry turns to go.
Suddenly, Jacques throws
an elbow at Fred...WHAM!
In one move, he takes Fred's gun...
and he's got the drop on Harry.
Harry is deader
than a pound of roadside stew!
Then, all of a sudden,
a single shot rings out.
- Andy, my man!
- All right, Andy!
Go ahead, Andy,
give it your best shot! Go on!
Oh, Andy!
Oh, Punky...
I'm pregnant.
Uh-oh!
Fresh coffee.
- What?
- Let me talk to the sheriff.
The sheriff isn't in at the moment.
Would you care to leave a message?
You tell him Leo Johnson said
to check out James Hurley.
- He's an easy rider.
- An easy rider?
- You got that?
- Yes, but Leo, wait! Leo!
Did you take Laura and Ronnette
up to your cabin that night?
They'd both been up there before.
They was no nuns!
That's where you took the pictures
for "Flesh World"?
That was Laura's idea.
She talked Ronnette
into making them ads.
What did you and Leo
fight about that night?
Bastard hit me with a whiskey bottle!
- Why?
- I don't know, that's why we fought!
I'm bleeding like a stuck pig,
and he's laughing.
So you used Leo's shirt to stop
the bleeding. What then?
I got sick.
I go outside, pass out.
I wake up, I'm laying on the ground.
- Where was Leo?
- Leo and the girls, they're gone.
- What about the train car?
- I don't know nothing about that.
I come down the hill,
Leo's car is gone.
Had to walk 15 miles
back to my own house.
When they brought him in,
he was rambling incoherently.
These things he said to you,
they're pretty incredible.
I know. Let's hope he pulls through.
Well, he's stabilised anyway.
So Leo had to take the girls
to the train car by himself?
- You believe him?
- He's too stupid to lie.
He'll testify against Leo,
we got him.
We got to find Leo first.
- Doc, how's Jacoby?
- He's out of the woods.
Listen...he says he got a phone call
from Laura Palmer.
He was on his way to see her
when he was jumped.
- Any description of the assailant?
- He didn't see him.
But he says he saw Laura Palmer
by the gazebo in Easter Park.
It's not here!
It's not here, either. Damn!
Oh...
...Midge!
Midge Jones.
What are you doing?
It's...my old high school yearbook.
I thought it was gone forever.
Oh, Pete.
Sorry.
What?
It's at the mill.
- What is?
- What you're looking for.
Drying shed three,
near the north gate.
Pete...
Yes, I'll look in the other room.
What do you want? Talk terms.
We'll let you know.
Norma, you still have that
down comforter on your bed?
Yes, Hank.
The mattresses
they give you on your bunk,
they're probably...
this thick, you know.
And you lie there at night...thinking,
"If this mattress is so skinny, how
did they get all those rocks inside?"
So...you'll forgive me
if I tell you that night after night,
I dreamed of you
lying on that big feather bed.
I guess the hired help shouldn't be so
familiar with the boss lady, eh?
I can't blame you for dreaming.
I wasn't just dreaming
about being with you, Norma.
What I was trying to...
- I shouldn't be saying this much.
- I think you should.
No...I haven't earned the right,
Norma.
I've been back what? Two days.
Say what you want to say.
I've been trying to picture a whole
life with you...with the diner.
Making it soar. Making it blue sky.
I always talk too big,
that's my biggest fault.
I learned that talking
to my counsellor inside.
This is new territory for me.
But I'm gonna try.
You know...it's 20 years
we've been together next month.
Can you believe it?
Maybe we're doing this all backwards.
Maybe it's the next 20 that counts.
Give me time, Norma.
I'll make you proud of me yet.
Nadine?
Honey?
Oh, God! Nadine, don't you do this.
Nadine!
I need an ambulance.
My wife has just taken some pills.
422, Riverside.
For the love of God, hurry!
Stay with me, Nadine.
Please, don't go.
Stay with me.
Leo Johnson's gone to ground.
I bet he's holed up near his home.
- Sheriff, Leo Johnson called.
- When?
Ten minutes ago.
He left this message.
And Sheriff, in the background
I could hear a clock striking.
- What kind of clock, Lucy?
- Like the clock at Easter Park.
- Harry!
- Hawk. Good work, Lucy.
Pull surveillance off Leo's house.
Set up a perimeter
around Easter Park.
- Got it.
- You get some cars over there.
Harry, I gotta talk to you...
Harry, let me talk to James.
You want to investigate this?
Come on, James.
Harry...
Harry, is it true?
- You've found the killer?
- We've arrested a suspect.
- But is it him, Harry?
- I can't release any details now.
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
Leland, there's nothing you can do here.
You should be home with Sarah now.
Yes, you're right.
Of course, you're right.
- You're going back to the hospital?
- No, I'm heading home.
- Thank you, Will.
- Don't give it a thought.
Hospital...
I think you ought to listen
to this tape.
Why's that?
It was Laura's. We found it.
I think it'll help you find
who you're looking for.
- Who might that be?
- Somebody with a red Corvette.
Doctor Jacoby's in hospital
with a heart attack.
- Heart attack?
- He said he saw Laura tonight.
What kind of dangerous game
have you been playing?
Is Jacoby gonna be all right?
I've been very patient
with you, James.
From here on out, I'm gonna need
a better set of answers.
Let's start with why this was
in the gas tank of your bike?
Fine, fine, fine. OK.
OK. Ghostwood, fantastic!
I love it!
All your revisions are included.
Ben, I am so happy,
I can't even say how much.
- After you.
- No, no, no!
After you.
After me!
Excuse me.
Benjamin Horne here.
Time to black flag that little firebug.
Leo Johnson's gonna get
a house call.
Proceed.
Shelly?
Shelly, are you here?
- Shelly's not here, Bobby.
- Leo!
- Am I glad to see you...
- Something I can help you with?
It's you I was looking for.
The cops are after you.
Liar!
Shelly's dead! You killed her!
Leo!
Later, Leo.
I can't understand a word,
you have a thing in your mouth.
- Who are you?
- Shelly Johnson.
- You know who called me here?
- No. Please help me.
Be quiet...l'm thinking.
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
- Any of the boys still inside?
- Not sure.
Shift was over, but we're
still trying to get a count.
- Seen Catherine?
- No, Pete.
That's her car.
Jesus God!
You think she's still inside?
I guess I'm gonna have to find out.
Pete, that ain't such a good idea.
She's still my wife.
Catherine!
And that is that!
Ben, is this a great moment?
- Ghostwood!
- Incredible!
Ghostwood, eh?
Einar, tonight
you play on the house.
This is...marvellous.
Enjoy, my friend, enjoy!
To Ghostwood.
To Ghostwood Estates
and Country Club!
Congratulations, Boss.
Blackie, old pal...
this calls for a celebration.
Let's have a look...at the new girl.
Good luck, honey.
Close your eyes.
This is such stuff
as dreams are made of.
Diane, 4:37 am.
After a long investigative night,
returning to the Great Northern.
One suspect in custody. Leo Johnson,
who I believe killed Laura Palmer,
won't be able to escape
the dragnet much longer.
As you can hear
from the ambient sound around me,
and I notice, with some relief,
the Icelandic group on my floor
have either checked or passed out,
I may not need the earplugs
which I received today, Diane,
although I may put them to use
as a precautionary measure.
I ordered hot milk from room service.
Here's hoping that does the job, and
I can catch some quality sack time.
24-hour room service, the premier
achievement of modern civilisation.
"My Special Agent".
Cooper here.
Who is this?
Could this wait
till tomorrow morning?
Please excuse me,
I've got room service.
We found him...
We found Leo Johnson.
He's been shot. Agent Cooper?
www.tvsubtitles.net