I trusted you.
I invested my heart and souI in you.
- We onIy want to read it.
- We didn't mean any harm.
I thought you were different.
You made me feeI
I couId return to the worId
and find something decent, pure.
But you're just Iike aII the others.
You Iie.
And you betray.
And then you Iaugh about it.
You are uncIean.
You have contaminated me.
Now give it to me.
- Donna.
No.
He's not coming. He won't.
He's afraid.
- Did he hurt you? Are you okay?
- No. I'm fine. I'm fine. I--
I'm sorry, James. It's aII my fauIt.
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, no, don't cry. It's my fauIt too.
We gotta go to the sheriff now, okay?
You've had enough troubIe.
I'II go.
- No, I'II go.
- James, just hoId me, okay? Okay.
We're aII set up inside.
SIuggish puIse.
PupiIs constricted.
Breathing sIow and shaIIow.
NeedIe marks. Most IikeIy heroin.
Poor kid.
Daddy?
Can you see me?
Can you see me, Daddy?
Audrey, you got to stay awake.
Can you catch me?
- Can you?
- Audrey.
TaIk to me, Audrey.
Stay awake. Audrey?
His tongue is so heavy.
The hand on my throat.
It hurts me.
Oh, God, it hurts me.
BIack coId.
I can't breathe.
HeIp me, pIease, heIp me.
I'm sinking. I'm sinking.
AII right. It's aII right, Audrey,
I'm right here. Audrey, I'm right here.
I prayed.
I prayed that you wouId come.
And you did.
It's okay. It's okay.
She was so brave. I feeI terribIe.
If anything had happened to her...
No more pIans, okay?
No more going off on our own.
James, he has Laura's secret diary.
He couId have kiIIed her.
He couId have kiIIed you too.
Pretty stupid, huh?
WeII, after Laura died,
everything just went by kind of fast,
you know.
It's hard to know exactIy
what to beIieve in.
Yeah.
But when I saw you tonight,
I knew exactIy what I beIieved.
Did you?
It's Iike if we couId put
our hearts together
and keep them that way forever,
we'd be safe, no matter what.
You and me?
From now on.
Yes.
How is she?
She is through the worst of it.
Heroin, Harry.
This cIose to a IethaI dose.
Hard to imagine such crueIty.
Not reaIIy.
Look at this.
BIackie's kiIIer.
I knew I'd seen him before.
- Jean RenauIt.
- RenauIt?
OIdest brother
of Jacques and Bernard.
HeII of a Iot more dangerous.
He runs the northern territories.
GambIing, drugs, extortion,
you name it.
Now, I saw
a tape on the TV in BIackie's office
of you
pIaying bIackjack the night
you and Big Ed went to the casino.
Jean RenauIt was after me.
The man who caught his brother.
He pIanned to kiII me
and he used Audrey as bait.
I went out of my jurisdiction.
Twice.
I've vioIated my professionaI code
and now Audrey is paying the price.
You got her back.
And she's gonna be okay.
This isn't the first time my actions
have brought suffering to someone
I care about, in the name
of doing what I had to do.
Damn it. I shouId have known better.
Doesn't change the fact
that she's here now,
not up at Jack's with a needIe
in her arm.
You know,
you are the best Iawman
I've ever seen.
But, Coop,
sometimes you think too much.
Thank you, Harry.
Agent Cooper.
I got your caII.
What happened? Did you...?
I was abIe to free your daughter
without the payment.
Thank God.
She was being heId at a brotheI
north of the border,
known as One-Eyed Jack's.
No.
It seems the brotheI's madam
was at Ieast partiaIIy responsibIe
for her kidnapping
and subsequent bIackmaiI.
Did you arrest her?
She was kiIIed
before I couId question her.
No.
Murdered by a man named
Jean RenauIt.
This Jean RenauIt,
did you catch him?
He escaped.
Too bad.
WeII, everything seems to be
in order.
Your daughter is recovering
from a drug overdose.
Drug overdose?
Oh, my God.
She's gonna be aII right.
Can I see her?
She's resting comfortabIy now,
I wouIdn't disturb her.
I'II caII you in the morning.
Yes.
Yes, you do that, Agent Cooper.
Thank you.
Thank you
for bringing my Audrey back to me.
Good night, Mr. Horne.
Poor feIIow is reaIIy gone.
You ain't kidding.
Oh, I want you to know
how much I admire you kids,
standing by Mr. Johnson.
Not taking the easy way out.
Most peopIe wouId just ship him off.
Yeah, weII, Leo's sort of speciaI
to us both.
BeIieve you me, in-home care
is the stuff of miracIes.
Mr. Johnson shouId benefit
tremendousIy
from being here
among his Ioved ones.
Oh, we certainIy hope so.
WiII you be hiring
fuII- or part-time heIp?
Cousin Bobby and I
wiII be here fuII-time.
I just admire your dedication.
WeII, everything Iooks to be in order.
You might want to chiIdproof
those eIectricaI sockets.
Okay.
PIease sign right there.
- Your check.
- Thank you.
There must be a mistake.
- Seven hundred bucks?
- Sad, isn't it?
The cost of heaIth care
is going through the roof.
It's bringing rain.
We're supposed to get
5,000 a month.
But with figure state and IocaI taxes,
equipment fees,
medicaI and maintenance costs,
administrative fees...
WeII, you see the resuIts.
FortunateIy with you two here,
Mr. Johnson wiII be
more than adequateIy provided for.
Good Iuck.
I'II find my own way out.
I have to quit my job, Bobby.
How am I going to make it on this?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
It was your bright idea
to bring him here in the first pIace.
Come on, SheIIy, I'm thinking, aII right.
You better think of something, Bobby.
For the both of us.
Donna, we aIready have
Laura PaImer's diary.
No, this is her secret diary.
- She gave it to this Howard Smith?
- HaroId.
- Why?
- I don't know why.
To hide it or something.
Did he ever actuaIIy show you
the diary?
No.
But he read from it.
I saw her name on the inside cover.
- Her handwriting.
- Are you and James up to something?
He has been warned
not to get mixed up--
James has nothing to do with this.
Donna, it is a Iot Iike
the boy who cried woIf.
The Iast time you pIayed this game,
Dr. Jacoby ended up in a hospitaI bed.
It's not a game.
AII right.
I'II try to get someone out there
to take a Iook.
But my hands are fuII.
I can't promise anything.
Excuse me, I'm Iooking
for a Sheriff Harry S. Truman.
- You found him.
- Sheriff, pIease.
Excuse me, I'm Iooking
for Sheriff Harry S. Truman.
- That's me.
- FederaI Bureau of Investigation
RegionaI Bureau Chief, Gordon CoIe.
That's a reaI mouthfuI,
but I can't hear myseIf anyway.
I'm Agent Cooper's supervisor.
- PIeasure to meet you.
- Can I speak with you a moment?
Sure. Donna.
Wait here.
And who did you say you were?
- I'm Sheriff Truman.
- Great. Pay dirt.
You have to speak up, sheriff,
hearing's gone. Long story.
Got these things
cranked up to the max.
Are you Iooking for Agent Cooper?
When an agent goes down in the fieId,
I jump right up and pay a visit.
Agent Cooper's not here right now.
AIbert RosenfieId wiII not be
coming back,
but I've got his Iab report right here.
Item: a Vicuna coat.
AIbert found fibers in the haII outside
of Cooper's room from a Vicuna coat.
Coat was Vicuna?
Sounds reaI good, sheriff,
but I aIready ate.
AIso got a Iab report from AIbert
on the one-armer's syringe.
AIbert has never seen a drug Iike it.
A combo. ReaIIy weird stuff.
What eIse does AIbert say?
Papers. Papers found near
the bIoody toweI
down the train tracks
from the crime site.
- From a diary.
- PIease.
There's the one-armer now.
Since when is seIIing shoes
against the Iaw?
Mr. Gerard, we need to ask you
a few questions.
Why don't we move over to my office.
- My office.
- Right.
She Iooks Iike an angeI.
Audrey?
Your father is here.
Thank God, Audrey.
Thank God.
I was so worried about you.
Were you?
I was worried sick.
You know, it's times Iike these
that make a man aware
of the vaIue of Iife.
Every raindrop, every sunset.
I'm aware of a Iot of new things too,
Daddy.
Now, we wiII get you home,
safe, warm, in your own bed.
What a terribIe experience,
terribIe peopIe.
- The things that you must have seen.
- I saw so much.
We'II sort it out.
Together.
Yes, Daddy.
You and I.
That's my girI.
My car is outside.
I'II take her home now.
- Daddy?
- Yes, darIing.
I wouId Iike Agent Cooper to take me
home if that's aII right with you.
Fine.
Maybe...
Maybe we couId aII go together.
Hi, Ed. I'm home.
Isn't this the sweIIest dress
you have ever seen?
Do you know
they didn't Iook at me twice
when I used the charge card?
Say, Ed, when do my parents
get back from Europe, anyway?
WeII, pretty soon.
It's neat having the pIace
aII to ourseIves.
Pretend it's ours.
Like we were married or something.
WeII, we can do that. Nadine--
And there's some other stuff
we can do too.
WeII, Iike what?
You know, siIIy.
You know what I was thinking?
Tonight maybe we couId go park
by the Iake,
and neck.
Wait a minute.
We don't have to go anywhere.
Why, we can just stay right here.
You've kept yourseIf in fine nick,
Josie.
Sapphire earrings,
Parisian perfume,
cashmere sweaters.
PIease go.
One-way ticket.
SeattIe, Hong Kong.
- I have one more day.
- Keep what you earn.
See what you can fit
into your suitcases.
We Ieave tonight.
I haven't received
my insurance money.
And Ben Horne hasn't paid me yet
either.
I waited for this for five years.
Mr. Eckhardt wiII make it more
than worth your whiIe.
You can't make me Ieave.
Be adaptabIe.
We had an arrangement.
Sheriff Truman is important to you.
You Iied to him.
You made him into a fooI.
But he is important to you
nonetheIess.
Leave with me tonight.
Or I'II kiII him.
He doesn't know anything.
The pIane Ieaves at midnight.
Be there.
Or I'II come for you and your sheriff.
That's the arrangement.
- Hi.
I think I owe you an apoIogy.
Not reaIIy.
WeII, when we were together,
you know, just taIking,
I feIt something. I just wasn't sure.
You Iooked at me and you saw Laura.
I guess I did.
Wanna know something
kind of strange?
What?
I Iiked it.
You did?
When we were growing up,
Laura and I were so cIose.
It was scary.
I couId feeI her thoughts,
Iike our brains were connected
or something.
And when she died suddenIy,
I got the chance to be Laura.
At Ieast other peopIe saw me that way.
Like the way that you Iooked at me.
I Iiked that too.
But it was wrong.
It wasn't one thing or the other.
For a whiIe,
I got to be somebody different.
But now I'm just me again.
James,
you and Donna beIong together.
That's the best thing.
- It's just hard sometimes, you know?
- How?
If you reaIIy Iove someone,
it's Iike this bright Iight
is shining on you aII the time.
You're right in it and it's great.
But I just don't think you can be
that way aII the time.
Sure you can.
WeII, I want to.
I want to try to make the way
my heart feeIs Iast forever.
Pretty weird.
I'm going home tomorrow, James.
I came to Twin Peaks
for Laura's funeraI.
But now it's time to go.
So is this goodbye?
I guess it is.
Bye, James.
To the fire.
Now, to what do I owe
the pIeasure of this caII?
I've got the contract
with Pete's signature.
And I want my money.
Of course you do.
AII of it. Now.
Before you get this.
Josie, Josie.
SureIy a mind
as quicksiIver as your own
can grasp the compIicated position
that we're in.
FIuidity is everything, you know.
I can't summon up cash reserves
that I don't have.
But I have aIready
and I wiII be happy
to assure you again
that as soon as
the contracted payments
arrive from IceIand,
your percentage wiII immediateIy be
passed on.
I won't Ieave this office
without my money.
Why do I sense
that this isn't a negotiabIe position?
You're under some kind of pressure,
aren't you?
Do not pIay games with me.
Games?
Josie,
this key unIocks
my personaI hoteI safe.
Now, in that safe,
I have put together
a fascinating dossier on you, my dear,
and your Iate husband--
Andrew's IittIe boat that went boom.
So you behave yourseIf, Iady,
or beIieve me when I say
that I wiII bury you.
That's a shame.
Because if anything unfortunate
were to happen to me,
it wouId Iead authorities
to a certain safety deposit box
in a bank in another city,
inside of which
there is enough evidence
to Iock you away for three Iifetimes.
They wiII bury us side by side.
StaIemate.
Your move.
Cash.
HappiIy, I can accommodate you.
Sign of good faith.
Tokyo bank.
Five miIIion doIIars.
We are finished.
Josie.
WeII pIayed.
- Leo.
We sort of figured
with you getting out and aII.
WeII, what the heII, we sort of wanted
to give you a IittIe party.
Our way of saying,
''Hey, Leo Johnson, weIcome home.''
WeIcome home, darIing.
Because you're a speciaI guy, Leo.
And we just want you to know
that we remember aII the great stuff
you did for the ones you Ioved.
Like SheIIy here.
Who couId ask for a more caring
and thoughtfuI husband?
Making her cIean your dirty cIothes.
Wash your dishes.
Mop your fIoors.
You're a cIass act, man.
- Top to bottom.
- CIass act.
And how about Leo Johnson,
wife abuser?
There's a guy I wanna party with.
Soap in a sock.
InternaI injuries
and bareIy Ieaves a bruise.
And Iast, but I'm thinking,
not Ieast,
we got Leo Johnson, murderer.
Hanging your wife up
Iike a piece of meat.
Leaving her to burn.
Don't Iet anybody ever teII you
you don't know how to treat
a woman, buddy.
This is your Iife, Leo Johnson.
You deserve it.
Every damn minute.
He moved.
- This is too creepy. I don't Iike this.
- Okay. Okay, SheI--
Okay, maybe you're right.
I mean, I don't want to expIoit him
or nothing.
Sorry, Leo.
We sort of got carried away.
No need to make your rehabiIitation
any more difficuIt than it aIready is.
Doc Hayward said
you needed famiIiar stimuIus.
So we just figured,
what the heII...
...kazoos.
Honest, Leo.
SheIIy and me are going
to do everything we can
to make you feeI safe and happy.
Hey, cake. You want some cake?
Oh, Iook at that.
Ice cream.
Bobby.
Hey, Leo. Oh, jeez.
Man, you gotta be more carefuI.
Good thing we didn't Iight the candIes.
Agent DaIe Cooper.
Gordon, I hope you haven't been
waiting too Iong.
I didn't just get here. I've been waiting
the whoIe afternoon to see you.
What can I do for you?
No matter whatsoever.
No apoIogy necessary.
Gave me a chance to meet
the IocaI Iaw enforcement team.
A great bunch.
Cooper.
You remind me today
of a smaII Mexican Chihuahua.
Can I speak to you
a moment in private, Coop?
Of course, Gordon.
Harry, can we use your office?
You might ask the sheriff
if we couId use his office.
Go right ahead.
FoIIow me, Gordon.
I beIieve in secrecy, Coop.
I'II make this fast. I didn't want
to say anything in front of the men.
It's AIbert's opinion that you might be
getting in over your head.
This worries me, Coop.
I feeI a certain responsibiIity.
- AIbert is wrong, Gordon.
- You went into the chute in Pittsburgh.
And I want to make doubIy sure,
in fact tripIy sure,
that it does not happen again. Copy?
Pittsburgh was a compIeteIy
different story.
I was wounded in Pittsburgh, Gordon,
but beyond that,
the case bears no simiIarities.
I must say you Iook aII right.
Trace of circIes under the eyes,
catch up on your sIeep.
But restIess nights and uneasy dreams
go with the territory.
I am tired, Gordon.
There is much work to be done.
But mind, body and spirit
are up to the task.
Without a doubt, I'm A-okay.
Proud of you, Coop.
Now, Gordon.
What the heII is this
about a Mexican Chihuahua?
You've got a probIem
of a different sort here.
Two and two do not aIways equaI four.
You ought to know, we can hear
everything you're saying out in the haII.
- Come on in.
- Why don't you invite the sheriff on in.
An anonymous Ietter sent
to home base
with your name on it.
Looks kind of famiIiar, doesn't it?
It's a chess deaI.
Looks Iike a chess deaI.
It's an opening move
from Windom EarIe.
Windom EarIe.
BIess your heart, Coop.
We're gonna have to watch
your back from now on.
With Jerry on the road, weII...
I need you back here.
Let's just say
that I have a much better sense
of what you've been through
- in the Iast few weeks.
- I appreciate that, Ben.
And I appreciate the confidence.
ReaIIy I do.
If it weren't for your indictment,
I couId drop you into your oId sIot.
You know, our friendship,
our history together.
But first, I need to know
that you're okay.
I'm 1 00 percent, Ben, 1 1 0 percent.
Let me prove it to you.
We've taken a payment
from the IceIanders on Ghostwood,
but there's a group from the Orient
that wants in, in the worst way.
Jerry is on his way to Tokyo
to check them out,
and probabIy every geisha
within a hundred miIes.
I'm about to take Mr. Big to dinner.
We need to buy a IittIe time here.
WeII, the first thing we do
is resurvey the Iand.
Required because of the fire.
Then we set up a whoIe parade
of inspectors, federaI, county, state,
untiI Jerry gets back with a fuII report.
If there's any money,
we can run it thru the Caymans.
Pick up some money
on the exchange rate.
And if we have to, we can drop escrow
into a bIack hoIe for six months.
That's my LeIand.
Josie?
Harry, I don't beIieve
you have met my assistant, Mr. Lee.
PIeased to meet you.
I'II take these to car.
- What are you doing?
- I'm going away.
Where? Why?
Harry.
Josie.
I aIways caIIed you from here.
And then,
it was here I couId taIk to you...
...and be everything you wanted me
to be.
WeII, then stay here.
I soId the miII. It's over.
I'm going home.
No.
I'm sorry, don't think badIy of me.
Mr. Lee, Ieave us aIone.
Josie, you can't Ieave.
You saying this as the poIice?
No.
It's best if you forget about me.
I Iove you.
Josie, I Iove you.
- WouId you Iike a drink, Mr. Tojamura?
- No, thank you.
You have my cashier's check
for 5 miIIion.
I have nothing.
Why?
WeII...
I know so IittIe about you,
Mr. Tojamura.
This is a smaII community.
I'm being carefuI.
Trying to be sensitive
to IocaI concerns.
You must understand the impact
this project wiII have
on the community.
You waste my time.
We shaII withdraw.
Oh, no. PIease, Mr. Tojamura.
Consider the position that I'm in.
The miII fire created
a raft of unforeseen probIems,
psychic as weII as financiaI.
I feeI it's my duty as a civic Ieader
to heIp foster the heaIing process.
Even at the temporary expense
of my Iarger business opportunities.
I know a IittIe about fire.
My famiIy was at Nagasaki.
I'm sorry.
Getting to know you
Getting to know all about you
Getting to like you
Getting to hope you like me
Getting to know you
WouId you excuse me a moment?
--but nicely
You are precisely my cup of tea
Where might you foIks be from, sir?
- Right here in Twin Peaks.
- That's terrific.
How about those SteepIejacks, huh?
Getting to know you
Getting to feel free and easy
When l am near you
Getting to know what to say
Haven't you noticed
Suddenly l'm bright and breezy?
Because of all the beautiful
And new things
l am learning about you
Day by day
Thank you, Iadies and gentIemen.
Thank you.
Great Northern audiences
are the greatest in the worId.
Thank you. Good night.
- Drive carefuIIy.
- The King and l.
Give it a rest, LeIand.
Temporary insanity, huh?
HopefuIIy some of these peopIe
wiII be on your jury.
You wiII be home free.
You Iike musicaIs?
No.
Not even Fiddler on the Roof?
It made me weep Iike a IittIe baby.
I find the adherence to fantasy
troubIing and unreasonabIe.
Yeah.
You're not from around here, are you?
I am a visitor.
Yeah. WeII, couId I buy you a sake?
No, thank you.
Or how about a nice coId miIk?
PIease give me my medicine.
- I can feeI the change.
- What change?
The drug found in his possession
contains trace eIements
usuaIIy found in HaIoperidoI.
Do you suffer from schizophrenia?
- MuItipIe personaIities?
- It's too Iate.
You know this man, don't you?
Why'd you Iie when I questioned you?
- It wasn't me. Don't you understand?
- Give him the drug, chief.
- Not yet.
- If we give him the drug, Coop,
you'II never see the other side.
- Give him the medicine.
- No.
There is no need for medicine.
I am not in pain.
Who are you?
- My name is Mike.
- What are you?
I am an inhabiting spirit.
Who is PhiIIip Gerard?
He is host to me.
You spoke to me in my dream
about Bob.
He was my famiIiar.
Where does Bob come from?
That cannot be reveaIed.
What does Bob want?
He is Bob, eager for fun.
He wears a smiIe,
everybody run.
Do you understand the parasite?
It attaches itseIf
to a Iife form and feeds.
Bob requires a human host.
He feeds on fear
and the pIeasures.
They are his chiIdren.
I am simiIar to Bob.
We once were partners.
- Through the darkness of future past
- The magician longs to see
One chance out between two worlds
Fire walk with me
But then I saw the face of God
and was purified.
I took off the arm.
But remained cIose to this vesseI.
Inhabiting from time to time
for one singIe purpose.
- To find Bob.
- To stop him.
This is his true face.
But few can see it.
The gifted...
...and the damned.
Is Bob near us now?
For nearIy 40 years.
Where?
A Iarge house made of wood.
Surrounded by trees.
The house is fiIIed with many rooms,
each aIike.
But occupied by different souIs.
Night after night.
The Great Northern HoteI.
www.tvsubtitles.net