Mr. Horne?
Your secretary said to come in.
Bobby Briggs.
Bobby, you know
what you have to have in this life?
Balance.
Distance.
Symmetry.
Look.
lt's a beautiful thing, isn't it?
Mr. Horne, did you listen
to that tape that l sent you?
Yes, l listened to your tape, Bobby.
Frankly, l am surprised
that Leo could master the technology.
Damn it, Bobby, what do you want?
Mr. Horne,
l have a great admiration for you.
Admiration is for poets
and dairy cows, Bobby.
l don't know what you mean. l...
Bobby.
You're standing in front
of a mammoth skyscraper.
A leviathan that rips a hole
in the clouds.
Now, what's the first question
that comes to your mind?
The first question that you ask yourself
is, ''What's on the top floor?''
''Who's up there in the penthouse,
and why?''
Now, that's who l am.
Are you?
Yeah, of course l am. Yes.
Bobby, opportunity knocks.
l want you to follow Hank Jennings.
l want you to chronicle
his existence.
Show me something
that l don't already know.
l'd like to see both.
Very good. Which one
would you like to see first?
Well...
What is this?
l'd thought l'd taken that out.
That property
is called Dead Dog Farm.
And it's worse than it sounds.
- What is it?
- A puzzle.
No one ever really stays there long.
When can l see it?
Sorry l'm late.
But the little nipper is so excited
about our camping trip,
l just couldn't coax him
out of the car.
Richard, this is Judy Swain
from the Happy Helping Hands
organization.
l'm little Nicky's case manager.
Charmed, l'm sure. Shall we?
Sit down.
Okay.
As l was about to tell your friends,
the number one thing
to know about Nicky
is that throughout his brief life,
he has been very confused,
and perhaps traumatized
by a persistent random misfortune.
Looks like he's bounced around
quite a bit.
Well, yes, he has.
- Poor child.
- Yes.
An orphan, you know.
Really? What happened?
Did his parents die?
Nicely deduced, Andrew.
Persistent random misfortune?
They were killed.
How were they killed, Miss Swain?
Mysterious circumstances.
l'm afraid the orphanage has never
provided us with that information.
Andy, let's go.
Emergency up at the Great Northern.
Looks like a heart attack.
Once stimulated,
the female will respond in such a way
that the skin around her...
Oh, my God.
Looks like Dougie went out
with his boots on.
Love Poems of Lord Byron,
The Kama Sutra,
Hookers and Handmaidens.
Sheriff, look at this.
What a falling out was here.
Doug.
Lord, l hate to say it, l told you so.
Here, sheriff.
This is it.
The murder weapon.
She might as well
have blown his brains out with a rifle.
He never could say no to a woman.
You old fool.
You sexual adventuress,
you'll burn in hell for this.
- Take it easy, mister.
- l'm gonna shout till l wake the dead.
She murdered my brother.
She's a witch.
He's right, l'm cursed.
Don't be silly.
No, no, it's true.
lt all started in high school,
prom night.
My date went to kiss me.
lt was his first day
with his new braces.
Oh, and they gleamed
in the moonlight.
And his rubber band snapped
and his jaw locked open,
and we ended up
in the emergency room,
and the doctors had to break his jaw
in three places to get it to shut.
And it's just gotten worse ever since.
A curse needs a cure.
l know a bit about these things.
Are you the sheriff?
Let's just say, when something
really big goes down, l'm the man.
Boys, there's a story
about a great football coach,
whose name escapes me
at this time,
who was dead set against
having any black players on his team.
Until somebody brought him the finest
black halfback anyone had ever seen.
And when what's-his-name
saw him run 50 yards
and no one lay a hand on him,
he shouted, ''Look at that lndian go!''
That coach accepted
that athlete's desire to compete.
Nadine.
And today, this story applies
to this woman's--
This young girl's right to compete.
ln addition to it being her moral
and constitutional right.
Mike Nelson,
could you step up here for a second?
Yeah.
Come on, Mike, go.
Now, Nadine has chosen
to prove herself to us
by taking on our very best.
Our very own district champion,
Mike Nelson.
- Yeah! Come on. Come on.
- All right, man.
Go, Mike.
Hi, Mike.
Put your hand here.
No, here.
All right, now just push against me.
l'll try not to hurt you.
Wanna go out tonight?
This is called a tie.
- Oh, yeah.
- You stupid...
What did you say, Mike?
Neck, you're breaking my neck.
You're right,
this is sort of like necking.
What about tonight?
Coach?
Hey, coach?
- Get up, Mike.
- Oh, my God.
One, two and three.
Now will you go out with me?
What happened to you?
l got beat up by a girl.
What did you do to her?
Donna, l'm not kidding.
Now, you've gotta help me.
lt's bad enough getting stomped on
in front of the whole team,
but she likes me.
- Who?
- Mrs. Hurley.
Nadine?
lt's not funny.
l don't know, maybe an older woman
is just what you need.
l don't wanna go out with anyone
who can body-slam me.
Well, what do you want me
to do about it?
l don't know, talk to her or something.
Pretend you're still my girlfriend.
Sorry, Mike,
l'm not that good of an actress.
Donna, this is serious.
l'm gonna end up in traction.
May l help you?
Hang up a local service rebellion,
wonder if you'd help me bundle up
loose sticks and burn that master.
Malcolm, Malcolm Sloan,
as in brother to Evelyn.
Mr. Marsh's driver, as in,
''Bring that car around, James.''
So how badly
did she damage the Jag?
lt's repairable.
That's the nice thing about things.
You know, when she and Jeffrey
fell in love,
he gave her a whole new life.
That's for sure.
Now l got a nice uniform,
and the keys to the liquor cabinet.
God, l hope
l don't sound ungrateful,
because compared
to the life l was living,
wanton dissipation is a step up.
And Evelyn,
she learned a lot herself.
Defensive postures,
masking bruises, vicious cycles.
What are you talking about?
l'm sorry, am l being obscure?
Once a fortnight,
Jeffrey pounds her mercilessly,
and she tries to get even
by breaking one of his things.
lt only perpetuates the cycle.
She's your sister.
Why don't you stop him?
Sonny boy,
nobody stops Mr. Marsh.
That's a golden rule around here.
You can jot that down
and put it under your pillow.
l gotta get back.
Hey, thanks.
l mean that.
Well, it's still standing.
Almost by force of habit.
Well, habit can provide
a strong foundation.
Dead Dog Farm, huh?
That's an old legend.
Of all the people in the world,
the best and the worst
are drawn to Dead Dog,
and most turn away.
Only those with the purest of heart
can feel its pain.
And somewhere in between,
the rest of us struggle.
lrene, have you shown this property
to anyone else recently?
l don't think anyone's asked
to see it this last year.
There's three vehicles.
A jeep, a four-wheeler
and a luxury sedan.
lt's open.
Hello?
There's been a meeting here.
ln the past few hours.
What are you seeing?
They forgot
there was no running water.
Baby laxative.
More white powder.
Cocaine.
lrene, we have to notify the sheriff.
Nicky, stop that, please.
Nicky, stop it.
l don't understand this at all.
l just had the car checked
at Gas Farm.
He told me it was
in perfect working order.
Perfect working order.
This is all so technical.
Please, Nicky,
Uncle Dick is trying to read.
Nicholas, get out of the car!
Nicholas, out of the car, right now!
Out of the car!
Do you hear me?
Are you mad at me, Uncle Dick?
Well, of course l'm not mad at you.
Why should l be mad at you?
Scared you, didn't l?
Uncle Dick!
Don't worry, don't worry,
l'm all right, little Nicky.
What if you died?
You aren't gonna die, are you?
Of course not. Don't be silly.
Harry?
Cooper. This is Colonel Riley.
He's heading up
the Air Force's investigation
into Briggs' disappearance.
- Colonel.
- Cooper.
You were with Briggs
when we lost our coordinates on him.
Yes, l was.
When you were at the site,
did you notice any wildlife in the area?
- Wildlife?
- Birds, owls?
Yes.
Yes, just moments before the major
disappeared, l heard an owl.
Any visual contact?
Look, colonel, Garland Briggs
is a good friend of mine.
lt would be a lot better
if you'd just level with us.
We know about the monitors
and the messages from deep space
that you received pertaining to me.
You may know something,
but you best get your facts straight.
Our monitors are pointed
at deep space,
but the messages we intercepted
that Briggs showed you
were sent from right here
in these woods.
Now, where they were sent to
is another question.
Might this have something to do
with a place called the White Lodge?
That's classified.
Colonel, we'd like to help you,
but you need to give us
a little more to go on here.
Garland Briggs is the best pilot
l've ever known.
He was born with hardware
most of us only dream about.
l can tell you this:
His disappearance has implications
that go so far beyond national security
the Cold War seems like a case
of the sniffles.
The engine's fine,
the axle should be okay.
How did you get so good at this?
Oh, my uncle Ed.
You think l'm good,
you should see him.
He can fix anything.
l was talking to your brother today
a little bit about your situation.
Look, James,
mind your own business.
Are you afraid?
Are you afraid of your husband?
Are you?
There's nothing to talk about.
l know what it's like to be alone.
You are afraid of him, aren't you?
Why don't you just leave?
lt's complicated.
Oh, my God, it's him.
l've gotta go.
lt's not as bad as l made it out to be.
Oh, look who's here.
Did Daddy have a change of heart?
Daddy just made the smartest decision
that he's made all year.
Oh, yeah? That's not saying much.
What did he do?
He put me on the payroll.
Bobby, you junior achiever, you.
And this right here?
This is my first assignment.
Anything l can help you with?
Maybe.
Maybe you can help me celebrate
after l show this to the boss.
Well, you know what l think,
Bobby Briggs?
Tell.
l think that we should think
about doing business together.
Audrey, l like the way you think.
Thank you.
Hey, Mr. Horne, how's it going?
What is this
you're doing here, exactly?
Gettysburg, day one.
The South is winning.
l followed Hank,
got those pictures you wanted.
You see, l don't know what he's up to,
but l'm sure it's no good.
l mean, l've never seen
these guys before,
but they're not exactly from the Rotary,
if you know what l mean.
- l like you, Bobby.
- Oh, l like you too.
How much am l paying you?
We haven't actually
discussed money.
Well, you can consider this
your first raise.
Now, you come back tomorrow,
and we will discuss a full-time position.
Thank you, Ben.
l won't let you down.
Nectar of the gods, my dear.
lt's the bubbles.
Wine comes in at the mouth.
Love comes in at the eye.
I touch my gIass to my Iips,
I Iook at you and sigh.
Thank you, Pete.
That's very lyrical.
lt's Yeats.
He's a poet.
Yes, l know.
The only other toast l know
is a limerick.
No, really. Really, Pete, that was--
- There once was a Iady from GaIway--
- Josie!
- Yes.
- We'll have our appetizers now.
- Oh, Josie.
l just want you to know
that even though your station
in this household has changed,
l intend to show you all the respect
and affection that you deserve.
Thank you, Catherine.
And l will try to do the same.
Oh, and put on your little maid's cap.
Catherine, don't you think maybe
you're being a little hard on her?
l mean, she is still part of the family.
Josie had a hand in Andrew's death,
and she did everything in her power
to destroy me.
She is lucky she's not hanging
from a tree.
l don't believe it.
Not the Josie l know.
l would like to propose a toast
to Ben Horne's double-cross.
Here's to Josie Packard's
dirty deeds.
And here's to the woman
who brought them down.
Here's to me.
Here's to you, poodle.
Diane, l'm holding in my hand
a nationally distributed newspaper.
My opening move, responding
to Windom Earle's opening move,
was printed in the personal columns
per my instructions.
But l've already received
his response to this yesterday.
He anticipated my response
to his opening move perfectly.
He's toying with me, Diane.
l wonder where he is
and what he's planning.
Meanwhile,
l've spent the past two days
without badge and gun
the best way l know how:
Occupying both body and spirit.
Looked into some real estate,
what the local agent
charitably refers to as a fixer-upper.
Nonetheless, it's a place
where a man might make a home,
raise a family, which is something,
in spite of my past,
l still hope l'm able to do.
However, as is the case here
in Twin Peaks,
even this bucolic hideaway
is filled with secrets.
Secrets that may be connected
to my trouble at the Bureau
and the cocaine that was found
in my automobile.
Agent Hardy's deliberations
will soon be completed.
And if l'm not adequately able
to defend myself,
there's a very real possibility
of imprisonment.
- Hello, Agent Cooper.
- Audrey.
This is for you. l stole it.
Don't you think
you'd better give it back?
Not until you look at what's inside.
Okay.
What am l gonna find
in here, Audrey?
Pictures my father paid for.
l did good, didn't l?
Audrey, you did better than good.
You may have saved my life.
Good.
So that makes us even now, right?
- Denise.
- Hi, Coop.
Come in.
Sorry, am l interrupting something?
Special Agent Denise Bryson,
Drug Enforcement Agency.
This is a very good friend of mine,
Audrey Horne.
They have women agents?
More or less.
Audrey, if you'll excuse us.
Agency business.
l thought you were suspended.
l am.
Thanks again. Good night.
Thank you. You're welcome.
These are photographs
of an abandoned property
on the outskirts of town.
Jean Renault, Hank Jennings,
Norma Jennings' stepfather,
Sergeant King, mounted police.
They were at the scene
earlier today.
ln the kitchen l found traces of cocaine
and the baby laxative used to step it up.
l think if you compare this,
which was taken from the farm,
with the stuff found in my automobile,
you'll find it to be a match.
- That's good news, Coop.
- Yeah.
Now, can we talk about something
more important?
Exactly how old is that girl?
Denise, l would assume
you're no longer interested in girls.
Coop, l may be wearing a dress,
but l still pull my panties on one leg
at a time, if you know what l mean.
Not really.
You gonna eat that pie
or just push it around on my china?
l guess l ain't all that hungry.
Wanna talk about it?
Oh, you don't wanna hear
my problems.
We used to talk about everything.
We can still talk, Ed.
Remember when we were kids,
all those plans we made?
lt was like we were just waiting around
for our lives to begin,
planning all that stuff we'd do
when we did.
Somehow, life starts
before you know it.
Suddenly, you're halfway through
living it, and all those plans,
they just don't mean a damn thing.
This is my life, Norma.
l just don't like it much.
We can make new plans.
Andrew.
What is it, Dick?
May l have a word with you?
Sure.
- l feel we may have a problem.
- What problem?
lt's our mutual friend, little Nicky.
- Yes?
- How shall l put this?
Well, he's, he's...
Andy, l believe that little Nicky,
incredible as it may seem,
may in fact be the devil.
Devil?
Or at the very least,
homicidal in the first degree.
Andy, we've got to find out
what happened to his parents.
l've got the autopsy report.
Dwayne, Dougie died
of natural causes. Heart attack.
No evidence of foul play.
Did you check him for witchcraft?
That's not the kind of thing
that shows up in an autopsy.
l wanna press charges.
Now, Dwayne, you know
l can't press charges
if there hasn't been a crime.
Well, she killed him with sex.
And how much clearer
does it have to be?
Dwayne, it's been a long, hard day.
Why don't you just go home
and try and get some rest.
You want me to go to sleep.
Not until that murdering hussy
is behind bars, where she belongs.
l'll sue her, l'll file civil suits.
She'll not get her hands
on any of Dougie's money
as long as l have a breath.
Not one single red cent. Nothing.
l'll... l'll...
Harry, do you still have
that bottle of lrish in your office?
l wanna put some in a little warm milk
for the widow Milford.
O, she doth teach the torches
to burn bright.
lt seems she hangs
against the cheek of night
like a rich jewel in an Ethiope's ear.
Beauty too rich for use,
for earth too dear.
Twin Peaks Sheriff Station,
this is Lucy speaking.
One moment, please.
Sheriff Truman?
Sheriff?
Sheriff Truman.
Sheriff Truman,
you have a teIephone caII, Iine three.
One moment, please.
So wait, it gets better.
And then l said:
''Well, what do you think
underpants are for, anyway?''
Tell us another one.
Please, another. One more.
This one time, l had this cousin.
He was a clown
in this rodeo, you know.
They just had all these
really big horses, you know.
And you will not believe
what they made him do.
- What?
They made him-- Thank you.
- They made him stand in the middle,
- Yeah.
and take his clown costume
completely off.
Can l help you?
Mr. Niles, l don't wanna put
the squeeze on you.
You've been to prison,
l don't need to paint you
any pictures.
What's this all about?
For starters, you're guilty
of a serious parole violation.
Enough to put you back inside.
And unless you cooperate,
l intend to do everything in my power
to make sure you stay there.
My name is Ernie Niles,
and l confess.
l'm guilty.
l guess l'm terribly guilty,
against my will, of course.
Mr. Niles, we're not really interested
in all the--
They held me at gunpoint,
they beat me,
they threatened me
with physical violence.
These men are animals,
they'll stop at nothing.
Mr. Niles, just--
They wanted me
to sell drugs for them.
l tried to resist,
but my family means everything to me.
My family... When they threatened
my wife, well, l weakened, you know.
l'm terribly, terribly sorry.
l guess l did wrong but, you know,
love makes a guy do foolish things,
you know, illegal things--
Ernie, Ernie, Ernie, will you shut up?
Mr. Niles, we appreciate the trials
you've been through,
we sympathize with you.
- You do?
- That's why we're here.
- Oh, you are?
- Yes.
Now tell us everything you know.
Yes, this is-- Well, they tortured me,
and the thing was,
they did filthy, horrible--
Mr. Niles, please.
Just the information pertaining
to the selling of drugs, if you please.
All right, yeah.
Yeah. Well, they got four kilos
of cocaine to sell so--
And they're looking for buyers.
So to protect my family,
l told them l could find one.
Have you?
Are you kidding? l don't know anybody
who would do anything like that.
You do now.
A major drug trafficker
will arrive from Seattle tomorrow.
You will set up a meet with these men
at the Dead Dog Farm.
l will?
How will l--?
How will l know him?
You're looking at him.
Him? Him...
Will you excuse me?
l've got a nervous bladder.
Why?!
Why?! Why would you...?
You could have...
ls she gonna be okay?
First time he beat her,
l swore revenge.
Something violent and noble.
She begged me not to hurt him,
made me promise,
said it was for both our sakes.
That was four years ago.
One day, l swear, l'll kill him.
No matter what it costs.
Jeez, Mom,
give me a heart attack.
l'm sorry.
What are you doing here
sitting alone in the dark?
Nothing. Just sitting here.
Well, read a book or something,
will you? lt's creepy.
lt's Dad, right?
He'll be back, you know he will.
This is just some of that
top-secret jazz.
l'm not so sure this time.
l was at the Double R
a couple of weeks ago.
Dad and l, we had this talk
about this dream he had.
lt was a big house in white marble,
lots of lights.
Dad was there, and l was there too,
living a life of deep harmony and joy.
And there was all this stuff
about my future.
Good stuff.
Kind of nice. Mom, it was cool.
Your father
is an extraordinary human being.
My father
is a deeply weird individual.
But he has a lot more going on
under his hat than most people,
that's for sure.
Sometimes when l'm sleeping
he runs his fingers through my hair.
He thinks l don't notice, but l do.
How long have l been gone?
- Two days.
- Strange.
lt seemed much shorter.
Garland!
Bobby, l want you
to put out that cigarette.
Then l'd like you to fix me a cocktail.
A strong one, if you don't mind.
Sure, Dad.
ls everything all right?
No, dear.
Not exactly.
www.tvsubtitles.net