Now, Dale, listen carefully.
lt's your move.
Please put your heart into it,
will you?
l've noticed a certain tentative quality
in your thinking,
as if your mind were occupied
with issues
other than those on the board
before you.
Such preoccupation
not only weakens one's resolve,
but one's foresight as well.
A deadly failing in any match,
you must agree,
but in this particular contest,
quite disastrous,
as we play for grave stakes,
the likes of which
you have no doubt surmised.
Print your move in tomorrow's paper.
Or l will make it for you.
That tears it. Cooper,
I'm not Ietting you out of my sight.
Harry, if Windom wanted to kiII me,
I'd aIready be dead.
Yeah.
- Better get Pete on the horn.
- Right.
Lucy, caII Pete MarteII,
get him over here right away.
Then caII the paper.
Find out the Iatest possibIe deadIine
for tomorrow's personaIs coIumn.
Paper and Pete, got it.
l'll do it alphabetically.
She was beautifuI.
She was the Iove of my Iife, Harry.
Okay, Lucy.
Okay, yeah, just teII Harry
I'II be right there, okay?
Right.
Peter.
SaIt and pepper.
Coming right up, poodIe.
You two bring out the worst
in each other.
- Oh, Pete's a prince of a man.
- A court jester.
WeII, I've got to mosey.
Goodbye, you sweet Packards.
Oh, Catherine.
Catherine, I'd aIways have hoped
that time and age wouId meIIow
that tempest raging inside you.
Watching you two act
Iike the Hardy Boys
aIways brings on stormy weather.
What's happening with Ghostwood?
I taIked to the investors,
the meeting is set.
I Ieave for Paris tomorrow.
Oh, company.
Dear Josie...
I'm home, did you miss me?
Oh, she Iooked surprised.
- Poor Josie.
- Oh, she has her charms, though.
Yes, but not for Iong.
Come in.
- Hi, Harry.
- Save it, Hank.
What happened? Did you get up on
the wrong side of the bed this morning?
So I broke paroIe. Cry me a river.
You crossed the border into Canada.
You consorted with the drug deaIers
at Dead Dog Farm.
You tried to kiII somebody.
I'm charging you with
the attempted murder of Leo Johnson.
WeII, I think it's safe to assume
that I was at the diner
the night that Leo was pIugged.
- But you're weIcome to caII--
- I got a witness.
Puts you at the scene
with a gun in your hand.
Harry, you obviousIy seem serious
about this,
so I'm going to propose a trade.
How about information
Ieading to the arrest
and conviction
of Andrew Packard's murderer?
Hank Jennings,
witness for the prosecution.
No deaIs.
You're teIIing me
you're more interested
in the attempted murder
of Leo Johnson, feIon,
than Andrew Packard?
How's that gonna sit
with your constituents?
You're through, Hank.
My guess is, Harry, not too weII.
EspeciaIIy once they find out
who pushed the button on Andrew
and that you're sIeeping with her.
Gee, I'm sorry.
Get him out of here.
Get him out of here!
Give me that.
This is the buIIet we removed
from you.
This is the one that was excavated
from the dead man's skuII.
Same buIIets, same gun, same kiIIer.
Let's go get her.
- AIbert, hoId your horses.
- Coop,
I appreciate any reIuctance you have
for busting your paI's oId Iady,
but the woman ventiIated you
and Ieft you for dead.
AIbert, I don't take it personaIIy.
What about the gIoves,
the powder tests?
News at 5.
AII right, fine, you're not mad,
but there's an epidemic
of muItipIe gunshot wounds
foIIowing this chick around.
She is a menace.
I'II taIk to her.
Maybe she'II confess, turn herseIf in.
Maybe she'II grow wings
and join the circus.
Randy, I've got a Iist
of aII our non-repeat guests.
We're gonna send them a speciaI
invitation to the Great Northern.
Your enthusiasm brings
a saIty tear to the eye.
However,
I think you wiII find my job requires
a IittIe more
than a tight sweater
and a perky attitude.
Randy, I'm Iearning the business.
Every week a different department.
I don't want your job.
Yes, I Iook forward
to your stint in housekeeping.
This came for you this morning.
Good Iuck, Miss Horne.
You'II need it.
Hi.
- I just checked into Room 21 5.
- CongratuIations.
Strange, they toId me at the front desk
I shouId taIk to you.
What is it I can do for you?
Sorry, thought you were working.
I am working.
I'm working, see?
I see.
Audrey.
- Horne?
- At your service.
CouId you send someone out
to the airport?
I'm traveIing with some
heavy equipment this trip.
Didn't have enough room in the van.
- What fIight were you on?
- My own.
On the jet out there.
ShouIdn't be hard to find.
Is there anything eIse I can do
for you, Mr. RockefeIIer?
No, thank you.
Yeah.
I have a picture of you.
You're wearing a IittIe dirndI skirt, got
a white apron on, you have pigtaiIs.
It's unbeIievabIy cute.
I don't wear dirndI.
You did then.
It was right here.
The Great Northern dining room.
If I cIose my eyes,
I can aImost see it.
LittIe Audrey Horne as Heidi.
WeII, anyway, it's unforgettabIe.
Heidi.
I was 1 0. Hey!
Thank you.
''Save the one you Iove.
PIease attend gathering of angeIs
tonight at the Road House, 9:30.''
Nadine?
Honey, what are you doing home
from schooI?
Are you feeIing poorIy?
Don't.
Don't what?
Oh, Eddie. We have to taIk.
Okay.
Mike and I are in Iove.
- In Iove?
- I hope you're not hurt.
I wouIdn't wanna hurt you
for anything in the worId.
Honest, you have to beIieve that.
But Mike and I, on that wrestIing trip,
we had the most
magicaI night together.
AII night?
WeII, you and Norma did it.
WeII, that's fair.
So, what's this mean?
Eddie.
We have to caII a spade a spade.
We're breaking up.
Eddie,
I'm so sorry.
Josie, I want you to IeveI with me
about what happened in SeattIe.
I toId you.
How many times
do I have to say it?
I escaped from Jonathan
in the airport
and I don't know
what happened to him after that.
Do you understand
I couId arrest you right now?
I came here as a friend of Harry's.
Now, I don't know what pIace
he occupies in your heart,
but I do know that you own his.
I wouId think you'd Iike a chance
to expIain yourseIf to him.
PIease go.
This is the end of it, Josie.
There are no other options.
I want you at the station house
by 9:00.
Or I come and find you.
Oh, Josie,
I just saw Agent Cooper Ieave.
Was this a sociaI caII?
Dear, you Iook awfuI.
Is everything aII right?
- I don't feeI very weII.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
I wish I had better news.
I've spoken to Mr. Eckhardt again
on your behaIf.
WhiIe he's not
entireIy unsympathetic,
he does insist on seeing you aIone.
Tonight.
He'II kiII me.
To teII you the truth,
my biggest worry is
what he's going to do
when he finds out
that Andrew is aIive.
Won't Mr. Eckhardt think
that you've betrayed him?
But of course, you can teII him
that you didn't.
After aII, you did actuaIIy think
that Andrew was dead.
Oh, no.
I don't know. I don't know.
Maybe you can heIp me.
I think I'm going mad.
You wiII simpIy have to face
Mr. Eckhardt
sooner or Iater.
TeII him the truth.
TeII him whatever you want.
Just pray that he beIieves you.
Oh, there they are.
No answer. He must be on his way.
Thanks, Bobby.
Look, why don't you join us?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You know, board meetings are usuaIIy
nothing more than a gathering
of seIf-minded individuaIs,
each more intent
than the other on financiaI gain.
No, thank you.
But today...
Today is going to be
something compIeteIy different.
Am I Iate? Hot dog, Ben,
Iook at you. How are you?
- You are a sight for sore eyes.
- Look who's taIking.
- We taking good care of you?
- The best.
My Iuggage arrived.
Thank you, Audrey.
- You two have met?
- BriefIy.
John Justice WheeIer.
Used to be in construction.
- Came up the hard way.
- How nice.
You remember my brother Jerry?
- That is Jerry. Oh, my God.
- Hi, Jack.
And this is my executive assistant,
Bob Briggs.
- Bob.
- Hey, what's up?
- PIeasure.
- Why don't you aII just take a seat?
I've asked Mr. WheeIer
to join us on the board.
Years ago,
I made an investment in him,
a pittance,
which he buiIt into an empire.
Now, I don't take any credit,
but I beIieved in Jack
even when he was a IocaI boy
pounding naiIs.
I've asked him to return the favor
and beIieve in me now.
Ben, you're testing
my weII-worn modesty.
AII right, suffice to say,
Horne Industries Incorporated
have faIIen on hard times.
The miII,
the Ghostwood Iands, are now
soIeIy owned by Catherine MarteII.
We don't begrudge her,
the miII was and is, after aII, hers.
So,
in spite of these reversaIs
and stripped of aII the trappings
of success,
what are we Ieft with?
The human spirit.
What is the greatest gift
that one human being can give
to another?
The future.
I give you...
...the IittIe pine weaseI.
Found onIy in our tri-county area,
it is nearIy extinct.
They're incredibIe roasted.
According to an environmentaI
impact report,
what few pine weaseIs remain
wiII be aII but wiped out
with the Packard pIans
for Ghostwood deveIopment.
So you wanna save the weaseI?
No, Bobby.
Not just the weaseI.
But Iife as we know it.
I want Twin Peaks
to remain unspoiIed
in an era
of vast environmentaI carnage.
So we bIock Catherine's deveIopment
untiI the wheeI turns
and we get another shot.
That's briIIiant, Ben. That's briIIiant.
I pIan to fight
this Ghostwood deveIopment
on every ground
and with every avaiIabIe weapon.
The IittIe pine weaseI...
...is about to become
a househoId word.
Then what?
Then I am considering
a run for the Senate.
Thank you.
Annie, it's no probIem.
I've got pIenty of room.
You just get on the next bus, okay?
And I'II be waiting.
Oh, honey, don't cry.
It's gonna be aII right.
I'II see you soon.
I Iove you too.
Bye.
- So your sister coming?
- Tomorrow.
God, what do you have to do
to get out of a convent?
You just Ieave, it's not a prison.
Sounds Iike prison to me.
No TV, no boyfriends.
You know, when she was IittIe,
I aIways used to think
that Annie was
from another pIace and time.
I guess the convent has been good
for her in a way.
Hard to imagine her out in the worId.
Oh, Iook, here's something for you.
- Who from?
- I guess who was ever sitting there.
Look at this.
''Mountains kiss, waves cIasp.
FIower, sunIight, the moonbeams,
is aII this, thou kiss.''
None of this makes sense.
''Save the one you Iove.
PIease attend a gathering of the angeIs
tonight at the Road House, 9:30.''
Sounds intriguing in a way,
but it sounds dangerous.
I wonder who this is from.
Norma Jennings, I've Ioved you
every day for the past 20 years
and I dream about you every night.
It's time for us to be together.
WiII you marry me?
- Ed?
- We deserve to be happy.
It's our turn, baby.
All night long l held her in my arms
Just to keep her
From the foggy, foggy dew
Good job, feIIa.
Good boy.
Just a few more, and then we'II eat.
Fly to my breast,
Pierce me in colors autumnal,
speak to me only of love.
Leo, you have
an incompIete education.
For instance,
survivaI in the wiIderness?
A reIevant issue in your Iife,
my friend.
Now, this comes under the heading
of practicaI instruction.
I hope you've been paying attention.
Nature is crueI.
This is aIso a Iesson.
Hi, honey.
How are you feeIing?
Oh, great, now that you're here.
Hank, I came here
to ask you for a divorce.
WeII, first Iet me say,
I don't bIame you.
You gave me a second chance
and I bIew it.
I don't know
why I'm so seIf-destructive,
but I can see
that that's my priority in getting weII.
I got a Iot of work to do.
In fact, I decided
I'm gonna try to go into therapy.
I don't wanna be Iike this anymore.
That's very interesting, Hank.
But I have to get on with my Iife.
I know.
I know you do.
I just want you to be happy.
Thank you.
I want you to do me one Iast favor.
I want you to heIp me
get out of here.
If they send me back to prison,
I'II die.
TeII the sheriff
that I was at the restaurant
the night
that Leo Johnson was shot.
I was on my way home.
I can't prove it, but you can.
No more Iies, Hank.
It's not Iying,
it's trying to save my Iife.
No.
You're kiIIing me here, Norma.
Don't bIame this on me.
Don't you dare.
Is it Ed?
Is that who you're running to?
Okay.
Then here's the deaI.
You give me my aIibi
and I give you your divorce.
I didn't come here
to negotiate with you.
This is it, it's over.
Fine.
Go ahead.
You're his whore, Norma.
I'd rather be his whore
than your wife.
Norma!
Now, there are four or five
different ways of doing this thing,
and they aII have their virtues.
I remember CapabIanca and Lasker,
St. Petersburg, 1 91 4--
- Pete.
- Yeah.
We've onIy got five minutes.
AII right.
- Lucy.
- Sheriff?
Get the Gazette on the phone.
TeII them not to cIose out
the personaIs. We need more time.
- The Gazette.
- Okay.
That's it.
Guaranteed to cause
some sIeepIess nights.
As Iong as he can't remove
another piece from the board.
He can't do it.
Not at Ieast for five, six more moves.
Maybe he'II kiII anyway.
- Maybe it'II just frustrate him.
- I don't think so, Harry.
EarIe has a perverse sense of honor
about these things.
I never heard of a man
who murdered by the ruIes.
Coop?
AIbert.
Good work, Pete.
Here it is, straight up.
I got a match on the gun that
whacked you with the powder residue
on Josie Packard's gIoves.
SeattIe poIice have aIso
come up with an eyewitness
who positiveIy ID'd Josie Ieaving
the car where they found the stiff.
If you ain't gonna bust this bitch,
- I wouId consider it a personaI--
- AIbert, I can handIe it.
I think you just did.
Come in.
I assume
you stiII have a taste for bubbIy.
We've kiIIed enough bottIes
in our time.
To beginnings.
And endings, and the wisdom
to know the difference.
I am sorry, Andrew.
I hated you at first, of course.
PerfectIy normaI response.
As my anger diminished,
I recaIIed that Eckhardt has a way
of persuading peopIe to do anything.
- It was his idea, of course.
- Yes.
He made me do it.
And he said you never Ioved me.
You just married me
to get back at him.
That's not true,
I did Iove you very much.
Of course,
the same cannot be said for you.
PIease, Josie,
Iet there be no more Iies between us.
You had a job to do and you did it.
Now you're paying the price.
Every action has its consequence,
my dear.
The poIice are cIosing in.
If you don't take action,
you'II be sIeeping in a jaiI ceII tonight.
What can I do? PIease heIp me.
You must see Eckhardt.
Perhaps you were meant
to be together aII aIong.
I'm sure he truIy Ioves you.
He doesn't know I'm aIive.
He can get you out of this country.
Go to him, Josie.
Now.
Andrew.
We won't speak again.
Hi.
It's beautifuI.
I wanted us to go somepIace
we've never been before.
Come on.
How did it go with the poIice?
They asked a miIIion questions
that I didn't know the answers to.
But the ones I did
must have been enough.
EveIyn's gonna stand triaI
and I'II be a witness.
You're not wearing the ring.
I know about you and EveIyn.
I wouIdn't bIame you
if you hated me.
James,
I know what you were feeIing.
I was feeIing it too.
EveIyn just took advantage of it.
WeII, it was wrong
and I shouId've known that.
Look, it's okay for you to feeI bad
about what happened to you,
but I don't want you to feeI bad
for me.
If we couId just start over again...
PIease come home with me.
I can't. Not right now.
You're right. You shouId go.
But what about you?
Can't worry about me anymore.
I've been a part
of aII the horribIe things
that have happened.
I wanna be a part
of something good now.
James, go.
Take aII the time you need.
I Iove you.
I'm gonna miss you Iike crazy.
But you'II go away
and you'II come back
with great stories.
And none of them are gonna be
about Laura or Maddy or EveIyn.
And I'II be here.
- Come with me.
- No.
WeII, then, I'II come back, I promise.
Coming.
- Pete, I need to see Josie.
- Come on in.
- I think she's gone out.
- Yes, it's rather odd.
She took my car
without saying a word.
WeII, she toId me
the Great Northern.
Oh, did she? WeII,
she took a Iot of things with her.
I don't know where she was going.
But I'd say she was pIanning
to stay a whiIe.
What eIse did she say, Pete?
WeII, that she was going to see
an oId friend.
Who?
Sheriff, I suppose it's been very hard
on aII of us
Iearning the truth about Josie.
Catherine.
Who?
Eckhardt. Thomas Eckhardt.
Poor man.
Lobby, pIease.
Thomas.
We meet again.
I don't beIieve in ghosts.
Pity, it's an appeaIing notion.
The return of the grisIy phantom
from the grave.
You deserve haunting, to be sure.
Look cIoser, Thomas.
I'm aIive.
How?
Guess. It's reaIIy very simpIe.
Josie.
She warned me off herseIf.
CouIdn't bear to see
her beIoved husband perish.
Or more reaIisticaIIy, I suppose,
she feIt there was
some advantage to be gained.
She betrayed me.
We're aII famiIiar with betrayaI.
Josie is mine. She beIongs to me.
Oh, Thomas,
Iove wiII break your heart.
HappiIy, Iong ago, I Iost interest.
But Josie Ioses her heart
with aIarming reguIarity.
The IocaI sheriff, of aII peopIe.
- I have taken care of that.
- I don't doubt it.
Sometimes I wonder
if our Josie
does these twisted things
deIiberateIy.
Don't you?
As someone
who was once your friend,
I come back with a warning.
Josie is coming back to you,
be very carefuI.
I'm aIways carefuI.
WeII, here we are, the Iobby.
I'II be going back down
to the garage.
My resurrection remains
a weII-kept secret.
Thomas.
Bye.
I know that I have a Iot to Iearn.
Jack,
you shaII be my teacher.
Think of me as an open book,
upon whose virgin pages
you shaII scribe.
You okay?
So, Mr. WheeIer,
what is it exactIy you do do?
First off, caII me Jack, pIease.
I buy bankrupt, faiIing businesses.
I streamIine them,
bring them back up to speed
and then usuaIIy seII them.
At a substantiaI profit.
But not, I shouId add,
before making significant
environmentaI concessions.
No, when Jack is finished,
the waste is rerouted, the air...
The air is cIeaner.
And the peopIe happier.
Ben, you make me sound
Iike Santa CIaus.
I'm a businessman, that's aII.
You'II have to excuse me,
the chef just tried to stab Jerry.
You kids carry on.
Pay attention.
So, Mr. WheeIer,
which is it,
are we bankrupt or just faiIing?
I came to do an oId friend a favor.
And it's Jack.
My father's friends are rarer
than the pine weaseI.
WeII, Iet's just say
that Ben was once
a very good friend to me.
So you came back
to bring us aII up to speed.
You are Santa CIaus, Mr. WheeIer.
I'd better hang up my stocking.
You don't Iike me very much,
do you, Audrey?
I don't have an opinion either way.
But if you did?
If I did,
I'd say that the Hornes have managed
to take care of themseIves just fine
for more years than you can count.
And desperate
though we may seem,
wiII probabIy continue to do so
in the foreseeabIe future.
Indeed.
Where have you been aII this time?
I mean, when you weren't busy
rescuing widows and orphans
and making our worId
a better pIace to Iive in.
The far corners of the earth.
I teII you, it's gIorious out there,
Audrey.
AII in aII, it's good to be home.
I'm onIy 1 8.
And what exactIy does that have to do
with the price of eggs?
Nothing.
God, Iook at the time.
I have an appointment.
- CouId you teII my father?
- Sure.
Okay. See you.
Bye.
I'II see you Iater, Jack.
I'II see you, Audrey.
- SheIIy? Hi.
- Hi. How are you?
I'm okay. How are you doing?
You know Iife. Drag?
Are you waiting for James?
No.
ActuaIIy I got this reaIIy weird note.
Somebody wants me
to meet them here.
That strange?
That is strange, Iook what I have.
It Iooks Iike we aII have something
to taIk about.
It fits.
See the mountains kiss high heaven,
And the waves clasp one another
No sister-flower would be forgiven
lf it disdain'd its brother
And the sunlight clasps the earth,
And the moonbeams kiss the sea--
What is all this sweet work worth,
lf thou kiss not me?
- This is weird.
- I'II say.
Cooper here. Yes, Catherine.
No, no, I was just on my way over.
She's here?
Thomas Eckhardt's suite.
I see.
HeIp!
- PIease heIp.
- I Iove you.
- No!
- Josie, pIease. For God's sake--
Don't touch me. Don't touch me!
Don't hurt me.
Stay where you are.
He tried to kiII me.
Is that what you'II say about me,
Josie? That I tried to kiII you?
What about Jonathan?
Did he try to kiII you too?
He was taking me back.
Why did you shoot me, Josie?
Because you came here.
I knew this day was going to come.
I'm not going to jaiI. I can't.
Put it down, Josie.
- Harry.
- Put it down!
Harry, forgive me.
I never meant to hurt you.
Josie. Josie.
Josie.
She's dead.
Coop, what happened to dead Josie?
Oh, Josie.
www.tvsubtitles.net