I remember stepping from the fIames,
a vague shape in the dark,
then nothing.
UntiI I found myseIf standing
by the coId remains of our campfire
two days Iater.
Major, there are
some new techniques
that might help us break through
your amnesia.
My memories are immune
from regression.
I can feeI them, they are paIpabIe,
the smeIIs and sensation.
Everything is known to me,
yet somehow beyond my reach.
Do you remember anything else?
Very IittIe.
Save for one disturbing image
of a giant owI.
- Pervasive.
- A giant owl?
A giant owI? How big?
Enough to cIoud my mind
and memory.
Three trianguIar scars behind
the right ear in perfect proportion.
Major Briggs,
exactIy what does
your work invoIve?
That information's,
as I've repeated endIessIy
to myseIf,
cIassified.
Though the keeping of secrets
seems Iess meaningfuI to me now.
Perhaps there are sources
of information that are so important
as to transcend the human need
to conspire.
Information of such weight,
that pertains not--
Oh, God.
Is this meant for the souI?
My souI?
Major, perhaps you'd better
start back at the beginning.
Are you famiIiar
with Project BIue Book?
Yes, sir, I am.
The Air Force investigation
into the phenomena
of unidentified fIying objects.
OfficiaIIy disbanded in 1 969.
But there are those of us
who continue,
in an unofficiaI capacity,
examining the heavens as before.
In the case of Twin Peaks,
the earth beIow.
We are searching for a pIace
caIIed the White Lodge.
- Major Briggs?
- I've been expecting you.
- HoId on just a minute, feIIows.
- CoIoneI RiIey's orders.
I don't care what orders you've got,
this is my station and Major Briggs
happens to be a friend of--
Harry.
I'm afraid we wiII have to continue
this discussion at a Iater date.
Are you sure
you wanna go with them?
Yeah.
- Goodbye.
- Major.
Oh, go ahead, Ernie, it won't bite.
A Iot you know, paI.
These men are dangerous thugs,
not that I haven't met
pIenty of their kind before.
Jean RenauIt is a hard man,
but I've known men
that wouId make him quiver.
Ernie, come on.
Make the caII.
WeII, have we set the buy yet?
Trying to.
Ernie's a wee bit gun-shy.
Gun-shy?
Ernie NiIes is as boId as can be.
Let me at him.
PIease don't make me do this.
This is suicide, I know.
PIease, I'm begging you, pIease.
For everybody's sake, pIease.
Ernie, Ernie, Ernie.
HeIIo.
May I speak to Jean RenauIt,
pIease?
Hi, Jean. Yeah, I've got
that big out-of-town buy here.
Hi, Lucy.
Where have you been, Andrew?
There was a cat in a tree.
A peace officer's work
is never done.
But fortunateIy for us, my efforts
have borne more paIatabIe fruit.
I paid the Happy HeIping Hand
adoption agency a visit,
where severaI bIue-haired Iadies
were onIy too happy to sup
from my open paIm.
UnfortunateIy,
IittIe Nicky's records have been seaIed
and returned to the orphanage.
We'II never know what reaIIy happened
to IittIe Nicky's parents.
Courage, Andrew.
Do not despair, dear boy.
Next stop,
that seIfsame orphanage.
And IittIe Nicky's records within.
- Maybe we shouId teII Lucy.
- AbsoIuteIy not.
This, dear boy,
is strictIy a man's job.
FoIIow me.
- Lucy.
- Hi.
Any Iuck?
I checked the personaIs coIumns
in every nationaI newspaper on the Iist,
and I didn't see anything
that Iooked Iike a chess deaI
or find any mention
of the name Windom EarIe.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
More coffee?
You bet.
Is everything aII right, Ed?
CouIdn't be better.
This is for you.
Bye for now.
Bye-bye.
Come on, Leo.
That's a good Leo.
Each day brings a new beginning.
And every hour, the promise of...
It was your turn to feed him, Bobby!
I got practice.
FootbaII season is over.
BasebaII.
Our nationaI pastime?
Fine. You can cIean
when you get back.
I ain't coming back.
What?
You're Iooking
at Ben Horne's brand-new boy.
Do the words ''goIden opportunity''
mean anything to you?
This is my big break, SheIIy.
You don't think
I have anything better to do
than give Leo Johnson
a bubbIe bath?
And what about me, Bobby?
Do I not have anything better to do?
Not that I can think of.
Bobby.
Bobby!
God!
Big Ed's Gas Farm.
- UncIe Ed?
- James?
- Yeah, it's me.
- Where are you? Are you all right?
Oh, I'm okay.
Look, I need a favor.
I need you to get aII the money
out of my savings account.
That's only $ 1 2, James.
WeII, whatever's Ieft.
And send it care of me to WaIIies.
It's this bar out on 96.
Are you in trouble?
No, I reaIIy can't taIk about it.
- James--
- Listen, I reaIIy can't taIk right now.
- Okay.
- We'II taIk about it soon.
- Take care.
- Yeah.
- Call soon.
- Okay, bye.
- Long-distance?
- Twin Peaks.
Are you homesick, James?
No.
TeII me about Twin Peaks.
There's nothing to say.
You couId start with why you Ieft.
It was a woman, as I recaII.
No, you said it was a few of them.
I Ioved a girI who died.
Her name was Laura.
And I thought I knew her,
but I didn't.
I guess nobody did.
I'm sorry.
My Iife used to make sense,
you know?
I didn't Iike it aII the time,
but it was mine.
And I feIt Iike it beIonged to me.
And then Laura died.
And now I beIong to something eIse.
To Laura.
And no matter what I did,
or how much I tried to heIp...
...another girI got murdered.
I just wanted to get on my bike
and ride away.
Take off, just go as far from
Twin Peaks as the thing wiII take me.
I know the feeIing, James.
I know the feeIing.
Why do you Iet him hurt you?
Jeffrey's Ieaving.
I need you. WiII you heIp me?
- Mr. Marsh.
- What do you mean?
- I need your heIp.
- I'II put the bags in for you.
Very good, sir.
- Good morning, Mike NeIson.
- Oh, Lord.
You wanna share a soda?
How about a nice big piece
of cherry pie? Two forks.
Mrs. HurIey, Nadine,
I want my own piece of cherry pie.
In fact, I want two pieces
of cherry pie, by myseIf.
Okay. Meat Ioaf.
No. Cherry pie and coffee.
In fact, I want 1 6 cups of coffee.
I don't wanna taIk with you,
waIk with you.
I don't wanna see you,
I don't wanna know you.
Is that cIear enough to understand?
Or do I need a court order
to get my point across?
Mike NeIson,
you are the handsomest boy
I've ever known.
And I wouId reaIIy Iike it
if you and I couId go out on a date.
I'm sorry.
Sometimes I can't heIp myseIf.
Hey, Norma. Where are you going?
I have to run some errands.
It's a IittIe earIy for errands, isn't it?
We've stiII got most
of the breakfast crowd.
Just you and a kitchen fuII
of scrambIed eggs.
I'II be right back.
Just think of it as a test, Hank.
I'II do that.
I thought you were moving
into my pIace.
- I'm sorry.
- What happened?
What the heII are you doing here?
- This is my home.
- Home?
After everything Catherine
has done to you?
I have no choice.
Josie.
- Oh, go home.
- Josie, Iet me take care of you.
- No.
- PIease.
Listen, I'm safe here.
And when I'm here,
- you're safe too.
- No.
Stop.
Look at me.
I'm Catherine's maid.
I'm no good for you.
You are good for me.
I Iove you.
I want you.
LuciIIe...
What?
What's wrong?
Yes, sir, generaI.
I want you to Iead the charge
on LittIe Round Top.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir!
And where is GeneraI Stuart?
And his cavaIry?
He's a-coming, sir.
Damn his eyes.
- He's coming, sir. I know it!
- Daddy!
- He's coming. He had better be.
- Daddy.
For aII our sakes.
Because the enemy,
we meet the enemy here.
We meet him before morning.
- We meet him here.
- Daddy.
Yes, darIing?
What are you doing?
There's a war going on, darIing.
A war?
A war between the states.
Daddy, I think you need some heIp.
No, no, I'm aII right, darIing.
I just need a IittIe time.
This is a very important day.
Yes, Daddy,
this is a very important day.
We're gonna save the business.
- You and I.
- DarIing, darIing.
Yes, Daddy?
You are standing on GeneraI Stuart.
GeneraI Lee!
GeneraI Lee! Yes, sir.
OId Jeb, he's come.
Oh, I don't need any more wagons!
I want my eyes
and my ears beside me.
- Get me GeneraI Stuart.
- This is Audrey.
- I need you to get me Jerry Horne.
- Bring me GeneraI Norton.
- Ready the men of the AIabama 1 5th.
- This is an emergency.
- I've been figuring that we have to--
- I think we need to taIk about what--
Come on in.
You first.
Okay.
You're the Iast thing I think of
when I go to sIeep at night.
And you're the first thought
on my mind
when I get up in the morning.
I know this worId is going to pieces,
and it feeIs Iike it's designed
to keep us apart.
But we Iove each other, Ed.
I wanna be with you.
I wanna be with you
no matter what happens.
Ed, Ed, Ed. Your turn.
Later.
WiII you mind the chest hair,
wiII you?
You're sweating Iike a pig, Mr. NiIes.
Oh, thanks a Iot.
That's nervous perspiration, man.
Hyperhidrosis.
It's a chiIdhood condition.
I didn't notice it tiII the war.
Korea, remember that year?
I was Ieading a battaIion
up towards the 49th paraIIeI.
We were just a bunch
of fresh-faced kids.
I didn't know what kind of heII
we were stepping into.
Ernie. Ernie, I want you to focus
on the here and now.
Repeat your instructions to me
step by step.
Okay.
I take Denise up to Dead Dog Farm.
- I introduce her to RenauIt.
- Right.
I take RenauIt through the buy,
compIete the transaction
and get the heII out of there.
Good. Harry?
That's when you come in.
By goIIy, I sure wish
I couId join you feIIas.
But I've temporariIy Iost
my enforcement franchise.
- I'II bet.
- WeII,
I've been giving that
some thought.
Consider yourseIf deputized.
The Bureau's Ioss is my gain.
I hope I can Iive up to this.
He's done. You might wanna
toweI him off before we go.
Come on.
How Iong wiII it take you guys
to storm the farmhouse
after I compIete the buy?
You go out, we come in.
- Can I ask you a question?
- What, Ernie?
Don't make me do this.
This isn't my Iine of work.
I'm a coward. I don't do
this kind of thing, I'm a CPA.
- Ernie.
Just a momentary Iapse.
Look, I'm cooI.
Let's go do it, huh?
- Where's Denise?
- I haven't seen her.
You can caII me Dennis.
Oh, I don't know,
somehow it seemed more appropriate.
What do you think?
Our investigation
must proceed sub rosa.
We may have to pick the Iock.
Tricky business.
VoiIa. We enter.
- Where is everybody?
- Lunch.
Here we are, the case fiIes.
N, N.
N, N !
NaiIs, Neaster,
Neatherby, NeedIeman.
NichoIas NeedIeman,
our IittIe Nicky.
- We can read it in the car.
- Patience, Andrew.
- Dick.
- The usuaI background information.
BirthpIace,
initiaI adoption.
First of severaI, it seems.
Dick.
The pIot thickens.
Where are thy secrets, IittIe Nicky?
Dick.
Hi.
We're the Brunstons.
I know we're a IittIe earIy.
It's just that we're so darn eager
to see him.
Can we see him? Where is Donnie?
LittIe Donnie is dead.
Dead tired, I mean.
I'm afraid IittIe Donnie,
he isn't feeIing up to snuff.
WeII, he was in perfect heaIth
onIy yesterday.
- Dick.
- Just a minute.
Woody, Iet me finish heIping
these good peopIe.
Now, where were we?
Ed. Ed, it's Donna.
- I need your heIp, Ed.
- What can I do for you, honey?
WeII, I've been Iooking for James.
He hasn't been in schooI,
no one's seen him at the diner.
I even went by his house,
but I can't find him.
Listen, James is fine. He caIIed.
He asked me to send him some money
in care of a bar out on 96.
We didn't taIk Iong.
- It's aII I know.
- I'II take it to him.
WeII, what about your foIks?
I'II expIain, they'II understand.
- Okay.
- Thanks, Ed.
I have to get going.
I'II caII.
- We have a Iot to taIk about.
- Yeah.
- Bye.
Oh, Ed. The things we do for Iove.
Eddie, I'm home.
Eddie! Look out!
You big buIIy!
Eddie?
Can you hear me?
- Nadine?
- Yeah, Nadine's here.
Don't you worry about a thing, baby.
Nadine wiII take care of everything.
CoIoneI ChamberIain
and the 20th Maine
were trapped at the summit
of LittIe Round Top.
Now, his onIy chance
is to maneuver his Ieft fIank
down the hiIIside
Iike a swinging gate.
But we were waiting for him, Bobby.
And ChamberIain's desperate
maneuver ended, Bobby, in faiIure.
- Mr. Horne--
- LittIe Round Top, Bobby, was ours.
From that vantage point, we were abIe
to roII back the FederaI Iines.
Setting the stage
for Pickett's mighty charge, Bobby.
And victory!
Victory. Hurray.
GeneraI Meade,
you have suffered an ignobIe defeat.
And I accept
your unconditionaI surrender.
Okay, teII you what, Mr. Horne.
I'm gonna go and taIk
to President LincoIn first, okay?
So you just wait right here and...
And I'II get back to you
on this whoIe surrender thing.
Okay? Gotta go.
Don't wanna keep
the president waiting.
Sir!
Baby, I got some good news
and I got some bad news.
The bad news is that your oId man
just bought a condo in FIip City.
The good news is that he's about
to win the CiviI War.
I know.
UncIe Jerry said he was coming home
on the next pIane.
Dr. Jacoby said
he wouId come over tomorrow.
I think Daddy needs an injection.
God, we gotta heIp him.
Don't worry, baby,
Bobby's on the case.
Don't caII me baby.
Enter IiveIy.
Catherine.
HeIIo, Ben.
You've come here to gIoat,
haven't you?
To ceIebrate my demise.
WeII, you go ahead. You Iaugh.
You defeated me...
...as I have defeated GeneraI Meade.
It's true.
I did come here to gIoat.
You doubIe-crossed me.
You tried to kiII me.
And I wanted to bury you so deepIy
that future generations wouId unearth
and exhibit your remains.
SIimy rat bastard Americanus.
Do not feed.
Do not trust.
I suppose...
...that I'm not that trustworthy.
Despite everything
I know about you,
I find myseIf here with you.
Wanting you.
You can't be serious.
I want you, Ben.
Horrifying as it seems,
I can't escape it.
You...
You make my body hum.
Kiss me, GeneraI Lee.
On to victory!
Hurry up, Jim.
The champagne's getting warm.
Don't caII me Jim.
AII right, aII right, aII right.
- James, what?
- You may Iook!
Any pIace you wanna go?
Jeffrey wiII be home by midnight.
Doesn't Ieave us a Iot of time.
WeII, I'II take what we can get.
It's a deaI.
To handsome strangers.
And rebuiIt engines.
You know, I never thought
I'd see it drive again.
You're a miracIe worker.
No, honest.
You're being too modest.
Oh, go on. You deserve it.
You're strong and you're kind.
You have a wonderfuIIy honest face,
James.
Don't Iaugh, it's quite rare.
Every time I Iook at you,
I couId teII exactIy what you're thinking.
WeII, I'd better be carefuI
about what I'm thinking.
Don't be too carefuI.
Not on my account.
So, what are your pIans?
I don't reaIIy have any pIans.
Where wiII you go?
I don't know.
- James, don't.
- What?
I don't want you to Ieave.
Give me some more time, James.
I can think of a hundred reasons
for you to stay.
You sure you don't wanna wait
for Hank?
He toId me this morning
he wanted in on aII of this.
- I think we shouId wait--
- We'II start without him.
Whatever you say.
You're sweating.
Is something wrong?
Sweaty. You know, it's hyperhidrosis.
It's a chiIdhood condition.
I was Iiving in Guam at the time
I contracted yeIIow fever.
The effects are vicious.
You know, sweating is one
of the more sociaIIy unacceptabIe.
Sit down, Ernie. Take a deep breath.
- SociaIIy unacceptabIe.
- Everything seems to be in order.
Do you think we couId hurry this up?
I got a pIane to catch.
Jean. Jean, take a Iook,
his shirt is smoking.
The wire's dead.
Cooper!
- Cooper!
- Coop.
He came for me, Harry.
I want safe passage to the border.
First, reIease the hostages.
We're at cross-purposes, Cooper.
We'II kiII you if you don't.
Then everybody dies.
No, we'II trade.
Trade?
Ernie NiIes
and agent Bryson for me.
Coop.
- I want backup.
- State poIice?
CaII them in.
Lucy, it's Hawk.
Patch me through
to the state poIice.
How's our baby boy?
Sound asIeep.
Dreaming of Iove.
Lucky, Iucky, Iucky boy.
Lucky, Iucky, Iucky.
They moved him to the center room.
Andy, keep steady.
More deputies.
Sharpshooters.
Let's deaI or Iet's run.
WiII they Iet us run, Agent Cooper?
No.
So you think they wiII deaI?
What do you suggest we do?
Surrender.
Okay.
Are you crazy?
No.
But first, we must decide
to give up quietIy or to kiII him.
- Then we both die.
- I know.
Is my death so important to you?
My two brothers died.
I hoId you responsibIe.
Why?
Before you came here,
Twin Peaks was a simpIe pIace.
My brothers deaI dope
to the teenagers and the truck drivers.
One-Eyed Jack's weIcomed
the businessmen and the tourists.
Quiet peopIe Iived a quiet Iife.
Then, a pretty girI die,
and you arrive,
and everything change.
My brother Bernard,
shot and Ieft to die in the woods.
A grieving father smother
my remaining brother with a piIIow.
Kidnapping. Death.
SuddenIy, the quiet peopIe,
they're quiet no more.
SuddenIy, the simpIe dream
become the nightmare.
So if you die,
maybe you wiII be the Iast to die.
Maybe you brought
the nightmare with you.
And maybe the nightmare
wiII die with you.
I don't know what the heII
you're taIking about.
But I do know
we've got a damn probIem here.
And if you're not gonna soIve it,
I wiII.
- Jean.
- What?
Take a Iook at this.
- You order any food?
- No.
No, no, no, Iet her come.
Let her come.
It's just a girI.
- HeIIo.
- Suppertime.
Don't I know you?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Quick thinking, Denise.
It was just my Iegs.
Thank Sheriff Truman.
It was his idea.
Harry S. Truman.
Sometimes you gotta improvise.
He's dead.
Bobby?
Bobby, this isn't funny.
Leo?
SheIIy.
- Bomb. What do you mean, bomb?
- Start at the beginning.
WeII, the voice on the phone said
that there was a bomb
pIanted in the woods,
but it didn't say which woods.
Then aII of a sudden,
there was this huge expIosion
and aII the Iights went out.
So then I caIIed
the fire department.
- Good work, Lucy.
- Was there a fire?
Two of them. First there was one
at the power station.
But most
of the voIunteer fire department--
I'm gonna go check on the generator.
Something's not right.
Okay. So?
--were pIaying bingo, so it took a whiIe
to get everybody together.
- Excuse me, Lucy.
- Then there was the expIosion
I toId you about, which sounded
Iike it was right upstairs,
so we aII got out of here.
WeII, it turned out to be a transformer
on the poIe right behind
and above the buiIding.
WeII, we had to wait
to go back inside
because it was shooting sparks
everywhere
and we were afraid that the station
was gonna catch on fire too.
- But it didn't.
- Do they know how it started?
Suspicious in nature,
that's what Chief KippIe said.
He was suffering
from smoke inhaIation at the time,
so he sounded a IittIe hoarse.
You shouId hear his cough.
I'm gonna make him
some chicken soup.
- Harry?
- Yeah, Coop.
You'd better take a Iook
at this, aIone.
Lucy, wait here.
Good Lord.
Who is it?
I don't know.
It's a chess game.
Windom EarIe's next move.
www.tvsubtitles.net